<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Kin Lane</title>
  <updated>2024-12-09T07:00:00Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml"/>
  <author><name>Kin Lane</name></author>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id>
	<entry>
    <title>Radical Book Buzz with Library Freedom Project and Library Futures at the Francis Kite Club</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/12/09/radical-book-buzz-with-library-freedom-project-and-library-futures-at-the-francis-kite-club/"/>
    <updated>2024-12-09T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[Audrey and I headed down to the East Village last night for the Radical Book Buzz with Library Freedom Project and Library Futures at The Francis Kite Club. The intimate event showcased the good work of the Library Freedom Project and Library Futures organizations, but also showcased ten publishers who support radical authors across a variety of genres. No Straight Road Takes You There by Rebecca Solnit from - In the spirit of her bestselling book Hope in the Dark, Rebecca Solnit explores how our actions can shape the future and the liberatory possibilities of embracing uncertainty. Talking About Abolition by Sonali Kolhatkar from - Powerful interviews with scholars, organizers, and activists who are leading the movement to end policing and prison. Motherdom by Alex Bollen from - Blaming, shaming and flimsy evidence, welcome to the ugly world of Good Mother myths. B. Traven, Portrait of a Famous Unknown by Golo from - B. Traven, Portrait of a Famous Unknown is a graphic biography that tells the larger-than-life story of the German revolutionary, actor, and writer known as B. Traven (1882–1969). If I Must Die by Refaat Alareer from - This rich, elegiac compilation of work from the late Palestinian poet and professor, Refaat Alareer, brings together his marvelous poetry and deeply human writing about literature, teaching, politics, and family. Mafalda by Quino from - INTRODUCING MAFALDA, by the legendary Argentine comic book artist Quino! Frank Wynne will translate five volumes of MAFALDA comics for Elsewhere Editions, with our first volume set to publish next spring. Sympathy For Wild Girls by Demree McGhee from - A debut collection of surreal, skin-piercing stories about the boundless longing of queer Black women. Gabriële by Anne Berest &amp;amp; Claire Berest from - King of the North by Anne Berest &amp;amp; Claire Berest from - The Martin Luther King Jr. of popular memory vanquished Jim Crow in the South. But in this myth-shattering book, award-winning and New York Times bestselling historian Jeanne Theoharis argues that King’s time in Boston, New York, Los Angeles, and Chicago—outside Dixie—was at the heart of his campaign for racial justice. Ghassan Kanafani, Selected Political Writings by Ghassan Kanafani from - Ghassan Kanafani (1936 - 1972) is perhaps the greatest Palestinian novelist, whose books including Men in the Sun and Returning to Haifa documented the horrors of war and occupation. He was also a leading political thinker, strategist and revolutionary. Here, his writings on politics, history, national liberation and the media are collected in English for the first time I will be working through these titles, but also continuing to explore what is coming from these publishers. I published this list as YAML so that I can power future stories, but also feed my reminders to regularly tune into what these publishers offer and reduce my attention given to Amazon. I am thankful for the work of these two organizations for making the event happen and bring together the publishers, but also everyone that made it out last night for...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/12/09/radical-book-buzz-with-library-freedom-project-and-library-futures-at-the-francis-kite-club/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>The Portrait of Francis Williams Helps Me See the Bias in the System</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/11/20/the-portrait-of-francis-williams-helps-me-see-the-bias-in-the-system/"/>
    <updated>2024-11-20T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am obsessed with seeing and showcasing the bias in the Internet. My storytelling on API Evangelist is driven by this obsession and the AI images I use across my storytelling is all about keeping this bias visible. It is a long read, but this amazing story of the portrait of Francis Williams has helped better see the direct bias, but also the echoing programming of that bias within the systems and applications we are building with APIs. For me, APIs are just busy codifying what already exists in the real world, but making it harder to cut out once set in motion as part of the automation and AI applications we are setting loose at the moment. You will have to read the story for yourself—it is long, but well worth it. In short, a man is selling a painting of a black man from Jamaica in the 1700s, and the story behind the painting reveals just how far white people will go to discredit the intelligence and humanity of black people, but also how all of our own programmed biases work to prevent us from seeing the truth. This is just one man and one painting, but the story for me reveals the institutional mechanisms that exist millions of times each day throughout the physical and online world. And that we are codifying and automating the tools for white people to directly be this awful, but also equip everyone to do it unconsciously and far removed from any knowledge or consequence of. The more I see the institutional bias that exists all around us offline and online today, the more I can’t look back, and the more I see it. The direct bias is an easy target, and as we all are experiencing right now, it is still a dominant narrative, but I feel like it is the automated everyday bias like people applied to the portrait of Francis Williams along the way that is so very, very, very damaging. The guy who wanted to diminish any legacy Francis Williams might have had is awful, the way everyone sees the painting along the way is the deep dark shit that is baked into our everyday responses. This is the coding and programming that we are baking into the Internet, and enabling, automating, and abstracting away via our mobile devices and now artificial intelligence. I am fascinated by seeing the bias in the system in new and mundane ways, but I am also fascinated by how blind I am to much of it, but once I see, it changes everything. I get why it is so terrifying for folks to experience, but I’m obsessed with continuing to pull back the curtain on this. It is liberating to see and experience. It is painful and terrifying, but liberating. It drives me nuts to be ignorant. The gravity of white supremacy frustrates me. I do not like not being able to see things, and my white male privilege is regularly blocking...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/11/20/the-portrait-of-francis-williams-helps-me-see-the-bias-in-the-system/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Artificial Intelligence Is The Last Stop For My Technology Career</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/11/20/artificial-intelligence-is-the-end-of-the-line-for-my-api-career/"/>
    <updated>2024-11-20T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I have been listening and thinking deeply about why the artificial intelligence conversation is leaving such a bad taste in my mouth. It is hard to form a thought, let alone vocalize oneself in today’s hostile and noisy environment about not just AI, but the wider Internet, but I figured I’d draw a few lines in the sand on the beach of my little island. I am very confident in the fact that, as many AI believers love to point out, that I will be left behind by the current AI revolution. More precisely, I will stay behind. Meaning, this is where I get off this particular technological train. It is partly my age, but primarily just a difference in the ideology around what the Internet technology is for, and what it isn’t for, particularly when it comes to serving humanity. Let’s start with the fundamental building blocks of why I am skeptical of AI, which I feel pretty strongly are serious areas of concern. And I am confounded why people I thought were logical, caring, and pragmatic human beings are so willing to overlook, kick the can down the road, and believe that AI will “just fix”. Labor - AI Is so clearly being used as a way of shifting power in the labor discussion at this moment, and I am not just talking about perceived employee replacement—-I am talking about the blind desire of business leadership to use AI and automation to replace people even before understanding how it works and what the impacts are. Environment - AI uses so much energy and has renewed our appetite for coal and nuclear in a time where we were just beginning to make better choices for the future of our children, but the stupid tractor beam around AI does not at all seem to care about the negative impact of AI in the real world. Attribution - There is no respect, and there is even disdain or copyright, authorship, expertise, and any provenance regarding the data and connect being used to train LLMs, something that upends over a century of law that was put in place to protect the artists and creators who are having their works stolen. Black Box - Everything is such a black box, and not because it has to, but because it is by design—-the darker and more complex the better the environment is for spinning stories about what is possible, when it is actually all knowable and visible, it is just better to tell the story that it is all a mysterious magical black box. The first two points confound me. I get that rich people have a labor wet dream they want fulfilled using AI, but the droves of workers who are lining up to the trough to sell the future of their work to a few powerful corporations blows my mind. Reading a few science fiction novels when you were a kid and a belief that you will someday be one of the...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/11/20/artificial-intelligence-is-the-end-of-the-line-for-my-api-career/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Tech Regerts</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/11/05/tech-regerts/"/>
    <updated>2024-11-05T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I don’t have too many regrets as I enter the second half of my life. I am pretty confident in who I am and that my journey was worthwhile. I am a good and hardworking person. However, when it comes to Internet technology I have a couple of serious regrets, or more appropriately regerts. To help me deal with these regerts I went and got a tattoo on my arm to help me repent, but also not lose sight of what matters in the future—here are my regerts. I let my kid spend so much time online as a youth and teen. Believed in that libertarian manifest horseshit from John Perry Barlow. Believed the startup founders when they said they wouldn’t sell out. Believed VCs when they said they were selling the same product as me. Believed that y’all wanted to understand the system and do the work. Being complicit and playing a role in the rise and enablement of fascism. I feel like I’ve dropped the ball when it comes to Internet technology whispering bullshit into my ear. Getting a tattoo at age 52 was no minor shift for me. Not because of the pain, but because of the decisions I’ve made in my life. I have never gotten it because when I was younger I was a criminal that sold drugs. The first time I was arrested was at 18 years old on the corner of Haight Ashbury in San Francisco, and when they took me in they took pictures of the scars on my body and asked if I had any tattoos—I didn’t. This occurred three more times over the next couple of years, leaving me resolute that I would never get a tattoo—despite having an image of several tattoos that I wanted. Getting photographed naked holding your privates in a wet and cold jail cell leaves an imprint on you. At 52, while still a criminal I worry less about getting photographed naked. I get why police do it now-—to humiliate and belittle you. I have a pretty big scar on my left leg from a chainsaw accident cutting firewood, which is what the photographer always focused on taking from several angles, because I didn’t have any tattoos. So, getting a tattoo is a big deal for me, and the artwork I’ve chosen has a lot of meaning for me at many different levels—-providing me with a piece of artwork I can use to guide me forward in my work with technology. I can’t understate the importance of this moment in technology right now. I know that many people are willfully ignorant of what is happening, but we’ve been working on the fascist Maggie’s farm for the last 25 years, and we are complicit in standing up some fucked up shit. I will be rubbing my shoulder every time I talk to startup founders and VCs. I will be rubbing my shoulder with every post I publish to API Evangelist, and every Algorotoscope image I produce...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/11/05/tech-regerts/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Kamala Harris Will Win the Election</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/11/03/kamala-harris-will-win-the-election/"/>
    <updated>2024-11-03T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am going to call it now. Kamala Harris will win this presidential election. People are tired of Trump’s shit. While patriarchy is still strong, it has run its course and Trump is the final gasp of this destructive and toxic way of living in this world. We are ready for woman to lead, and specifically a woman of color. I don’t think a white woman could break through this, and I believe Kamala can. This is the moment, whether you think we are ready or not-—there is no better time than now.

Kamala will win. It doesn’t mean our problems will be solved. There is still so much work to do. Trump’s people will once again say the election was stolen. They weren’t running to win. They were running to bring it all down. Trump’s loyalists are in it for themselves, at all costs. They won’t just go away after Kamala wins. We will still have to continue doing the hard work to deal with the brain rot that exists in our country, but the majority of people will want better than that.

I write this because I believe in the people in this country. I don’t want to leave or checkout. I want to heal. I want to have a conversation about how do we improve our world. I believe strongly that we men need to step back a bit into supporting roles. We’ve had a good run, and we keep fucking things up. I think we need a little matriarchal healing. The only way I can envision anyone looking at Trump and saying “that is what we need”, is to conjure up memories of the hurt, painful, and scared men I’ve known in the past–a lifestyle that isn’t sustainable.

I am publishing this two days before the election because I believe. I am not worried about being wrong. I believe in us. We got this. Let’s choose to take care of each other. Let’s choose to be inclusive and caring. You can make all those old patriarchal comments you’ve been trained to over the years to say about women in leadership positions, or you can close your eyes and lead with your heart. Don’t be scared. The world can be a scary place, but we still have the capacity to make caring and confident decisions.

Hate will not win in this election…

UPDATE: I WAS SO WRONG ABOUT YOU AMERICA!! ;-(
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/11/03/kamala-harris-will-win-the-election/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Why I Need To Write Stories and Publish Them Publicly</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/07/08/why-i-need-to-write-stories-and-publish-them-publicly/"/>
    <updated>2024-07-08T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I have struggled with why I need to publish stories publicly on my blogs over the last year. After stepping back from social media, killing Twitter, and limiting my work storytelling to LinkedIn, and personal to Facebook and Instagram I was left with the question once again—why do I publish my stories on my blogs? It is all so wrapped up in my performance as both Kin Lane and API Evangelist, as well as the social media movement of the last 15 years, I struggle with unwinding it all. However, I finally have settled on an acceptable narrative for why I need to publish API stories to API Evangelist, journal my life on Kin Lane, and play with images on Algorotoscope, and fictional stories on my Alternate Kin Lane—it is me. My online identity is a big part of who I am. Soon after finding some success with API Evangelist I noticed how strong the tractor beam was to move to other platforms like Posterous, Tumblr, Medium, as well as operate via social media instead of using open standards like Atom or RSS. I consciously invested in Kin Lane and API Evangelist to retain “value” and “meaning” in what I was doing, and it paid off. My writing on API Evangelist resulted in some very successful storytelling, and has landed me several lucrative gigs along the way. My two domains play an important role in who I am online, but also offline. It isn’t just vanity. It isn’t just a desire to be read. It is my space. It is my voice. It is where I have the most control online in this digital world. These domains are more me than Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn ever will be. kinlane.com, apievangelist.com, and my other suite of domains are my digital self. I feel successful within my domain. I don’t have an editor or filters within my domain. I get to publish whatever images, videos, and text I want. I get to organize my domains exactly as I want, even if that means they end up a little untidy. I like when my stories get read, and I like it if people notice my images, but it is more important that I just produce and publish these things. I also get to go back and decide what gets deleted and removed, and which domains go away. I like this. It gives me a sense of control over my digital self (in a time where I am unsure). I like telling stories. I like for people to be able to find me online. I enjoy people knowing what I am up to in a self-service way. You just type in my name and explore what I am up to. Page views and likes don’t matter, it is just about sharing my view of the world via my digital channels, and contributing in my own positive way to the online realm. I still share stories from API Evangelist on LinkedIn, and occasionally a Kin...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/07/08/why-i-need-to-write-stories-and-publish-them-publicly/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>The Frame Rate of Reading a Book, Listening to Music, and Walking Through the World</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/07/07/the-frame-rate-of-reading-a-book-listening-to-music-and-walking-through-the-world/"/>
    <updated>2024-07-07T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I feel like an overclocked processor most days. Back in the early days of the Internet I used to gather old computers from large companies and recycle them. As part of this work I’d find certain processors and graphics boards that had more value for modification than others. I remember there were a handful of processors that you could mess with their BIOS and set the rate they would work beyond the factory settings—-it was called overclocking. Most of the time you’d end up with a super fast computer, but sometimes you’d fry and burn out the processor, and you were left with nothing. I am not fully recovered from my latest burnout, but I am far enough into it that I can understand more about what put me there and what got me out of it. I learn a lot with each burnout. About myself and the world around me, but more specifically how I respond to the world around me. I get wound up easily. I let myself be overclocked beyond my factory settings. Others understand that people like me exist and take advantage of overclocking me to get more performance than you’d get out of normal folks. Capitalism is good at this. It is good at figuring out what your limits are and pushing you as far as it can, while extracting most of the value for itself. I am hyper aware of how I get to the point where I burn out. I am kinetic. I easily get wound up. It is how I work—-I throw myself into it. It is what I do. I don’t know of any other way to approach what I do for a living. It is something that isn’t always in alignment with employers, but is also something that can be wonderful for generating value for a startup. Which is where I’ve seen the most exploitation of my day over the last 25 years, leading to my burning out. It isn’t just startups, the poster child for late stage capitalism. It is also Internet technology. It has a way of charging me up, something that is difficult to unwind. If I don’t deal with it on a daily or weekly basis, it manifests itself as burnout. I thrive at a high digital frame rate. My brain will work through massive system architectures in hours or days, which might take others weeks or months. This is a frame rate that becomes dangerously high, leaving me stuck in a movie theater till room purgatory most evenings with the project spinning and filling, slapping the back of my mind with each revolution. After months or years of living in this state, I begin to lose my grip. The antidote to this is relying on a more analog frame rate on a daily and weekly basis, counterbalancing the velocity of working with APIs in the technology sector. Two examples of this analog frame rate are reading a book, walking around New York City, and listening...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/07/07/the-frame-rate-of-reading-a-book-listening-to-music-and-walking-through-the-world/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Sitting Down and Listening to an Album</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/07/06/sitting-down-and-listening-to-an-album/"/>
    <updated>2024-07-06T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I sat down this morning and listened to two new albums I had purchased this week—-Only God Was Above Us from Vampire Weekend, and As It Ever Was, So It Will Be Again by the Decemberists. I didn’t just put on these albums and then go do something else, like get online, or clean the house. I just sat there and looked out the window, sometimes closed my eyes, and listened to both albums end to end. It is really, really, really hard to sit and be present listening to music. You have to put the emergency break on. You have to make a commitment to stay engaged with the sounds coming out of the speakers, and be satisfied with the real world images in front of you. Sitting and listening to an album from end to end in the order intended by the artist is important. Sitting and listening is important. Sitting and just being in this world is important. It is something I don’t do enough of. Sure, I sit on my ass all day, but I am not present, I am online doing 10 different things at any given moment. I am doing too much, and sitting listening to music reminds me of what matters. Both of the albums I listed were two record albums, meaning there were four albums each with two sides—-that was a total of eight sides, and two hours of music. Two hours of sitting and listening. The albums are great. I love both bands. Their storytelling ability, and the energy behind is moving. It is what I need. It is something I don’t do enough. I have listened to a lot of music since I got my record player last year, but I am usually still online or doing something else. I very rarely do I just sit there and listen. I think about the trade-off we have made in our lives that prevents this from happening on a regular basis. What stops us from sitting and listening to music? Why do we insist on multitasking? I feel like we’ve accepted a lot of distractions for not a lot of return, and are letting what truly matters slip away. Sure we keep a digital version of our music, but it isn’t the same. Listening to an album the way the artists intended reminds me a lot of reading a book end to end. They are much richer and nourishing moments than any I spend online. These analog experiences are greater than their digital equivalent. There are just more nutrients present. They slow or stop the cybernetic gears from spinning around me in the moment. Even as much as I enjoy doing this, my regular day doesn’t allow for it, and I have to make trade-offs like listening to music while also doing work online in the evenings. Just like reading books, I will be pushing myself to listen to my music more. Not just having it playing in the background, but actually...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/07/06/sitting-down-and-listening-to-an-album/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Learning to Tie My Shoes Again</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/06/13/learning-to-tie-my-shoes-again/"/>
    <updated>2024-06-13T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I have tied a double knot in my shoe laces since I first learned to tie my own shoes. It is something I haven’t thought about a lot over the years. I just do it. Along the way I learned to tie many other types of knots, and I have worn boots, tennis shoes, sandals, and many other types of footwear. I’ve still just always tied a double knot. There has been no change in tne 45+ years of lacing up my shoes. Now, 50 years in, I have just simply started tying just a simple bow. No double knot. No special types of knot. I just lace them up, tie a bow, and go on with my day. When I was married to my first wife she used to make fun of me regularly about tying my shoe with a double knot. I have now learned she was just sad and mean. Back then I still regularly wore boots and I worked manual labor across my houses and properties, so I didn’t let it bother me when she made jokes about me tying a double know with dress or athletic shoes. I just kept tying my shoes like I always have, even when I stopped wearing boots and doing manual labor. Another side effect that grew out of this practice that I never quite grew out of, was that when I wore regular shoes I would just kick them off instead of untying them, something that would eventually wear down the heels—-but it was something that didn’t matter until I got older. I recently had a 4 week long painful achilles heel episode which I realized was due to me wearing an old pair of tennis shoes longer than I should have, and that the heel was worn out from me not untying my shoes and just kicking them off. I’ve since stopped tying my shoes in a double knot and stopped kicking them off, opting to untie and put them away. This has all been a sign for me that I needed to change my behavior. My earlier programming was having a real impact on my reality today. My young male programming and stubbornness was manifesting itself in ways that caused me real pain today, and I needed to change. I need to relearn tying my shoes, and not worry if they come untied as I make my way through the world. Unwinding what I was taught earlier in life has become a regular chore for me. I find these little things are what seem to matter the most. It is alright if my shoes come untied while walking down the street. I can stop and tie them. I can also tie my shoes tight enough that this doesn’t happen too often. I am getting good at unwinding things I was taught as a young child. I am on the hunt for other simple things that I can change in my life that will have a real impact...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/06/13/learning-to-tie-my-shoes-again/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>I Got Covid Again</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/06/09/i-got-covid-again/"/>
    <updated>2024-06-09T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[Last Sunday I started feeling like crap again, and by this Sunday, I am writing this while feeling thankful to be alive. I can’t say that this experience was worse than my first or previous experiences (3 times now), but I can say it is a humbling experience. Monday through Friday the fever was an extreme roller coaster. Tuesday through Thursday I could barely breathe. After a week I am extremely tired, my chest hurts, and I am slowly coming back into the world.

I am seriously humbled by the power of Covid. It resets everything for me. I don’t think about work. I don’t worry about the world around me. I am simply focused on living and getting better. It really flattens you in that way. I know this isn’t the experience for everyone, but for me, it is a world altering journey. I know for some it is barely a blip for them, but for others it becomes life threatening-—with my experience somewhere in between. It confounds me that there are so many folks who are dismissive of its powers, when Covid clearly wields such strength.

I don’t feel like my life was in danger this week, but I am thankful to be alive coming out of it. It moves me that much. Covid shakes my being. There are few things in this world that leave me just sitting at peace in total silence for hours counting my blessing to be alive. I’ve had numerous brushes with death, and Covid is sobering. It leaves me wondering why so many don’t respect it. What is the basis for this? Did they not have similar experiences? Are they are too swept up in the noise of the world? IDK. Regardless, I am thankful and humbled after such an experience, and welcome every little bit of strength and life as it comes back into my body.

Life is precious. I love y’all. I love myself. I am very thankful to be here. I am very thankful for humbling experiences like this. It means everything to me to be here on a Sunday afternoon writing this. I am 52, and made it 25 years further than I ever thought I would make it. Weeks like this one force me to pause and reflect on everything I have, and show me just how lucky I am. Audrey was fortunate as she had just gone in to get her latest vaccine booster, which is something I should have done. I will go in to get a fresh dose in the next month, and I feel like getting flu and Covid shots will be something I end up doing for the rest of my life, and hopefully I won’t get taken out by one of these episodes at some point in the future.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/06/09/i-got-covid-again/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Four Years In</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/06/09/four-years-in/"/>
    <updated>2024-06-09T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[It has been four years since you checked out Isaiah. Some things have gotten harder and some things have gotten easier. We have made it through your 4th death day, and coming up on your 31st birthday. I am sure it would drive you bonkers and make you roll your eyes that I write a post like this addressed to you, but you are dead and I am left alive taking care of your mother, so too fucking bad. I am pissed at you because I have to be here for all the pain and anger your mother has to experience, but it is also so fucking dystopian for me because I had the same death wish you had, but here I am living and experiencing what is like to outlive you as well as all my own junkie buddies. The last four years have been fucked. There have been many good moments in there, and I am thankful for everything that has happened, but god damn it has been a thick soup of emotional hell since you checked out. Your mom is in therapy, getting the help she needs. We’ve stopped drinking. But I can’t say shit has gotten any easier. I would say that it has gotten harder. I would be concerned if I didn’t see progress and understand that we are doing all the hard work. It all reveals how much trauma existed in you and your mother’s reality before you even decided to check out of the world. And I am not even completely accounting for all my trauma and junkie baggage, just you and your mom’s. We live in New York City. We went shopping yesterday to celebrate with you. It will make you scoff to learn that I actually enjoyed shopping at Ralph Lauren yesterday, and came home with a shirt and pair of paints. I hated Ralph Lauren growing up, and did not understand why in the hell you connected with the brand. I think I will go back and develop my old NYC dude look from the racks. I’ll give you credit for this. I think if you had managed to hold on a little bit more and had made it to NYC for any sustained period of time, you would have made it through to the other side of things like I have. But, you didn’t. So fuck you, I get to do the shopping and wear the clothes—-it will be my little tribute to you. It is so weird to be here and alive in this moment after you, Manny, Dave, Jim, and others have checked out. I thought about this last week because we were approaching your birthday, but also I had a particularly nasty bout of Covid, leaving me thinking about my mortality. I realized I am still here because I am a particularly nasty, mean, and stubborn human being. Nastier, meaner, and more stubborn than you. But you probably knew that after hanging with me for that...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/06/09/four-years-in/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Cities Aren’t Loud, Cars Are Loud</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/05/28/cities-arent-loud-cars-are-loud/"/>
    <updated>2024-05-28T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I read the title of this post on the Internet. It resonated with me. Sure there are things in the city like constructions and crowds that can be noisy, but really the noise is primarily cars. But as I was thinking about this it isn’t just that cars are loud, and we separate this and apply to the city, but also everything that is wrapped up in our obsession with cars and how much we love to hate cities because of our largely avoided institutional racism.

I am all about unpacking my historical programming. It is one of the central purposes of my life for my remaining years. Part of this work is about unpacking how I viewed big cities like New York early in your life due to the programming I received from Hollywood, family, and friends in the 1970s and 1980s. Much of this programming is driven (pun intended) by our belief in the automobile, and for me, isolated in the woods as the result of my parents’ flight from urban areas.

New York City isn’t that loud. It is when you first come here, but once you get to know your neighborhood, you are able to separate out what the noises are. It is mostly cars. It is the engines, the horns, and screeching tires. Which I feel are all outward expressions of the institutional anxiety, fear, and racism that people in those cars possess. Think of what cities would be if cars were limited to a handful of arteries, and the rest of the streets open to walking and bikes.

We have an unhealthy relationship with the automobile. We have an irrational relationship with cities, because of our unhealthy relationship with cars. Everything is out of whack. I have fallen in love with New York City, and fallen out of love with the automobile. This is something that is changing my relationship with this country. I want to walk. I want to experience it. I don’t want the isolation of an automobile anymore, no matter how far and fast it will get me.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/05/28/cities-arent-loud-cars-are-loud/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>I Am Happier Without a Car</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/05/27/i-am-happier-without-a-car/"/>
    <updated>2024-05-27T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I just solid our 2021 Kia Telluride and travel trailer to a wonderful family the other day. It makes me very happy. I basically gave them the trailer if they paid blue book for the car. It was a hell of a deal, but it was so worth it to get rid of it without any friction, and an added bonus that it went to such a great family. It has once again left us without a car, living in a big city, but absolutely loving not having to own an automobile, and I am hoping will be something that will continue for the rest of my life. I do not think we are capable of assessing the true cost of automobile ownership. I am not just talking about the car payments, fuel, and insurance. I am talking about the psychological toll of driving, parking, always having that car out there somewhere that we have to worry about. I have gone a couple cycles in my life where I have not owned a car, and I can confidently say that I am truly happier without a car in my life—-despite all the beliefs we deeply hold that our cars are good for us. I am a good driver. I’d even say a really good driver. I have only had two accidents, one someone pulled out in front of me and it wasn’t my fault, and the other I was completely drunk and it was totally my fault—-luckily it was a single car accident. I am also a very aggressive driver. I am not afraid to drive anywhere, and I get pumped up in high pressure situations. I have owned a lot of cars in my life, had motorcycles, and have driven big trucks and trailers—-I historically have loved cars. I am going to work really, really, really hard to avoid owning a car again in my life. I will also work hard to not have to rent a car. I’d prefer to walk, ride a bike, take transit, trains, and occasionally a plane. I want the second half of my life to be car free. I am happier that way, and I am genuinely a better person. To achieve this means that I will have to live in big cities. That is fine. It is a tradeoff I am willing to make. I will visit places I can get to on trains, and hopefully walk from there. When Werner Herzog said, “The world reveals itself to those who walk”, it shook my soul. It rattled my being. It revealed to me just how much of our institutional baggage is wrapped up in the automobile. The automobile is oozing with all the patriarchy and institutional racism that spews from the exhaust pipe of our society. I feel that not owning a car and living somewhere where I don’t have to own a car is one of the most radical things I can do to push back on the system I despise...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/05/27/i-am-happier-without-a-car/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>The History We Need To Learn so That We Begin the Healing</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/04/21/the-history-we-need-to-learn-so-that-we-begin-the-healing/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-21T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am a big fan of facing our pasts. It is the only way we will find peace and balance in our world. We have to do this at the individual, community, and national levels. In doing this work, I have learned too much about the history of our country to look the other way. This history I’ve been learning about differs very much from the history we were spoon fed in school across the United States. From how we engaged with the human beings who lived here when we founded this nation, to the human beings we enslaved to build this country, to how capitalism and racism is used to control us–we have a lot of music to face before we can get on with the healing that is needed for the United States.

There are a number of books I have used to find my way to this understanding, effectively deprogramming myself from what I learned growing up. However, three books stand out as essential reading for any in this country who is truly interested in wrestling with how this nation came to be the way it is. White Trash by Nancy Isenberg, Stamped From The Beginning by Ibram X. Kendi, and the Indigenous Continent, The Epic Contest for North America by Pekka Hämäläinen. These three books pull back the curtain on the foundation of this country to reveal the structural rot that has been here from day one. These three books rewrite the whitewashed version we received in school as youth, and should make you question the still dominant white narrative that owns the conversation in this nation.

I would never run for office, but if for some reason I found myself as President of the United States I would do four things, 1) Indigenous Land Back, 2) Reparations for Slavery, 3) Free Health Care, 4) Free Education Through University. I know how controversial it is, but it is what we need to even begin the healing this country needs. There would still be huge amounts of work, but these four things would help repair our foundation. Without this, we will never fully heal. These things aren’t in our past, and they are what keeps us separated today, and are what keeps us from truly finding American strength, not just the fabricated, white-washed, and corporate sponsored version we ended up with.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/04/21/the-history-we-need-to-learn-so-that-we-begin-the-healing/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>My First Dream That Was Not a Cybernetic Digital Hamster Wheel Hustle</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/04/21/my-first-dream-that-was-not-a-cybernetic-digital-hamster-wheel-hustle/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-21T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I dream a lot at night. Every night I dream. However, last night was the first time I have not had a dream that was a complete hamster wheel of a hustle, and was just an interesting vision from my home. There is a lot in that sentence that makes sense to me, but I need to unpack for anyone reading this, but also so that I draw a little line in the sand of my journey with a stick. My dreams are always a television channel left on overnight, but when it comes to which channel is left on, it is something that is very much influenced by how I am doing overall when it comes to being Kin Lane. For about four years now, my dreams are just what I consider digital hamster wheel hustles. If you’ve ever seen the movie It’s a Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World from 1963, it is a more incoherent, less funny, and cybernetic version of that. Sometimes I wake up more exhausted than when I went to bed. I get myself wound up in the day and it is something that plays out in my dreams. I am always chasing some cryptographic puzzle, system hack, or other inevitable digital adventure that I am stuck in. The world winds me up. Technology winds me up. Capitalism seems to wind me too far up. I live a very kinetic existence, and my dreams are just a reflection of this reality. I don’t always properly manage the cycles and find myself in a bad way, in my regular day, but also in my dreams. When I am home, in heaven, or the beautiful place, it is in a dream version of the Empress Hotel in Victoria, British Columbia. I know it sounds weird, but the hotel is a recurring place in my dreams from long before I ever laid my eyes on the waterfront hotel. I’ve since spent many nights there roaming the halls, just like I am in my dreams. When I am in a good place in my real life, I spend my nights attending concerts, dinners, and parties there. All my dead best friends are there. Rock stars are there. It is where I go home in my dreams. I know every inch of the place and have been dreaming about it since the 1980s. I haven’t gone there in my dreams since before covid. Luckily I’ve gone there in real life, so it kind of makes up for it. Since Isaiah passed I haven’t gone there. I also haven’t gone there since I worked at Postman. Maybe it was Covid. IDK. Likely a combination of all three. My dreams since 2020 have all been cybernetic hamster wheel hustles where I am stuck in the gears of late stage capitalism with digital velocity. Last night I was just sitting in the hall drinking tea and waiting for my friends to arrive so we could go see Pink Floy play in the great...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/04/21/my-first-dream-that-was-not-a-cybernetic-digital-hamster-wheel-hustle/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Living With Your Heart and Mind Open</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/04/21/living-with-your-heart-and-mind-open/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-21T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I’ve come to realize that it isn’t me that is mentally ill, it is that I choose to live in this world with my heart and mind open. I have chosen not to live with a wounded and closed heart, and living an intellectual existence is literally the only way I can stay sane. Unfortunately a by-product of these two choices means that each day has its ups and down as you make your way through the world and actively respond to a very extractive, exploitative, and often uncaring world of people who have their hearts and minds closed. The world, especially life in the United States, makes sure that you know it is you with the problem, and it is up to you to shoulder the weight of the world each day. In my old age I’ve realized that this is capitalism, and it is how the wealthy and greedy obtain their unfair share, and extract value from others around them each day. I have learned that I am the way I am because of my environment. Living in a world where you see environmental catastrophe as the only future, you inevitably experience your day perpetually responding to this reality—we are a product of our environment. I have had my heart broken in many ways. It would be easier to just shut down and close up. I have chosen not to. I really wanted to live. And I don’t just want to live. I have experienced what it is like to live with your heart fully open. It really is the only way I think living a life should be conducted. You just miss so much when you roll through life with a closed heart. You don’t see other human beings, and often just see monsters or enemies. You can’t see art. You don’t really experience music. Eventually you just stop feeling. I don’t want that. The problem is, you also have to live with a heightened sensitivity to all the pain, suffering, but also the joy and happiness. There have lived in many intellectual deserts in my life. I can’t go back to ever being that thirsty. It took me until I was 30 to realize I required intellectual stimulation to literally survive. There is no going back. I have to read and write. I have to understand and explore. I need to be curious or I will lose my mind. The more I know, the more I realize how much I don’t know. The more I know, the more I see how ignorance is used manipulate all of us at scale. Reading, and turning off the TV and Internet is essential to not being a puppet in a very mindless world. I do not want to live In a world where I do not feed my brain, and will spend every moment I can learning about this amazing world I’ve found myself living in each day. That emotional roller coaster I’ve attributed to my brain for the...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/04/21/living-with-your-heart-and-mind-open/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Quantitative and Qualitative as a Zero Sum Game</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/04/04/quantitative-and-qualitative-as-a-zero-sum-game/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-04T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[Technology likes to focus on scale, prioritizing quantitative approaches to defining and shaping what digital success looks like. To achieve scale you need to effectively reduce an experience or series of experiences to scalable transactions. This is a game that often begins with an equal balance of qualitative and quantitative approaches to defining, measuring, and ultimately shaping digital success, but over time it becomes easier to focus so heavily on scale and quantitative measurements that push you lose sight of what quality means, reducing whatever hustle you have going on to zero sum game. I know that the venture capital hustle is all about scale. Scale at all costs. My quaint view of delivering useful technology that human beings need is easily chewed up and spat out in this hustle. I am good at the venture fueled startup hustle within a certain range from Series A to D, and once you succeed things become about things I am not good at, or feel comfortable doing. This is where the company selling a product becomes the product, which I fully understand to investors. This was always true, but when you are on the ground floor of a startup, you don’t see it this way. I’ve been along for the ride of several startups now. I have a clearer picture now. I got on these roller coasters, or aided in their operation as a carny, fully knowing that the roller coaster wasn’t the product, and that even the roller coaster experience wasn’t the product—that it was the carnival. It doesn’t change who I am. I can’t help but focus on the product or service. The direct tangible things that humans need or do not need. I get it now that this belief gets used and abused by startup founders and investors—they need people like me to operate the ride. They need people like me to bring the qualitative experience to the carnival, and get people riding the roller coaster. I get that there is a lot of money to be made in a carnival. In operating, speculating, and hustling folks as your carnival rolls through town. I just struggle with existing and operating at that level. I thrive the most at the direct human to technology engagement level, not the detached, derivative, scaled up version. I am running the roller coaster, teacup ride, and shooting balloon game level. However once you reach series D and you start rigging the shooting balloon game and making the prizes cheaper and shittier, this is where I get frustrated. Series D is where you cease to offer, measure, and believe in the qualitative value your users need, and you focus solely on the quantity of tickets sold to the carnival. The individual rides and acts do not matter anymore—-it is just about tickets sold at the door. In the beginning it is all about the clowns, rides, acts, and making it as much fun to be at the carnival as possible. You want to get people...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/04/04/quantitative-and-qualitative-as-a-zero-sum-game/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>What Will We Do After This AI Wave</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/04/01/what-will-we-do-after-this-ai-wave/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-01T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I like my blog because it provides me with dated looks into how I feel in any particular moment–something I need to feel sane in a pretty insane digital landscape that likes to just memory hole things so it can perpetually celebrate what is next. With this in mind I wanted to write a blog post about the current AI wave we are in so that I can read it after we have survived it—-which we will. It is so fascinating how people so badly want to believe in AI, and the oxygen gets sucked out of the room for anyone with thoughts on other subjects, or push back on AI in any way. I just want a journal entry for this moment, not so I can point back and say “I Told You So!”. It is just so I can stay sane in all this insanity. So, what will we do after this AI wave? The same as after previous ones. Keep doing the hard work to tame the tech beast we’ve unleashed. When I see what AI is capable of, I see useful incremental shifts in how we communicate, build, and manage technology in our business and professional lives. When I see what promises are made around what AI is capable of, I see a lot of hustling, money moving around, disrupting labor, and many people who enjoy being “prompt engineers” while being fed what the narrative is. I am sure we will obtain some new and interesting incremental AI tools and services this round, but I see things already beginning to settle into what I’ve seen with previous waves, and people will begin looking for what is next without much retrospection on what just was. It is how things work. I think this round I will do more work to solidify my business and financial base so that I can more easily weather future hype cycles around AI. One thing I’ve learned about AI (and other technological) believers, is the line up at the trough to believe again. I see a lot of parallels between religion, drug addiction, and digital technology. Believers are going to believe, often despite overwhelming real-world evidence. In this AI cycle the big tech companies like Microsoft and Nvidia, who are selling the AI picks and shovels will do well. There will be another layer of companies who are selling AI experiences directly who will do well, but not because of what they are selling to AI consumers, but what they are selling to investors and the market. AI is just one of the more visible storytelling derivatives all wound up and bundled with previous derivatives to deliver this generated digital financial products. Honestly I find a little more oxygen and peace up here above the hype. It is lonely. But I am not caught up in the insanity of building a specific tool or service, or trying to make investors and the market believe my business is actually real when it isn’t....]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/04/01/what-will-we-do-after-this-ai-wave/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>That Emotion That Prevents You From Reading Books</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/04/01/that-emotion-that-prevents-you-from-reading-books/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-01T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[My eyes get tired. I don’t have the time. It is hard to focus. And the many other excuses I have uttered throughout my adult life when it comes to why I can’t read even 1 book, let alone possess a steady diet of book reading, all seems intentionally crafted to me these days. I’ve managed to carve out two (going on my third) dedicated session where I carve out dedicated time and make book reading a priority. I’d say that in normal times I am to the point where I am always moving forward (albeit slow) with a book at any given time. Something I haven’t done for about 20 years. This session I find myself in right now I am thoughtfully unpacking that emotion I have when I stop ready, or make an excuse why I open the laptop or turn on the TV instead of cracking open a good book. It is a well-known, yet uncomfortable feeling that provides me with a rich substrate for growing a diverse range of insecurities. The emotion has become an essential driver of who I am, or more aptly, who I am not. I can read. I can read well. I actually enjoy reading. I know reading is better for me than television or the Internet. Yet, I still accept this lesser version of myself. I crave book reading, but the world around me seems to have all roads leading towards me not reading. The undercurrents always pull me towards reading something online or watching something on television. It all seems to be designed that way. I have to consciously battle these forces daily and make the decision to read a book instead. The only thing that comes close to reading books for me is reading my news and blog feeds online. Social media, videos, and other sources just don’t do it for me. The cycles are too short. The feedback loops are too volatile. Reading a book is the only time my brain slows down to healthy levels, and living too long with a nutrient starved online information diet leaves you more susceptible to the forces working to convince you not to read. It feels like the frame rate of reading books or blog posts is of an acceptable speed, where anything faster has the potential to become too much like being on a hamster wheel and do not have deep enough roots or nutrients to sustain me. Everything in life seems to pull you away from reading. Work, the Web. It all seems to demand your attention. I have long recovered from the urge to watch television being a stronger pull than reading a book, but I have just begun the same journey when it comes to the Internet. Largely because my career is wrapped up in being online, but I suspect there is more. I am still unpacking all of this, and as with the television I know that I will find my way out. I want to...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/04/01/that-emotion-that-prevents-you-from-reading-books/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>My Domains</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/03/24/my-domains/"/>
    <updated>2024-03-24T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am a big believer in owning your own domain. I do not care what you put there, but you should have at least on online domain which you control. Ideally you have an email address there too, and keep your site(s) somewhat active. I have winters on each domain where I do not update anything, but I always come back to them, otherwise I let a domain go. Today is one of those days where I step back and assess the state of my personal and professional domain(s). My Personal Side I have historically been very public with the personal side of my storytelling, and this is something I think I will continue as long as I can. I find it rewarding to be in control of the narrative for my digital self this way. Kin Lane (kinlane.com) This is me. This is my doorway. Sometimes it is very personal. Sometimes it is political. Sometimes more technical. Other times it is just my personal journal. Alternate Kin Lane (alternate.kinlane.com) This is where I write about the things I see that aren’t real. The line can be blurred sometimes with my professional world, but everything I write here lives in alternate realm. Alorotoscope (algorithmic.rotoscope.work) This is the image factory for all of my domain, where I produce images evolved from photos I took using AI models I’ve developed to show how technology obfuscates and distorts reality. The Digital Self (thedigitalself.org) This is my religion. It is just what I tell myself daily to find balance in this digital world. I believe strongly that taking control over our digital domain is how we’ll save our physical self. Drone Recovery (dronerecovery.org) This is a site about Isaiah and the summer we went out to wrestle with his addiction. Ultimately I wasn’t successful in recovering this drone, but I revisit this site often. My Professional Side This is where I do my professional work focused almost exclusively on APIs. Because of my approach to storytelling it can be difficult to understand where the line between my personal and professional storytelling is. API Evangelist (apievangelist.com) This is where I have been working to make sense of the technology, business, policies, and people of APIs since 2010, sharing stories about what I am seeing at this dimension of our digital transformation. APIs.io (apis.io) The search engine I am developing with my partner in crime Steve Willmott, working to make APIs more discoverable using our open source API discovery format called APIs.json. APIs.json (apisjson.org) The open source API discovery format that I developed with Steve Willmott back in 2014, and we have been working on ever since, and have found renewed energy for here in 2024. API Commons (apicommons.org) The open source API lifecycle format that I developed with Steve Willmott back in 2014, as part of my work on the Oracle vs. Google copyright case, which we are giving some more attention as a common place to store machine-readable APIs.json properties. API Specification Toolbox (apispecificationtoolbox.com)...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/03/24/my-domains/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>The Book I Needed to Understand Our Gun Obsession</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/25/the-book-i-needed-to-understand-our-gun-obsession/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-25T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I just finished Gun Country, Gun Capitalism, Culture &amp;amp; Control in Cold War America, by Andrew C. McKevitt. It was exactly the book I needed to continue unpacking my youth — 1972 through 1995. I do not own guns anymore, but I did up until 2012 (and briefly again in 2019), and only just now coming to terms with the crazy mixed up feelings I have about them. I am very thankful for this book because it was the first academic book I have found that addressed World War II forward. Loaded, by Roxanne Dunbar-Ortiz, was the only thing I have read recently that shifted my views of the landscape in any meaningful way, but Gun Country just gave me everything I need to keep unpacking my shit-—thanks Andrew! You have to read the book to grasp what is wrong with this country, but it is also a guide to understanding the toxic reality in which I grew up in, and what I am working so hard to unwind. I grew up in Southern Oregon in the 1970s, in the cities and counties the book references as the heart of the shift that occurred in the NRA and gun culture that led us to where we are today. I was a product of the Cold War fear, white flight, and anti-government programming that got us where we are today. I managed to get out just as Obama was taking office, and was successful in elevating my view of things to a more global perspective-—only occasionally looking back, while desperately looking for answers. I’d say Obama shifted things for me, allowing me to begin studying my earlier programming. I gave away all my guns to my best friend Derek in 2012, and chose to live in Los Angeles, New York, DC, and travel the world. My work in Washington D.C., and the shift to Trumpism showed me there was no going back. In 2020, my best friend shot himself in the head with one of my guns, just as covid took hold of our world. In 2020, my last conversation with my partner’s son was a fight where I refused to give him his guns back, I never saw him again. He didn’t commit suicide, but he overdosed the same month Derek did–just as covid grabbed hold of us. I now live in a world where I remember my first 22 rifle, .270 Winchester hunting rifle, 9MM pistol, 12 gauge shotgun, .54 caliber black powder rifle, fully automatic rifle, SKS Chinese rifle, and the smell of cleaning and firing them while also confidently knowing I want nothing to do with having a gun ever again–no matter what. This book helps you see the control of it all. The culture. The consumerism. The racism. The nationalism. The fear. The fear. The fear. It helps you see that most of the rhetoric is born after WWII, and not a handed down tradition since the founding of this country. I mean the racism is,...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/25/the-book-i-needed-to-understand-our-gun-obsession/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Going Directly to the Source to Buy Books</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/25/going-directly-to-the-source-to-buy-books/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-25T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am looking for all of the ways I can push back on the often suffocating world around me. I am looking for daily incremental  ways in which I can push back, or at least not entirely be complicit in all the capitalism introduced illnesses that plagues us. One of the cornerstones ways in which I push back is that I read books, but I also work really hard to make sure I buy a book from the author and publisher, rather than Amazon.

I wrote this idea for a post on my blog when I purchased Loaded, A Disarming History of the Second Amendment, by Roxanne Dunbar-Ortiz, a couple years back.



While purchasing her book, I made sure I went directly to her publisher to make sure I supported them, and not a lion share going to Amazon-—it really wasn’t that much work for me to click on the 2nd or 3rd link on Google search, but something that mattered.

Now, more recently, after learning about Gun Country, Gun Capitalism, Culture, and Control in Cold War America, by Andrew C. McKevitt, I was reminded of making sure I purchased from the source because of the related 2nd Amendment topic of the books.



After reading though, I’ve added the dimension that I am not just going directly to the publisher to support the smaller publishers and their authors, I am organizing these regular actions into a bucket of actions I take regularly to push back on capitalism. Gun Country reminded me that suicides, mass shootings, and other gun related atrocities are things that I have very little control over, but I can do more to push back on the capitalism that makes gun ownership a reality.

Both of these books are on my list of books I’ve used to deprogram me, and having links to the publishers page helps me, and my readers quickly support their work, while expanding their horizons reading these books. Purchasing books from the source is a small thing, but something that will add up over time for someone who reads regularly like me, and something if encouraged by each other, could grow into something that actually has a meaningful impact.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/25/going-directly-to-the-source-to-buy-books/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Wrestling with Toxic Masculinity</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/23/wrestling-with-toxic-masculinity/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-23T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I went to see Moulin Rouge on Broadway with Boy George as Harold Zidler yesterday, and then came home and watched the movie Iron Claw. I am having flashbacks to the 1980s and much like the movie Iron Claw, I am wrestling with experiences and programming around masculinity and just how toxic and wild the ride has been. I remember passionately declaring I did not like Boy George, not because I didn’t like Boy George, but because my life would be made a living hell by those around me if I didn’t. I find it to be therapeutic to sort through these emotions, gather my memories and feelings, and write them down to potentially rewire much of the programming I received in the 1970s and 1980s. I wasn’t into wrestling and I didn’t have a domineering father. I had a series of boyfriends and stepfathers to contend with, and never knew my dad, so I think the masculine signals and programming I received were a mix of jumbled noise from television, movies, and the world around me. I remember when Culture Club rose to popularity, and despite the songs being catchy and ubiquitous, you knew as a young teenage man in a rural area that you could not signal any affection for the music or fashion, otherwise your life would be made miserable. I was straight, I couldn’t imagine what this would do to your reality if you actually were queer. It fucked me up so badly for a period of time I thought maybe I was actually gay. I can say, looking confidently back from the age of 50, that the 1980s were a fucked up period of programming for young men. I am sure that every decade meets this definition, but damn the 1980s were brutal. I can see now how my fear of retribution by the kids around me manifested itself into a performance of hatred for Boy George. How confusing and reinforcing of self-hatred. I can see now how fear manifested itself into masculine confusion and toxicity in these moments, and resulted in WWE style performances in the hallways, lunchroom, and on the playground. I was skinny and weak, so never participated in physical performances, but it surely fed my love of knives, guns, and made my brain a rich environment for toxic masculine programming in the 1980s. I can’t tell if things would have been better or worse for me if I had grown up with more muscles. I absolutely loved Moulin Rouge. The music and spectacle was soul nourishing. I loved to be able to see Boy George, and experience them singing “Do You Really Want To Hurt Me”—even just the little bit they did. It is healing to be in New York City in 2024 experiencing Broadway musicals, despite the programming I received in 1984. I am confident in my sexuality at 50, and have wrestled with the majority of my masculinity issues. My wrestling was more about Boy George than it was...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/23/wrestling-with-toxic-masculinity/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Using the Term Luddite To Understand Where People Stand</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/23/using-the-term-luddite-to-understand-where-people-stand/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-23T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I always make a mental note of folks who wield the term “Luddite” to describe people who in their minds are anti-technology. Luddites weren’t anti-technology. Luddites were anti-exploitative labor practices that coincided with technological shifts that were happening across the industry landscape. If you are invoking Luddism when people push back on AI, saying they are anti-technology, you are joining forces with the team who are in favor of exploitative labor practices.

I know there are hundreds of concepts like this that are used to size each of us up on a daily basis. I am just revealing one of the ways in which I am sizing folks up on social media and in casual conversation. Luddism being anti-technology is something I used to believe, but now after reading several books on Luddism and the movement, I understand not just how ignorant I was, but more importantly how this ignorance gets used to undermine our lives on a regular basis.

I would consider myself a Luddite. I am not actively interested in smashing machines, but I support those who do. I am fascinated by modern equivalents of this like AI poisoning. I am not anti-technology. I am anti technology being used to exploit people. I am fascinated by how the term Luddite gets twisted and used to manipulate us. I am fascinated by how a history deprived audience can be made to believe in the opposite meaning of a word or phrase, co-opted and twisted by those who are threatened by the phrase.

I am sure that I say numerous things that are ignorant of history, and others use to judge my awareness and position in the world. It is my desire to minimize these things through reading. Not online. Books. I am confident that our only defense against this very slippery slope where words get used against us is to ground ourselves in reading as many books, across as many different subjects, by as many diverse authors as possible. Where you stand in the future will regularly be defined into two dimensions, those who read and those who do not.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/23/using-the-term-luddite-to-understand-where-people-stand/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Subways, Skyscrapers, and Servers</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/22/subways-skyscrapers-servers/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-22T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I’ve been reading about Frank Sprague who contributed to the development of the electric motor, electric railways, and electric elevators, and his impact on cities. While he was perfecting the electric motors usage to power early subway systems, he was simultaneously applying the electric motor to elevator systems in tall buildings. Sprague literally laid the foundation for our modern cities reaching for the skies by allowing people to live in the suburbs and ride the subway to work each day, but also work in increasingly taller buildings because they could take the elevator to the top. I am left with images of millions of humans moving in, up, down, and out of cities each day, and how this is playing out when the digital landscape is introduced. I can’t help but see the servers behind the web as part of this same set of mechanisms propelling us through space, and now cyberspace. When I look at the API infrastructure that drives our world through this Sprague-ian lens, I can’t help but see little cybernetic belts and gears moving us through cyberspace, and increasingly in the physical space we occupy. I’ve long associated the subway and public transit with API infrastructure, but the more I read about and experience NYC transit, the more parallels I am seeing. I see Sprague motors taking me from my home to the street, and from the street where I live to the street where I work, and then up to my office. As I make this journey I use my API-powered apps to literally navigate and access transit, but also find myself observing people on their mobile devices as well. When I close my eyes and visualize our relationship with servers in the same way I do with subways and skyscrapers I see a fusion between industrial age factories with belts connecting machines and Neo unplugging himself and getting a look at the energy grid in the Matrix. I see the digital belts and gears that connect our mobile devices, automobiles, televisions, and daily experiences and propel us through the physical and digital worlds. Sometimes I feel cursed seeing this landscape, where other times I feel like I am blessed. I close my eyes and I see systems all around us. Like with subways and skyscrapers we are being moved around where we are needed or want to be, but in this new cybernetic realm we can move in many directions at once, changing our relationship with ourselves and the world around us in new ways we don’t fully understand. It is tough to quantify the role that electric motors have played in shaping the world around us, but how we move through it. When you see APIs as little virtual electric motors that move our digital bits, you begin to see overlaps between these complex systems we’ve set in motion around the world. APIs are just state machines, which act as little belts, gears, and motors that power our digital experience. They are what...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/22/subways-skyscrapers-servers/</id>
  </entry>
</feed>
