<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Kin Lane</title>
  <updated>2024-04-04T08:00:00Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml"/>
  <author><name>Kin Lane</name></author>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id>
	<entry>
    <title>Quantitative and Qualitative as a Zero Sum Game</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/04/04/quantitative-and-qualitative-as-a-zero-sum-game/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-04T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[Technology likes to focus on scale, prioritizing quantitative approaches to defining and shaping what digital success looks like. To achieve scale you need to effectively reduce an experience or series of experiences to scalable transactions. This is a game that often begins with an equal balance of qualitative and quantitative approaches to defining, measuring, and ultimately shaping digital success, but over time it becomes easier to focus so heavily on scale and quantitative measurements that push you lose sight of what quality means, reducing whatever hustle you have going on to zero sum game. I know that the venture capital hustle is all about scale. Scale at all costs. My quaint view of delivering useful technology that human beings need is easily chewed up and spat out in this hustle. I am good at the venture fueled startup hustle within a certain range from Series A to D, and once you succeed things become about things I am not good at, or feel comfortable doing. This is where the company selling a product becomes the product, which I fully understand to investors. This was always true, but when you are on the ground floor of a startup, you don’t see it this way. I’ve been along for the ride of several startups now. I have a clearer picture now. I got on these roller coasters, or aided in their operation as a carny, fully knowing that the roller coaster wasn’t the product, and that even the roller coaster experience wasn’t the product—that it was the carnival. It doesn’t change who I am. I can’t help but focus on the product or service. The direct tangible things that humans need or do not need. I get it now that this belief gets used and abused by startup founders and investors—they need people like me to operate the ride. They need people like me to bring the qualitative experience to the carnival, and get people riding the roller coaster. I get that there is a lot of money to be made in a carnival. In operating, speculating, and hustling folks as your carnival rolls through town. I just struggle with existing and operating at that level. I thrive the most at the direct human to technology engagement level, not the detached, derivative, scaled up version. I am running the roller coaster, teacup ride, and shooting balloon game level. However once you reach series D and you start rigging the shooting balloon game and making the prizes cheaper and shittier, this is where I get frustrated. Series D is where you cease to offer, measure, and believe in the qualitative value your users need, and you focus solely on the quantity of tickets sold to the carnival. The individual rides and acts do not matter anymore—-it is just about tickets sold at the door. In the beginning it is all about the clowns, rides, acts, and making it as much fun to be at the carnival as possible. You want to get people...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/04/04/quantitative-and-qualitative-as-a-zero-sum-game/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>What Will We Do After This AI Wave</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/04/01/what-will-we-do-after-this-ai-wave/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-01T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I like my blog because it provides me with dated looks into how I feel in any particular moment–something I need to feel sane in a pretty insane digital landscape that likes to just memory hole things so it can perpetually celebrate what is next. With this in mind I wanted to write a blog post about the current AI wave we are in so that I can read it after we have survived it—-which we will. It is so fascinating how people so badly want to believe in AI, and the oxygen gets sucked out of the room for anyone with thoughts on other subjects, or push back on AI in any way. I just want a journal entry for this moment, not so I can point back and say “I Told You So!”. It is just so I can stay sane in all this insanity. So, what will we do after this AI wave? The same as after previous ones. Keep doing the hard work to tame the tech beast we’ve unleashed. When I see what AI is capable of, I see useful incremental shifts in how we communicate, build, and manage technology in our business and professional lives. When I see what promises are made around what AI is capable of, I see a lot of hustling, money moving around, disrupting labor, and many people who enjoy being “prompt engineers” while being fed what the narrative is. I am sure we will obtain some new and interesting incremental AI tools and services this round, but I see things already beginning to settle into what I’ve seen with previous waves, and people will begin looking for what is next without much retrospection on what just was. It is how things work. I think this round I will do more work to solidify my business and financial base so that I can more easily weather future hype cycles around AI. One thing I’ve learned about AI (and other technological) believers, is the line up at the trough to believe again. I see a lot of parallels between religion, drug addiction, and digital technology. Believers are going to believe, often despite overwhelming real-world evidence. In this AI cycle the big tech companies like Microsoft and Nvidia, who are selling the AI picks and shovels will do well. There will be another layer of companies who are selling AI experiences directly who will do well, but not because of what they are selling to AI consumers, but what they are selling to investors and the market. AI is just one of the more visible storytelling derivatives all wound up and bundled with previous derivatives to deliver this generated digital financial products. Honestly I find a little more oxygen and peace up here above the hype. It is lonely. But I am not caught up in the insanity of building a specific tool or service, or trying to make investors and the market believe my business is actually real when it isn’t....]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/04/01/what-will-we-do-after-this-ai-wave/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>That Emotion That Prevents You From Reading Books</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/04/01/that-emotion-that-prevents-you-from-reading-books/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-01T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[My eyes get tired. I don’t have the time. It is hard to focus. And the many other excuses I have uttered throughout my adult life when it comes to why I can’t read even 1 book, let alone possess a steady diet of book reading, all seems intentionally crafted to me these days. I’ve managed to carve out two (going on my third) dedicated session where I carve out dedicated time and make book reading a priority. I’d say that in normal times I am to the point where I am always moving forward (albeit slow) with a book at any given time. Something I haven’t done for about 20 years. This session I find myself in right now I am thoughtfully unpacking that emotion I have when I stop ready, or make an excuse why I open the laptop or turn on the TV instead of cracking open a good book. It is a well-known, yet uncomfortable feeling that provides me with a rich substrate for growing a diverse range of insecurities. The emotion has become an essential driver of who I am, or more aptly, who I am not. I can read. I can read well. I actually enjoy reading. I know reading is better for me than television or the Internet. Yet, I still accept this lesser version of myself. I crave book reading, but the world around me seems to have all roads leading towards me not reading. The undercurrents always pull me towards reading something online or watching something on television. It all seems to be designed that way. I have to consciously battle these forces daily and make the decision to read a book instead. The only thing that comes close to reading books for me is reading my news and blog feeds online. Social media, videos, and other sources just don’t do it for me. The cycles are too short. The feedback loops are too volatile. Reading a book is the only time my brain slows down to healthy levels, and living too long with a nutrient starved online information diet leaves you more susceptible to the forces working to convince you not to read. It feels like the frame rate of reading books or blog posts is of an acceptable speed, where anything faster has the potential to become too much like being on a hamster wheel and do not have deep enough roots or nutrients to sustain me. Everything in life seems to pull you away from reading. Work, the Web. It all seems to demand your attention. I have long recovered from the urge to watch television being a stronger pull than reading a book, but I have just begun the same journey when it comes to the Internet. Largely because my career is wrapped up in being online, but I suspect there is more. I am still unpacking all of this, and as with the television I know that I will find my way out. I want to...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/04/01/that-emotion-that-prevents-you-from-reading-books/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>My Domains</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/03/24/my-domains/"/>
    <updated>2024-03-24T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am a big believer in owning your own domain. I do not care what you put there, but you should have at least on online domain which you control. Ideally you have an email address there too, and keep your site(s) somewhat active. I have winters on each domain where I do not update anything, but I always come back to them, otherwise I let a domain go. Today is one of those days where I step back and assess the state of my personal and professional domain(s). My Personal Side I have historically been very public with the personal side of my storytelling, and this is something I think I will continue as long as I can. I find it rewarding to be in control of the narrative for my digital self this way. Kin Lane (kinlane.com) This is me. This is my doorway. Sometimes it is very personal. Sometimes it is political. Sometimes more technical. Other times it is just my personal journal. Alternate Kin Lane (alternate.kinlane.com) This is where I write about the things I see that aren’t real. The line can be blurred sometimes with my professional world, but everything I write here lives in alternate realm. Alorotoscope (algorithmic.rotoscope.work) This is the image factory for all of my domain, where I produce images evolved from photos I took using AI models I’ve developed to show how technology obfuscates and distorts reality. The Digital Self (thedigitalself.org) This is my religion. It is just what I tell myself daily to find balance in this digital world. I believe strongly that taking control over our digital domain is how we’ll save our physical self. Drone Recovery (dronerecovery.org) This is a site about Isaiah and the summer we went out to wrestle with his addiction. Ultimately I wasn’t successful in recovering this drone, but I revisit this site often. My Professional Side This is where I do my professional work focused almost exclusively on APIs. Because of my approach to storytelling it can be difficult to understand where the line between my personal and professional storytelling is. API Evangelist (apievangelist.com) This is where I have been working to make sense of the technology, business, policies, and people of APIs since 2010, sharing stories about what I am seeing at this dimension of our digital transformation. APIs.io (apis.io) The search engine I am developing with my partner in crime Steve Willmott, working to make APIs more discoverable using our open source API discovery format called APIs.json. APIs.json (apisjson.org) The open source API discovery format that I developed with Steve Willmott back in 2014, and we have been working on ever since, and have found renewed energy for here in 2024. API Commons (apicommons.org) The open source API lifecycle format that I developed with Steve Willmott back in 2014, as part of my work on the Oracle vs. Google copyright case, which we are giving some more attention as a common place to store machine-readable APIs.json properties. API Specification Toolbox (apispecificationtoolbox.com)...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/03/24/my-domains/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>The Book I Needed to Understand Our Gun Obsession</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/25/the-book-i-needed-to-understand-our-gun-obsession/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-25T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I just finished Gun Country, Gun Capitalism, Culture &amp;amp; Control in Cold War America, by Andrew C. McKevitt. It was exactly the book I needed to continue unpacking my youth — 1972 through 1995. I do not own guns anymore, but I did up until 2012 (and briefly again in 2019), and only just now coming to terms with the crazy mixed up feelings I have about them. I am very thankful for this book because it was the first academic book I have found that addressed World War II forward. Loaded, by Roxanne Dunbar-Ortiz, was the only thing I have read recently that shifted my views of the landscape in any meaningful way, but Gun Country just gave me everything I need to keep unpacking my shit-—thanks Andrew! You have to read the book to grasp what is wrong with this country, but it is also a guide to understanding the toxic reality in which I grew up in, and what I am working so hard to unwind. I grew up in Southern Oregon in the 1970s, in the cities and counties the book references as the heart of the shift that occurred in the NRA and gun culture that led us to where we are today. I was a product of the Cold War fear, white flight, and anti-government programming that got us where we are today. I managed to get out just as Obama was taking office, and was successful in elevating my view of things to a more global perspective-—only occasionally looking back, while desperately looking for answers. I’d say Obama shifted things for me, allowing me to begin studying my earlier programming. I gave away all my guns to my best friend Derek in 2012, and chose to live in Los Angeles, New York, DC, and travel the world. My work in Washington D.C., and the shift to Trumpism showed me there was no going back. In 2020, my best friend shot himself in the head with one of my guns, just as covid took hold of our world. In 2020, my last conversation with my partner’s son was a fight where I refused to give him his guns back, I never saw him again. He didn’t commit suicide, but he overdosed the same month Derek did–just as covid grabbed hold of us. I now live in a world where I remember my first 22 rifle, .270 Winchester hunting rifle, 9MM pistol, 12 gauge shotgun, .54 caliber black powder rifle, fully automatic rifle, SKS Chinese rifle, and the smell of cleaning and firing them while also confidently knowing I want nothing to do with having a gun ever again–no matter what. This book helps you see the control of it all. The culture. The consumerism. The racism. The nationalism. The fear. The fear. The fear. It helps you see that most of the rhetoric is born after WWII, and not a handed down tradition since the founding of this country. I mean the racism is,...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/25/the-book-i-needed-to-understand-our-gun-obsession/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Going Directly to the Source to Buy Books</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/25/going-directly-to-the-source-to-buy-books/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-25T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am looking for all of the ways I can push back on the often suffocating world around me. I am looking for daily incremental  ways in which I can push back, or at least not entirely be complicit in all the capitalism introduced illnesses that plagues us. One of the cornerstones ways in which I push back is that I read books, but I also work really hard to make sure I buy a book from the author and publisher, rather than Amazon.

I wrote this idea for a post on my blog when I purchased Loaded, A Disarming History of the Second Amendment, by Roxanne Dunbar-Ortiz, a couple years back.



While purchasing her book, I made sure I went directly to her publisher to make sure I supported them, and not a lion share going to Amazon-—it really wasn’t that much work for me to click on the 2nd or 3rd link on Google search, but something that mattered.

Now, more recently, after learning about Gun Country, Gun Capitalism, Culture, and Control in Cold War America, by Andrew C. McKevitt, I was reminded of making sure I purchased from the source because of the related 2nd Amendment topic of the books.



After reading though, I’ve added the dimension that I am not just going directly to the publisher to support the smaller publishers and their authors, I am organizing these regular actions into a bucket of actions I take regularly to push back on capitalism. Gun Country reminded me that suicides, mass shootings, and other gun related atrocities are things that I have very little control over, but I can do more to push back on the capitalism that makes gun ownership a reality.

Both of these books are on my list of books I’ve used to deprogram me, and having links to the publishers page helps me, and my readers quickly support their work, while expanding their horizons reading these books. Purchasing books from the source is a small thing, but something that will add up over time for someone who reads regularly like me, and something if encouraged by each other, could grow into something that actually has a meaningful impact.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/25/going-directly-to-the-source-to-buy-books/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Wrestling with Toxic Masculinity</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/23/wrestling-with-toxic-masculinity/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-23T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I went to see Moulin Rouge on Broadway with Boy George as Harold Zidler yesterday, and then came home and watched the movie Iron Claw. I am having flashbacks to the 1980s and much like the movie Iron Claw, I am wrestling with experiences and programming around masculinity and just how toxic and wild the ride has been. I remember passionately declaring I did not like Boy George, not because I didn’t like Boy George, but because my life would be made a living hell by those around me if I didn’t. I find it to be therapeutic to sort through these emotions, gather my memories and feelings, and write them down to potentially rewire much of the programming I received in the 1970s and 1980s. I wasn’t into wrestling and I didn’t have a domineering father. I had a series of boyfriends and stepfathers to contend with, and never knew my dad, so I think the masculine signals and programming I received were a mix of jumbled noise from television, movies, and the world around me. I remember when Culture Club rose to popularity, and despite the songs being catchy and ubiquitous, you knew as a young teenage man in a rural area that you could not signal any affection for the music or fashion, otherwise your life would be made miserable. I was straight, I couldn’t imagine what this would do to your reality if you actually were queer. It fucked me up so badly for a period of time I thought maybe I was actually gay. I can say, looking confidently back from the age of 50, that the 1980s were a fucked up period of programming for young men. I am sure that every decade meets this definition, but damn the 1980s were brutal. I can see now how my fear of retribution by the kids around me manifested itself into a performance of hatred for Boy George. How confusing and reinforcing of self-hatred. I can see now how fear manifested itself into masculine confusion and toxicity in these moments, and resulted in WWE style performances in the hallways, lunchroom, and on the playground. I was skinny and weak, so never participated in physical performances, but it surely fed my love of knives, guns, and made my brain a rich environment for toxic masculine programming in the 1980s. I can’t tell if things would have been better or worse for me if I had grown up with more muscles. I absolutely loved Moulin Rouge. The music and spectacle was soul nourishing. I loved to be able to see Boy George, and experience them singing “Do You Really Want To Hurt Me”—even just the little bit they did. It is healing to be in New York City in 2024 experiencing Broadway musicals, despite the programming I received in 1984. I am confident in my sexuality at 50, and have wrestled with the majority of my masculinity issues. My wrestling was more about Boy George than it was...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/23/wrestling-with-toxic-masculinity/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Using the Term Luddite To Understand Where People Stand</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/23/using-the-term-luddite-to-understand-where-people-stand/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-23T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I always make a mental note of folks who wield the term “Luddite” to describe people who in their minds are anti-technology. Luddites weren’t anti-technology. Luddites were anti-exploitative labor practices that coincided with technological shifts that were happening across the industry landscape. If you are invoking Luddism when people push back on AI, saying they are anti-technology, you are joining forces with the team who are in favor of exploitative labor practices.

I know there are hundreds of concepts like this that are used to size each of us up on a daily basis. I am just revealing one of the ways in which I am sizing folks up on social media and in casual conversation. Luddism being anti-technology is something I used to believe, but now after reading several books on Luddism and the movement, I understand not just how ignorant I was, but more importantly how this ignorance gets used to undermine our lives on a regular basis.

I would consider myself a Luddite. I am not actively interested in smashing machines, but I support those who do. I am fascinated by modern equivalents of this like AI poisoning. I am not anti-technology. I am anti technology being used to exploit people. I am fascinated by how the term Luddite gets twisted and used to manipulate us. I am fascinated by how a history deprived audience can be made to believe in the opposite meaning of a word or phrase, co-opted and twisted by those who are threatened by the phrase.

I am sure that I say numerous things that are ignorant of history, and others use to judge my awareness and position in the world. It is my desire to minimize these things through reading. Not online. Books. I am confident that our only defense against this very slippery slope where words get used against us is to ground ourselves in reading as many books, across as many different subjects, by as many diverse authors as possible. Where you stand in the future will regularly be defined into two dimensions, those who read and those who do not.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/23/using-the-term-luddite-to-understand-where-people-stand/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Subways, Skyscrapers, and Servers</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/22/subways-skyscrapers-servers/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-22T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I’ve been reading about Frank Sprague who contributed to the development of the electric motor, electric railways, and electric elevators, and his impact on cities. While he was perfecting the electric motors usage to power early subway systems, he was simultaneously applying the electric motor to elevator systems in tall buildings. Sprague literally laid the foundation for our modern cities reaching for the skies by allowing people to live in the suburbs and ride the subway to work each day, but also work in increasingly taller buildings because they could take the elevator to the top. I am left with images of millions of humans moving in, up, down, and out of cities each day, and how this is playing out when the digital landscape is introduced. I can’t help but see the servers behind the web as part of this same set of mechanisms propelling us through space, and now cyberspace. When I look at the API infrastructure that drives our world through this Sprague-ian lens, I can’t help but see little cybernetic belts and gears moving us through cyberspace, and increasingly in the physical space we occupy. I’ve long associated the subway and public transit with API infrastructure, but the more I read about and experience NYC transit, the more parallels I am seeing. I see Sprague motors taking me from my home to the street, and from the street where I live to the street where I work, and then up to my office. As I make this journey I use my API-powered apps to literally navigate and access transit, but also find myself observing people on their mobile devices as well. When I close my eyes and visualize our relationship with servers in the same way I do with subways and skyscrapers I see a fusion between industrial age factories with belts connecting machines and Neo unplugging himself and getting a look at the energy grid in the Matrix. I see the digital belts and gears that connect our mobile devices, automobiles, televisions, and daily experiences and propel us through the physical and digital worlds. Sometimes I feel cursed seeing this landscape, where other times I feel like I am blessed. I close my eyes and I see systems all around us. Like with subways and skyscrapers we are being moved around where we are needed or want to be, but in this new cybernetic realm we can move in many directions at once, changing our relationship with ourselves and the world around us in new ways we don’t fully understand. It is tough to quantify the role that electric motors have played in shaping the world around us, but how we move through it. When you see APIs as little virtual electric motors that move our digital bits, you begin to see overlaps between these complex systems we’ve set in motion around the world. APIs are just state machines, which act as little belts, gears, and motors that power our digital experience. They are what...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/22/subways-skyscrapers-servers/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>I Am Not Mentally Ill, It is Just the World</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/11/i-am-not-mentally-ill-it-is-just-the-world/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-11T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I’ve spent considerable time talking about my mental health publicly and privately. I’ve never been diagnosed with any particular condition, but as the person who is most familiar with what is going on in my head, I can tell you it is a far-out space roller coaster. You’ll have to read my blog, as well as my alternate blog if you want to understand more about how I see things. However, in this moment I am looking to zoom in on a statement from my wife Audrey that echoes in my head whenever I talk so openly about my mental state recently. She simply says, I think we focus too much on the phrase “mental illness” too much, when this is not about us, it is about the world around us. This is powerful. This is everything. She is right. We’ve all been trained to carry this load. That the illness is us. It is our heads. I am tired of carrying this burden. I am going to change the words I use to describe what is happening. I tried to describe what I’d traditionally call “mental illness” in my family, and my kids’ family the other night, and it was really hard to describe it as about how society works, nor more aptly, how it doesn’t work. I just don’t have the vocabulary. I am so used to blaming myself, my family, and the people in the communities I grew up in. It will take me some effort and practice to shift how I talk about this condition that seems to afflict so many of us, but I fear it has been misdiagnosed. I was trying to practice this reversal in how I think about things on the NYC subway yesterday, where what I’d call “mental illness” was on full display. Rather than a sick young woman smacking my hadn’t off the railing near her, and defending her space from others with her feet, bags, and overall presence-—I saw a young woman who had been chewed up by a society that lacked the systems for properly supporting what she truly needed. Granted, I am not a doctor, and lack any training in identifying any of this, but I feel it helps me be more compassionate and empathetic to see this about society and not this young woman’s fault. Which I see as a dangerous side effect of rugged individualism-—so many of us get left to deal with things on their own. It is our fault. Viewing my world this way gives me an outward thrust when it comes to the gravity of living in the world, where before I felt like my world was always caving in. I struggle each day being Kin, but it is so worth it. I am thankful for everything I have when it comes to my physical and mental health, as well as my personality, interests, and beliefs. I am determined to stop shouldering myself with the blame for all the illnesses in the...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/11/i-am-not-mentally-ill-it-is-just-the-world/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Apocalypse Is Coming And You Choose To Prep Rather Than Just Live</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/10/apocalypse-is-coming-and-you-choose-to-prep-rather-than-just-live/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-10T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[One thing I find fascinating about myself is that up until about 40 years of age I was steeped in an apocalyptic prepper culture frame of mind. The world was always and perpetually going to end. It was always right around the corner and there was no denying it. It was just a fact. In this reality you are always stocking up, hoarding, and prepping for what is to come. It was just a fact of life. You had guns, a garden, and a pantry full of food you most likely will not eat. I was not alone. Most folks I grew up with saw the world this way, and many still live in this state. The thing I find the most fascinating about this state of mind is that in the face of impending doom, instead of getting out in the world and living, we choose to stockpile food and weapons and further isolate ourselves. I am fascinated by my wild lack of imagination in accepting this narrative. That in the face of the world ending apocalypse I chose to prepare instead of live. It is this “free beer tomorrow” mentality that bothers me so much of this state of mind. If I really believe the world is ending tomorrow, why not live today, and each day until that happens. Why not seek out all that life has to offer today? Who first told the pepper narrative and those listening thought, “that makes a lot of sense”. I know that there is a whole lot of other trauma, programming, and emotions driving this state of mind–I have been unwinding that for over a decade, but the absurdity of it grabs me regularly, and leaves me chuckling. Looking back, this state of mind seems so distant, and almost fictional. However, I know people who encounter my state of mind, and view it with the same distance and levels of absurdity. If you haven’t had someone you knew and loved, or experienced this state of mind first-hand it is difficult to explain. I refuse to look out into the world and feel like it is dangerous. I refuse to look into the future and believe I do not have one, let alone one for the only child I have brought into this world. Especially since my partner in crime literally left this world because they didn’t believe they had a future in it. I refuse to believe in an apocalyptic prepper, because I have to believe. I believe for the younger generations. I much prefer spending my money on a broadway show over a survival bunker. I much prefer eating a mix of ethnic cuisines. I love overeating meals ready to eat (MRE). Yes, I am sure at some point there will be an environmental disaster. It is the future we’ve cultivated for our children. However, I am confident that my neighbors and the government will work together to overcome it. Yes, I can have faith in my neighbors and government....]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/10/apocalypse-is-coming-and-you-choose-to-prep-rather-than-just-live/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Only Seeing Value As The End Result</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/09/only-seeing-value-as-the-end-result/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-09T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[It is easy to see the output of work we do each day as the value. Capitalism has taught us to value the tangible results of capitalism, not the incremental inputs from human beings along the way. I get caught up in this really quite often and think that the resulting blog post from some research is what matters, or the talk I give using a presentation. I am regularly reminded, and humbled when the real value reveals itself to me in the research, process, and hard work that goes into the regular churn of output across my world. The value of API Evangelist does not lie in the 4000 blog posts on the blog, it lies in me, and the skills and awareness I have developed while producing those 4000 blog posts. I guess this is how it is all designed right? Value is transferable. It is something that can be sold. Right? It feels like this lack of respect for the value we possess is why we embrace AI so willingly. It just makes sense with this obfuscation of value, purpose, and reducing everything to a transactional output. AI is a convenient vehicle for us to give away our value without recognition, compensation, or purpose. We are only the sum of our output, and the process that went into reality doesn’t matter. The experience behind the output doesn’t matter. The authorship behind an output doesn’t matter. Only the output matters. The more you obfuscate the process, the more you transfer value to the output. I find that many people in technology under value the human interaction portion of work. You code alone. You wrench on infrastructure in isolation. There isn’t any value in us working together on something. Let alone working together to plan before or tell the story afterwards. I fall for this belief quite often, but then I always come back around to remembering that 99.999% of my ideas aren’t mine, they were accumulated along the way by working with others. I don’t think this tendency for technologists to forget the human side of things is by accident. I think it is purposefully orchestrated to keep us from talking too much and sharing knowledge around processes. If we don’t see the value of working together, we will gleefully work ourselves into a state where we are specialized in technology and unaware of how the business of it all works. My API Evangelist blog is really the strongest evidence of this for me. Sure, there is value in the 4000 blog posts published to apievangelist.com, but honestly it doesn’t possess much SEO juice anymore, as I don’t regularly publish anymore. The real value of it all lies with me. The accumulation of value from the reading, researching, writing, publishing, and socializing of my work as part of API Evangelist is and was the value generated. The site could be shut off today and I still retain much of the value generated from 2010 through 2024. It remains...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/09/only-seeing-value-as-the-end-result/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>We Will Look Back And See The Internet Like We Do The Automobile</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/02/07/we-will-look-back-and-see-the-internet-like-we-do-the-automobile/"/>
    <updated>2024-02-07T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[The more I study the early years of the automobile between 1890 and 1960s, the more parallels I see between the automobile and the Internet. While the car has brought an immense amount of change in the world, once can easily argue not all of it was good. I am already seeing the similar signs of strain of human beings when it comes to the Internet that were there in the early days of the automobile if we had been paying attention. Despite these signs, I am afraid we seem determined to strike a path that puts humans second and new Internet connected technology first-—the same way you can see we’ve put the automobile before humans when you look out across the landscape. If you look back over the 20th century you can say that the automobile transformed this country, but I’d say the automobile became an unhealthy focus over other more efficient, environmentally, and human friendly approaches to moving us human beings around. We could have invested heavily in public transit, rail, and other more socialized, efficient, and effective modes of transport, but we repeatedly have doubled down on cars, roads, and parking garages. As I sit in my NYC apartment I am haunted by the decisions of men like Robert Moses, who transformed the landscape as we know, but with a little more empathy, coordination, and sensibility, we could have crafted a more equitable landscape. Sadly, we are doing the same with the Internet. When it comes to how we invest in mobile and other Internet technology we are doubling down on everything connected to the Internet being good, often at the expense of more proven analog approaches. As with cars, we see much of it. More damaging and exploitative approaches impact poor people as well as people of color, and this conveniently being overlooked when it comes to healthcare, education, and the judicial system—to name just a few. We just don’t seem to have the capacity to ever be asking “should we do this”, and be honest with the negative environmental impacts of an always online world—-until it is too late. Like our physical environment, we seem oblivious to the cesspool that being online has become and what the toll is on our mental health. I do not have any answers here. I just wanted a story with a timestamp on it stating that someone was seeing the signs. As we struggle with the impacts of global climate change, I can’t help it is an excellent time to be more honest and pragmatic about how we apply Internet technology. Sadly, I think we will continue ignoring the warning signs on both the impact on our physical environment that the car has, as well as the impact on our mental health environment the Internet has. I know many folks feel that the automobile was inevitable and its role in our society is too large to question, but it isn’t. The same goes for the Internet. We are in...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/02/07/we-will-look-back-and-see-the-internet-like-we-do-the-automobile/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>This Is Rarely About Selling the Product or Service</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/01/21/this-is-rarely-about-selling-the-product-or-service/"/>
    <updated>2024-01-21T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I consider my bullshit skills to be pretty refined through performing as the API Evangelist over the years. I like telling stories. I like spinning yarns. I do embellish and bullshit quite often as part of this storytelling and yarn spinning. I am not a liar or con artist. So there is always a line. I don’t like feeling like I have taken advantage of someone or tricked them into believing one thing, only to be meaning something else entirely. This is why I struggle in the world of business and more specifically startups. I can bullshit amongst the best of them, but I find the elevated hustle of startups, with the focus on the company and its products or services, distracting from the long or short selling that is occurring at a portfolio or market level, untenable. Until you’ve worked in Silicon Valley for a while you just don’t see the hustle that is going on. What you believe in this technology startup game tells a lot about where you exist in the food chain. Rarely is this game ever about the products or services a company sells. It is about the company as a product and / or the role that a company plays in a larger narrative. For example, the real artificial intelligence focus is not about OpenAPI selling ChatGPT, the real value there lies in OpenAI as a financial vehicle and the role it plays in the wider AI narrative. I am a long time techno believer. I’d say I’ve moved into the recovery phase, but I can still believe without much effort. However, having moved into the world of finance, and learning about how the different roles view markets, I find it hard to wallow in the more ground floor storytelling, and more concern with stories that will enjoy more longevity and relevance. I’ve learned over the years that my interest, scope, and level of storytelling occasionally finds alignment with the techno narrative of the moment. I like telling tech stories that developers will care about. However, I find the ground floor stories to be too prescribed and dishonest to join in right now. I am not going to tell AI stories until I find some angle I give a shit about, and I think matters across a diverse spectrum of my audience. I am not selling you AI. I am not investing in, or shorting AI. I am not applying AI in my work. I am watching and studying the role APIs play in AI. Not selling anything forces you to have a different lens when it comes to analyzing what is happening. It does not mean you will be right about where things are going. It just means you aren’t as easily influenced by the stories about a product or service, or even the next level-up about a company being the product—you are able to view things a little more objectively, and a little less emotionally. I find it hard to write marketing...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/01/21/this-is-rarely-about-selling-the-product-or-service/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Kin Is Gold Accumulated Over the Years</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/01/21/kin-is-gold-accumulated-over-the-years/"/>
    <updated>2024-01-21T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I had the best Ramen I have ever had last night at a place appropriately called “Kin Ramen”. Like so many things for me in this moment the meal was a sort of milestone reached in a much longer journey that began as it does for many youth in this country with Maruchan Ramen, but it was also the accumulation of meaning, purpose, and flavor in other richer ways over the last 40+ years. I knew it was going to be a memorable evening as soon as I walked in the door, sat down, and looked at the menu. As I opened the Kin menu, their definition of Kin shook me a bit. “Kin means gold, and to become gold, it needs to accumulate over a long period from small minerals to be one of the precious things in the world. Same as us, we have gained experiences over and over.” It is this accumulation of meaning and flavor over time that spoke so heavily to me about how far I have come, but it was also the Gyoza and the soul nourishing pork broth of the ramen I ate at Kin which moved me. Audrey and I have a theory about sushi, in that you can’t just take someone new to the world of sushi to an expensive Omakase meal and expect them to understand what has been in front of them. To fully grasp what each dish possesses you have to have experienced the good, the bad, and the mediocre of Sushi in the United States. But with an open mind, and the right amount of exposure and exploration you can accumulate a flavor for what truly matters, elevating beyond the California roll, mayonnaise sauces, and ascend to a place where Omakase from the right place and people will just blow your mind and changes who you are. I absolutely love the food journey I have been on since I was about 20 years of age, but to understand the depth and richness of the geological accumulation of flavors and experiences you have to go back to my beginnings. My overall journey, but also Ramen journey begins in that single wide trailer home in rural Oregon in the late 1970s and early 1980s, taking me eventually to the big city of Eugene, OR, but then on to California and New York. I know this part of my journey is not unique to me, but you have to understand the role that ramen played alongside frozen burritos, frozen pizzas, as well as the canned meat and free box cheese that came with being poor in 1970s and 1980s if you are going to understand what I experienced last night at Kin. Growing up with a single mom in rural Oregon in the 1970s and 1980s meant you prepared many of your meals from what you could find in the freezer and cupboards. This meant you were faced with the decision of whether you wanted chicken, beef, pork, or oriental...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/01/21/kin-is-gold-accumulated-over-the-years/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Those Leaving This World</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/01/15/those-leaving-this-world/"/>
    <updated>2024-01-15T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[The week ended on a thick note. Audrey was sitting in her office and she caught what she said looked like a large bird flying by. It wasn’t a bird. It was a person. She texted me what just happened, and thank god, because of her poor eyesight, she couldn’t see details of this beautiful human being lying on the garden rooftop 30 floors below. I hesitated in writing this post and sharing this story, as it is a very dark one. However, this is my domain. My space. I won’t be sharing outside on any other platform, but here on my platform I talk about the difficult things I encounter each day. I want to pause for a moment for this human being who chose to leave this world, but also the numerous other people I love who have made the same choice. Dave, Manny, Kaya, and Derek, I love and miss you all. I want to make it clear to anyone reading this, that if you are thinking about leaving this world, please reach out. Please. As the week closed I found myself thinking constantly about the last moments of the people I know and loved who chose to leave this world. I have never had suicidal thoughts, as I have made a strange and twisted commitment in my head to stay in this world after surviving my youth, but I emphasize deeply with those who do. I also understand that it is often a split second decision made in a single moment, and rarely something that you plan or would have time to call a suicide hotline. I don’t blame anyone who wants to check out of the painful hotel, and that specific moments can make living seem impossible, but what an opportunity we have with this life given to us. Our lives are a gift no matter how shitty the world can get, and how much pain we can be saddled with as a human being in this world. I have to process this shit. I know suicide is hard to talk about for folks, but I’ve seen so much of it, I have to talk about it. At least here in my domain. I sure do not think I have the answers for others when it comes to how to persist, let alone thrive on this planet. I do not have the skills to talk you off the ledge. I do not carry a light bright enough to show you the way out of the darkness. I have struggled heavily throughout my life to find my own way forward, and find myself experiencing crippling anxiety as I begin or end my days. I’d say that telling people I know that I love them, and writing about the difficult things I encounter in the world here on my blog within my domain is the most strength I can muster. This week spun me. It’s got me thinking about Dave, Manny, Kaya, Derek, but also Isaiah. All...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/01/15/those-leaving-this-world/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>It Is Not You New York, It Is Me</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2024/01/15/it-is-not-you-new-york-it-is-me/"/>
    <updated>2024-01-15T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I was programmed from an early age that New York City is bad. I fully understand that in the 1970s and 1980s New York was a very different place, but as I see the same programming flowing from my elders on social media in 2024, I’ve learned this has very little to do with New York City. I lived in New York City in 2017 and 2018 for the first time, which I enjoyed, but this time living here, I am falling deeply in love with the city I’ve spent a lot of time fearing. As I rode the 1 from Columbus Circle to Cathedral Parkway, and rode the M104 back down Broadway, I realize just how rich, beautiful, and nourishing this city can be, that it was me was not programmed to receive any of this, which is something that is changing in me in this moment. As I continue to unpack my New York baggage I realize just how pervasive my anti-NYC programming has been. Between Hollywood, the news, and my elders, I have a completely fictional view of what is New York City. Sure, much of what I’ve learned exists, but the majority is made-up, make-believe, and stories intended to keep people where they “belong”. Or rather, where people believe others belong. I learned in 2017 during the early Trump administration that the number one reason the elders in my life did not like New York City was race. Sadly, black and brown faces terrify them. One of the reasons I absolutely love it here is that it is a place that is unfriendly, intimidating, and often terrifying to many folks I grew up with in rural Oregon. I’ve learned through my own hard work that it is not New York City, and that feeling you have when you see all the black and brown faces going about their day is you, not them, and definitely not New York City. Beyond just race, you hear that people aren’t friendly in New York City. Once you live here you realize again, it isn’t New York, it was me. I didn’t know the customs. I looked different. I move at a different pace. I take up the sidewalk walking 2 or 3 abreast. I stopped and looked up. I wasn’t in rhythm with the city. After living here for a while you begin to see how stark tourists are, and when you are just trying to get to and from work, I can see how people might occasionally get the impression that I am not nice. However, once you find the rhythm, you figure out there are more songs other than by Alicia Keys or Frank Sinatra, depending on how old you are. Don’t get me wrong, New York City is still intense. It is the human condition amplified, which I can deal with more than I can deal with the banal rural human condition in mono over a shitty single speaker. New York City is rarely ever what...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2024/01/15/it-is-not-you-new-york-it-is-me/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Accepting When You Have Made It</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/12/10/accepting-when-you-have-made-it/"/>
    <updated>2023-12-10T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am here. I reached that place I saw in my minds eye all those years ago. Those undeniable images I had in my head back in the 1980s have been realized. I live in NYC. I enjoy my career. I get to tackle large scale problems. I make good money. I have savings. I am married. I have a kid who is getting ready to graduate from University, which I was able to pay for. I am there. I am writing this post to remind myself that I need to accept that I have made it. Breathe. Breathe. It is hard to separate visions of my future from the movies and television of 1980s, but wherever the source, it all makes a lot more sense now. I never fit in within the small town in Southern Oregon that I grew up in. I always new I was meant for bigger things. I just didn’t have the self-confidence, support, and resources to make it happen. That didn’t matter. I was going to figure it out one way or another. In the moment I did not have any precise career path or destination in mind. I had a vague vision of being a computer programmer, but when my counselor said my math skills weren’t strong enough, I said I wanted to be a writer. I am now a little of both. I couldn’t tell you how I got here, or provide anyone with any sort of map or timeline. It is all a blur. Without a clear vision it is hard to know when I have made it–if I didn’t know where I was going. This is why I want to draw a line in the sand. I have exceeded anything I could have imagined, and I am very proud of where I stand at 51 years of age in 2023. The only thing I don’t have is my own home, but honestly I am not sure I want to own one yet-—I am enjoying moving where I need to be. I have everything else I want or need. I am content. I really can’t remember the last time I could really say that. The trick for me know is to slow down a bit, and enjoy what I have created. I could step away and coast at this point. However, I am curious of what I am capable of. I am really interested in the governance of APIs. I am really interested in how we are going to stabilize this sprawling digital landscape we’ve created. I am thankful for the opportunities I hav win front of me at Bloomberg, and living in New York City. I am slowly finding my writing mojo with API Evangelist and have been moving forward some of my APIs.json work. I think there is more out there. But it really is all gravy at this point. I just wanted to pause a bit and pat myself on the back, look around and take in the...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/12/10/accepting-when-you-have-made-it/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>My Dark Side of The Moon Ritual</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/11/19/my-dark-side-of-the-moon-ritual/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-19T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I have recently started a new ritual where I begin my Sunday mornings off listening to Pink Floyd’s Dark Side of the Moon. Before I look at my cell phone or flip open my laptop. As the kettle is cooking water for my tea–I turn on the album. I find that the album listened to from end to end to be a soothing end (or start) to my week. While listening to the album has end to end experience provided to me by the band, it is also my personal experience with the album over the years that soothe me the most. While I was first introduced to the album sometime in the early 1980s, it was in 1983 when I first experience it. My mom and step-dad had divorced and I went to live with him in Santa Barbara for the summer, and I found myself sitting in his truck watching the sunset, listening to Dark Side of the Moon. One afternoon we drove out past Goleta, CA to where the 101 becomes isolated in the hills as it winds its way north and found an isolated parking lot looking out over the Pacific Ocean. While my step-dad smoked a joint and drank a beer, I sat and watched the sunset while listening to the Dark Side of the Moon from end to end—-it has stuck with me ever since. I’ve had numerous drug and alcohol fueled experiences with the album since then, further laying grooves on my existence, but I find listening to the album end to end sober on a Sunday morning as very healing and nourishing some 40 years later. It isn’t any particular song, but the entire end to end experience that moves me. It just properly resets, unwinds, and leaves me in a better state than when I started. It programs me in a way that Internet technology never can, and defrags my soul un a way that allows me to face the week and recover from the last one. I can listen to Miles Davis Kind of Blue on a Friday night and heal from the week, and fire up some Jerry Garcia on a Saturday to sooth my soul, but I am finding The Dark Side of the Moon is an essential reconfiguration on a Sunday morning. There are several things going on here. There are memories and experiences of a father I love and miss, the music of my childhood, but there is another artistically spiritual realignment as well. I miss my stepfather Ron a lot. He taught me a lot. His pain and suffering showed me how to live. All of the songs combined and in the order they are given to me also have taught me how to live, then and now. I didn’t realize how much they were programming me back in the day, and it is hard to quantify how much they help me deprogram the state I find myself as I wake up each Sunday morning...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/11/19/my-dark-side-of-the-moon-ritual/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Stories About Artificial Intelligence in This Moment Are More About Labor</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/11/12/stories-about-artificial-intelligence-in-this-moment-are-more-about-labor/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-12T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I asked Audrey for her latest thoughts on the groundswell of artificial intelligence (AI) fever everyone is suffering from right now. She has always been my grounding rod in technology, and while I still find myself swept up in currents from time to time, she can almost always see through the stories. When I asked about why the AI story is being told right now, she answered simply that it was about labor in this moment. It isn’t that AI is a thing, or the average people’s lives are being shifted right now by AI, it is because business leadership desperately wants to believe they can replace workers with AI, and they invest heavily in the storytelling machine to make it come true. Spoiler, it won’t. Sure, AI will continue to be used and advanced in new ways. We’ve had AI baked into things powering autocorrect, search, and many other common online applications for a while now, but this moment will fade just like the last one. AI will incrementally shift things here and there, and yes it will replace some jobs, but it will not come even close to 95% of the promises made today. It won’t. The stories right now aren’t about AI. Audrey is right, they are about labor. It is about creating a distraction and kicking up dust as workers are gaining more rights, demanding more pay, and pushing back on the “gig” economy. Labor unions are seeing the most positive moment they’ve seen in years, and business owners and the wealthy want to put people in their place with some good old fashioned storytelling. They are good at telling stories about how workers will be replaced, and you will be rendered useless by technology, and leaving it up to our own fears, self-doubt, and word of mouth storytelling to do the rest. I am fascinated by how the world works like this. People down in the weeds just can’t see how our worlds work at this storytelling level. AI, robots, and automation haven’t replaced us after almost two centuries of this rhetoric, but the stories and incremental advancements in technology do wreak havoc on our lives (“wreak havoc on our lives” was the suggestion of autocorrect—-they are coming for us!! Ahhh!!!). The rich and powerful don’t believe they will replace us with AI right away. I am sure plenty have wet dreams about and would like to believe, but they do know that stories will help them maintain the upper hand in how things work. Once you stop seeing AI as about technology, and see the evidence that human workers aren’t going away anytime soon, you have to reconcile with where these stories come from, and why people believe so hard. For me, it alleviates my anxiety around why people believe so hard in AI and other technologies—-revealing how wrapped up our identities are in our work, careers, and capitalism. I remember when Wolfram Alpha and associated AI came on the scene after 2010, and...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/11/12/stories-about-artificial-intelligence-in-this-moment-are-more-about-labor/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>FTX Syndrome</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/11/11/ftx-syndrome/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-11T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I find it hard to continue working in tech and taking things seriously. I genuinely want to use technology wisely, make a good living, and live my life. I historically have gotten caught up in doing things the right way, where many around me seem fine with riding the waves of the day, cycle, and latest trend. As I watch the FTX trial wrap up with a verdict of guilty on all counts, I can’t help but think people will once and for all see through crypto hustle. But no, it is the opposite, they are doubling down. It feels like the same thing with Trump, and everything else in our world, despite all the evidence to the contrary, people are just willing to believe the story of the day, this election cycle, and whatever the latest twist on how we line up at the feeder to consume. It is fascinating to watch people double down on technology being the answer despite the mounting evidence that it is rarely the answer. I still believe that Internet technology can be done well, but I just rarely see evidence of it action. Bitcoin is rebounding despite FTX. Artificial Intelligence is booming, despite it really not enjoying much daily usage and adoption. I hear a lot about the promise of AI, but honestly it doesn’t touch my daily work. I feel like I live in an API Groundhog Day, where we keep talking about the benefits, but the sprawling API landscape is just getting larger, not better. I don’t feel like there is any growing body of people who want to do APIs well, just waves up newbies who believe it can be done well, but rapidly burnout—with a few of us veterans sticking around for gits and shiggles. I feel like FTX is similar to the drug addiction I grew up around, and the broken record conspiracy theory condition that affects many people I grew up with. People want to believe. People don’t want to do the work. People want a story that aligns with their beliefs. I find it hard to keep a straight face in all of this, let alone properly plan and navigate through the world of Internet fueled technology. I feel like what I was really good at with APIs is just telling stories, and finding the bullshit alignment with what everyone else wants. It had nothing to do with my technological understanding and skills. I find it disturbing to be in a room full of people in a Silicon Valley startup who are pretending to care about customers and solving real world problems, when all they really care about are the perceived valuations of the company. I find it disorienting to live such a lie in private and in the open. It all leaves me thinking that capitalism is just many levels of people conning other people, and believing is just what you do. You are either believing and in the know or you are believing and...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/11/11/ftx-syndrome/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>It Is All a Hustle</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/11/01/it-is-all-a-hustle/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-01T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I regularly fall into the belief that work is real. I end up caring too much about some technology, corporation, or other capitalist song and dance. I do not love money. I really enjoy what it can afford me, but I don’t dwell on it and chase it like many other people do. I refuse to live each day focused on getting rich, scamming or taking from others, but I do enjoy making good money, and enjoy having a top-tier hustle to keep me living the best version of my life. I first learned to hustle on the Grateful Dead tour in the 1980s and 1990s, making my way around the country. I polished this in the lot, and the after hour parties, and increasingly the business I did along the way. By the end of the 20th Century I traded in that hustle for a new one involving technology, which by 2010, became the hustle known as the API Evangelist-—where I played the part of someone who knows everything about APIs. I find that the greatest danger of hustles occurs when you begin to believe the hustle. When you are committed to the game, you live dangerously near the line where you think the game is real. If you are going to convince others, you have to convince yourself. If you are fully invested in your hustle, there will always be mornings you wake up and realize that you have gone too far. It goes with the territory, and you have to decide whether or not you just pull the mask back over your face and keep going, or you step away from the fire and move in a new direction. Oftentimes you can’t keep up with the hustle once you have slipped past the point of believing, for fear of losing yourself. Other times you slip back in like the hustle is a comfortable old hoodie, and you get right back to it, forgetting your true self even exists. It is all a hustle. What I find fascinating about hustles is that the longer running and more powerfully funded hustles have the upper hand in the narrative. These hustlers get away with the unthinkable and often unspeakable. And people accept it as truth. It is often seen as the way things are, and when someone in a lesser role pulls the same hustle, it is deemed as being crazy, bad, or something other than the normal way of doing things. People can’t imagine getting away with something like that which is a normal place for others. The class separation of the hustle fascinates me, and once you begin to see the role that white supremacy plays in separating the institutional hustlers from the street hustlers, you realize the game is the same, but the deck is always stacked in one direction. Most people know their place and stay there. Hustlers always gotta explore the edges and push their skills to new heights. It is all a hustle. Remember...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/11/01/it-is-all-a-hustle/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Going to Bed Early is Just Preemptively Sleeping In</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/10/14/going-to-bed-early-is-just-preemptively-sleeping-in/"/>
    <updated>2023-10-14T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I went to bed pretty early last night. It was about 8:30 PM when I laid down, and about 10:00 PM before I fell asleep. As I was waking up at about 5:45 AM, I laid there thinking that going to bed was just preemptively sleeping in. I love to sleep in. I am not a morning person, although in the second half of my life I realized that I am a better person when I get up. So it makes sense for me to also begin to retire earlier in the evening.

I cherish being able to sleep in on the weekends and holidays. It is one of my favorite things to do. However I like the idea of going to bed earlier to achieve the same goal—-sleeping as much as I can. I love a good 8-9 hours of sleep in my old age. I am a better person when I get up early, so I might as well make the math work, any which way I can. If I get it on the front-end or tail-end, what does it matter? I know, I know. This is old person logic. That is OK, I am fine with that.

My 18 year old self would laugh at me. Hell, my 51 year old self is laughing at me. It is OK. Sleep is important. Getting enough sleep is probably one of the most important things I can be doing each day. Gone are the days where I stay up late coding. No more staying out partying. I’m officially old. It is OK. I had a good run. The balance is working for me, so I might as well go all in. I am getting better at planning, and I think my new preemptive sleeping in is just an example of planning for more comfort and stability in my life.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/10/14/going-to-bed-early-is-just-preemptively-sleeping-in/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Regularly Overwhelmed by the Scope of Things</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/10/07/regularly-overwhelmed-by-the-scope-of-things/"/>
    <updated>2023-10-07T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[About 3-5 times a week I get overwhelmed with the scope of things in my work. Things are just big. There is a lot going on. There are many moving parts, people, all built on a whole lot of history. I find myself feeling like I am drowning in the details and escape multiple times a week. However, thankfully, each time, within hours I am able to find a solution to whatever led to me feeling overwhelmed, and I was able to connect the dots in a way that resolved things for me. While the feelings I have are overwhelming and can give me anxiety in the moment, I enjoy all of it a lot. It is where I am good, and have potential to excel. I was driven up to Portland back in the late 1990s as I was trying to get my shit together to apply for a job with one of the top global consulting agencies. Once I got there, they sat us down and had us spend a couple of hours taking tests on computers. When we were done I went to talk to my representative who promptly told me to leave. I asked why? What had I done? He said I cheated on the tests. I said what are you talking about? He said, you scored 75% on the introductory and mid-level courses, but had scored 98% on the advanced courses. This is an assessment that tends to describe they way I am most days. I am good at complex things, but even the simplest of things can trip me up and leave me confused. Growing up in a small town I was just odd. However, living in New York City, I finally feel like I am operating at the level I need. I like large scopes. I like complex systems. I like working my way through sprawling technical landscape studying the technical, but also the business, and the people end of things. I am thankful for feeling like I am drowning 3-5 times a week, because it means I am pushing myself. It means I am swimming in the deepest end of the pool or even out in open water. I need this. As much as I’d like to just go sit on a beach or along some lake, reading books—-I need to challenge my brain. I need the scope of problems and challenges I face working at Bloomberg. Otherwise, I worry I will have even more anxiety about myself and life than I do now. I am very thankful for having found my career path. I am very thankful that I was able to successfully find my way out of a small town, and out of poverty. I just don’t think I would have survived. Literally. While it isn’t easy to get through the week working on such large projects, I fear it would be much more difficult for me to get through the week working some dead-end job in a small town....]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/10/07/regularly-overwhelmed-by-the-scope-of-things/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>That Writing Mojo</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/10/04/the-writing-mojo/"/>
    <updated>2023-10-04T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I love writing. I need to write. But once again I find myself unable to write. Well, I’ve been writing in my notebook, fleshing out some ideas, but I haven’t been publishing anything on any of my domains. This is mostly due to recently recovering being chewed up by the content factory that is expected within tech startups, but it is also the shift in the social media landscape, forcing me to ask the hard questions regarding why I publish stories. I am brutally honest with myself about these things, and I am determined to find my mojo when it comes to telling stories-—I know blogging isn’t as cool as it used to, but personally I find so much value when it comes to writing, I must find my way forward in all of this, in order to survive and thrive. Don’t get me wrong. I can turn out the content, and only about 1/3 of my writing I am proud of. There is a lot of API blah blah blah on my blogs. This isn’t about the complete body of my work, this is about the core of it, the mojo that keeps me writing and eventually producing stories I am proud of. I have a little over 4000 blog posts on API Evangelist, and about 1500 on Kin Lane, and I want to keep the momentum going, but most importantly the nutrients flowing. I learn so much when writing these stories. The conversations, research, and reading required to produce all of this work pushed me to learn so much, and resulted in some serious growth when it comes to my understanding of the technology, business, and politics of APIs. I don’t want to lose that. When an idea grabs hold of me it reminds me of watching my Rottweiler chew on one of her toys-—it clearly feels good to gnaw on that thing. I do not enjoy writing just to get other people’s attention, but it clearly is an inevitable aspect of writing. I write to make sense of things. Which I find keeps getting lost in the actual making a living part of my day. People clearly are interested in my stories because I have developed several waves of readership over the years. I have generated a significant amount of interest in my ideas when it comes to API lifecycle and governance within the enterprise. My writing is why I have a job, a career, but I regularly also suffer and freeze up due to the strain of my employment. So, how do I write, nourish myself, pay my bills, and make sense of the world around me without driving my storytelling into the ditch? As I drive out of the ditch, pause along the side of the highway, and inspect my tires, undercarriage, oil, and fuel levels, I know the answer is just keep going. Just keep writing. I feel like the age of social media is over. At least for me. I am thinking I...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/10/04/the-writing-mojo/</id>
  </entry>
</feed>
