<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Kin Lane</title>
  <updated>2023-07-25T08:00:00Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml"/>
  <author><name>Kin Lane</name></author>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id>
	<entry>
    <title>Leaving People Behind</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/07/25/leaving-people-behind/"/>
    <updated>2023-07-25T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I have long struggled and written about the people I leave behind in my life. There are a long list of people I have moved away from, severed communication with, and just evolved beyond over the years. Honestly, very, very, very few people can keep up with my mercurial approach to living, my appetite for travel and learning things, and more recently my determination to do the hard work of unraveling the programming of my youth has left even more people behind.

I am writing this to brush off the latest wave of cords that I’ve either released or have been neglected and ignored to the point that they’ll break free without much effort. I am sitting in New York in the most expensive apartment I have ever rented, going to work for a major financial data and media outlet. I struggle to find people in my life who I can discuss my success with. I can only talk to a handful of friends about what I do and how far along in my journey I am—others can’t relate, and some actively see me as rubbing it in their face and bragging.

I’d say that I only have about 5% guilt left about my success when engaging with people from my past. I’d say I’ve moved from about 60% guilt to 25% guilt in the last five years through a lot of hard work. However my last two trips to Oregon to visit friends and family, and exiting from Postman this summer has helped me get down to about 5% guilt regarding the people I leave behind. I am not cutthroat	and mean in my approach, but I don’t have many fucks to give when it comes to moving forward in the second half of my life.

I am not doing this to be snobby, rich or famous. I am simply looking to live my life to the fullest–while celebrating along the way. I avoid screwing people over financially, but I am very, very guarded when it comes to whom I let in emotionally. This is my game. You have to pay your dues to get in on the game and hustle. You also have to be moving at a similar velocity either physically, creatively, or technically—otherwise we aren’t even on the same wavelength. Historically I have done most of the work switching wavelengths, but now that I have turned 50 I am expecting others to do the work. The bar is much higher now.

]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/07/25/leaving-people-behind/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Making the Most of a Strange World</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/07/23/making-the-most-of-a-strange-world/"/>
    <updated>2023-07-23T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I’ve done a lot of thinking lately. The 3rd anniversary of Isaiahs death has me reassessing everything around me. The last three years have been surreal. The covid pandemic dictated the shape of how I see the world around me, but it was something in which Isaiah’s death had taken to new levels. The world always has seemed a little off to me, but in May and June of this year, everything seemed off and in need of shaking up. So I did just that—I shook the Etch A Sketch with all of the powers at my disposal, and in the way I saw fit. First I stopped working. Burnout had left me near total depletion. Covid took away any fucks I had to give about anything except what really mattered. Then coming up on the 3rd anniversary of Isaiah’s death and turning 51 was forcing me to think of things in very absolute terms. There was no room for unnecessary energy or activity in my life. The world is strange, and most of the time I just deal with the world on its terms, letting each day roll by as it is, but I found myself unable to do this, and in desperate need to shift the world to match exactly what I wanted and needed. The math for my job wasn’t penciling out anymore. Living in Oakland seemed tainted by Covid. Audrey seemed like she has not just recovered, but was beginning to grow and thrive again—however I needed to be sure. The world just had that weird Truman Show like quality to it, but with some disturbing and dark Instagram filter applied. Nothing seemed real. It all seemed scripted and out of my control. I needed to shake the Etch A Sketch, and redraw everything around me, otherwise I wasn’t going to unable to continue functioning. It was that serious. I don’t know how to articulate it, but if I didn’t reconfigure my life and the world around me, I wasn’t sure I would be able to continue with the regularly scheduled programming. We moved from Oakland, CA to New York, NY. I went from Postman, a startup, to Bloomberg, a well established enterprise. I spent May and June getting my head on my shoulders. I tore myself down and rebuilt myself back up. I had let myself get into pretty bad shape, though working too hard in a covid tinged world, but more importantly through ignoring my mental health. Luckily I don’t drink anymore, otherwise I think it could have been much worse. The result was still a very unwieldy couple of months emotionally, but ultimately something that was neatly wrapped up within 60 days and done in a way that caused the minimal amount of damage to Audrey, Poppy, Kaia and my well being (can’t speak for others). Something that I historically haven’t very good at, but this round I was pretty proud of my laser focus. The world is a strange place. I find...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/07/23/making-the-most-of-a-strange-world/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Do We Want a Contactless World</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/04/18/do-we-want-a-contactless-world/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-18T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[During my recent wanderings in Oakland, I came across a parking sign that promised a “Contactless” experience, which got me thinking about the concept of contactless in our world today. It’s a term we hear quite often, either explicitly stated or implied by barriers, plexiglass, or the absence of human presence. As usual, I have some questions about this phenomenon: What is contactless, exactly? Do we want a contactless world? Is contactless inherently good or bad? What are the social implications of contactless? According to the definition, contactless refers to anything that doesn’t involve physical contact or direct interaction, such as technology that enables a smart card or mobile phone to connect wirelessly to an electronic reader, often for making payments. I understand the need for social distancing during the pandemic and think it’s a sensible approach. I have also always been a fan of minimizing human contact by using self-service checkout lanes, vending machines, and other forms of automation. Although I lean towards avoiding human interaction, there are moments when I can be very good at engaging with people under any circumstances. I am torn between celebrating a contactless world and recognizing that it may not be a good thing. When I contemplate who contactless is for and what it is, I find myself in some uncomfortable places. At first glance, contactless is meant to prevent the spread of a virus, which is a positive thing. However, contactless didn’t start in 2020. Self-service and contactless mobile experiences have been evolving for some time now. Although I believe contactless is intended for consumers, I think it’s more for business reasons than for us. There are many financial, labor, and other concerns intertwined with the idea of contactless. Each contactless interaction generates one more data point to surveil, resulting in yet another digital cord attached to your digital self. Every contactless transaction throughout your day adds up, generating timestamps, surveillance photos, biometric data, and other information. While a coffee order placed with a human and paid for with cash may be captured on a security camera, the interaction does not appear on my permanent digital record. These data accumulations have significant consequences, and we have yet to discuss how they are used to shape our lives. Human interaction is crucial. We know it is essential for the development of children and continues to be important throughout our lives. It can be what keeps us alive for a long time. Losing contact with one another seems like it would be harmful to humanity. It feels like it would remove the lubricant we need to function as communities and as a society. I will spend time looking into research in this area. I am genuinely interested in understanding the impact that mobile devices are having, as well as how this phenomenon has escalated during the pandemic. I find it increasingly challenging to interact with people in public because I don’t do it as much as I used to. I’m out of practice. Although...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/04/18/do-we-want-a-contactless-world/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>How We See Things Like a Bank Collapse</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/03/19/how-we-see-things-like-a-bank-collapse/"/>
    <updated>2023-03-19T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I have been thinking about the storytelling surrounding the recent collapse of the Silicon Valley Bank (SVB) a lot lately. I just gave a talk at a company retreat about the importance of storytelling, and how all dimensions of the SVB situation is about telling and believing in stories. From our belief in money, markets, banks, to our continued belief in technology and venture capital, the recent goings on was all about stories. A significant part of this storytelling involves how we see things, and when you have very abstract concepts like financial products, businesses, and technology, the images we use to understand what is happening. When it came to SVB I particularly noticed the usage of images involving the front of SVB bank branches.

Hey, what is going on in there?


Let’s have a dude making a phone call in front!


Let’s get some security guards out front to make it look like something of value is in there.


Let’s make sure to show that they are responding to customers.


Ok, people are getting the message.


Show a money truck in front to show there is money.


Let’s just show people hanging out having fun.


Let’s be a little more creative with a reflection.


Throughout the goings on of the last couple of weeks I was just tuned into the storytelling, and the visuals that media sites and blogs were using grabbed my attention. I love that our notion of a bank is still so anchored on the notion of a physical bank with vaults of cash. That when there is a digital run on a bank we still need images of physical locations to tell our stories. All of this stuff is so very abstract, and out of reach of our imaginations, despite spending so much of our time online.

I feel like our inability to see complex financial products and the expanding digital landscape that shapes our lives is something that is going to continue to disrupt our lives. I think our world is increasingly complex and nobody has a complete picture in their head about how it all works. This allows for some seriously messed up hustles to occur on multiple levels, and is something that will take years for us all to understand the impact our financial system has had on our lives.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/03/19/how-we-see-things-like-a-bank-collapse/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Things Are Hard</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/02/26/things-are-hard/"/>
    <updated>2023-02-26T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am struggling lately. I made it through the kid passing, covid, and managed to quit drinking, lose a bunch of weight, and get healthier, only to be really, really struggling in this moment. I want to make sure and document this moment in the calendar, if nothing else just to be able to look back and remind myself of the ups and downs of being Kin Lane. I have a well-paid job, amazing team, and yet I am struggling with showing up to work and giving a shit. It has been about 3 weeks now, and while I seem to have gotten through the worst, I am really finding it challenging to show up for work each day. I am four years into my job and it is the longest I’ve had a job in decades. I love my work. I love my team. I struggle with capitalism. I struggle with working at a fast-growing startup. I struggle with working in technology. I struggle just being Kin Lane. I wish I could put my finger on exactly what it is, but it is clearly approach burn-out levels. I’ve seen it before. I am working hard to find balance and step away from work on the weekend, but it can be challenging to leave it behind. The only way I can do it is to take long weekends and get out of the house and go somewhere in the RV. It is the only that stops the brain, heals the body, but sadly it doesn’t seem to be enough to get me through the week. I hear a lot of folks are going through this right now. People from all over the world, from all industries, are just hitting the wall. Sadly, I think that business leadership doesn’t see this, or simply doesn’t care. Or maybe they are hitting their own kind of wall. I am at the top of my game, and I’d gladly take a massive pay cut to be able to work for myself again and switch back to the freelance or small business hustle. It seems so dumb. I am paid very well, but I am just not feeling the mojo. I have amazing work on the table, but I am just not feeling the mojo. I can’t help it is the result of some collective squeezing by the man right now that is leaving me in this state. I feel like we are all getting squeezed and despite my privileged position, I can’t help but emotionally feel solidarity with the rest of the tech workers and other industries being consumed by technology. I can’t help but feel complicit. This is what I mean when I say that I spend my days reducing everything to a transaction, as I translate our very meaningful physical worlds into digital API transactions. I feel like I work for the “nothing”. You know that all-consuming presence from the Never-ending Story? I feel like I am complicit in sucking the life...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/02/26/things-are-hard/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Becoming a Hunter Gatherer in the Information Age</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2023/01/05/becoming-a-hunter-gatherer-in-the-information-age/"/>
    <updated>2023-01-05T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I was watching a documentary on Fat the other night on PBS. They were conducting a study on a tribe in Africa to better understand why they don’t struggle with obesity and heart disease. The long story short is that our challenges with obesity is wrapped in a mix of our genes, processed foods, and our sedentary existence. The tribe in Africa is just always on the go, and they aren’t eating food that is as processed as ours is, and they have been doing this for many, many generations. I am guessing that our weight problems aren’t the only problems we face due this reality we’ve constructed for ourselves, and I am guessing that many of our mental health challenges are a result of our diet and lack of activity. Leaving me thinking both about my physical and mental health as I move into 2023, an enjoy my 50th year on this planet. I have done a lot of work to get a handle on my physical health this last year. However, I can do more. I am still not in as good of shape as I need to be. I want to be stronger. I want to be more active. I have also done a lot of work to get a handle on my mental health in recent years. However, I can do more. I still have highs and lows, and some days I struggle to function at all. I’ve done well without medication, and watching my friends struggle with different types of diagnosis and side effects of pharmaceuticals, I am confident I am on the right track. I am able to strike a balance between maintaining my passion, drive, creativity, as well as know when I’m slipping into depression or some other worse state. With this said, I feel like much of my mental health challenges are just due to regular old capitalism and making our way in this fucked up world. I am pretty convinced that if I didn’t work so much, and spend so much time online, I would be in much better shape. This is something I’d like to understand more, and make adjustments over the next couple of years. While I love my work, I don’t love all that comes with working at a fast moving startup, managing a large team, and spending so much time online. I am good at what I do. I am paid well. I also work at one of the best startups around. I am definitely top of my field. Yet, I still struggle showing up and being present every day. I feel like this is due to 1) work &amp;amp; capitalism, and 2) being online. I don’t mind working hard. I enjoy it. I hate everything that comes with a job. I also am getting sick of being online all day. I want to be offline, but I struggle with how I will maintain the quality of life I enjoy working in technology. I grew up poor,...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2023/01/05/becoming-a-hunter-gatherer-in-the-information-age/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Some See What Is Missing but I See Opportunity to Build</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/12/28/some-see-what-is-missing-but-i-see-opportunity-to-build/"/>
    <updated>2022-12-28T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[Over the Thanksgiving holiday I setup Mastodon instances for my personal and professional domains. Over the last month I’ve invested time into understanding how this federated world works and doesn’t work, and began doing the hard work of building community in this new space. Numerous folks from my Twitter community have come over to Mastodon, but many I know have opted to stay in the Twitterverse, or opted to join other communities for a variety of reasons. The main reason I’ve seen is that there is nothing happening in the Fediverse once they sign up. They don’t see their people, their topics, or anything going on, leaving them wondering why you’d want to be in this universe in the first place.

Maybe it is because I was there to help build Twitter, as well as numerous other communities in the early days, or I am just a builder mentality, but I see nothing but opportunity to build community within the Fediverse. In addition to seeing opportunity to build community I see a number of the historians, librarians, journalists, artists, and other people I see being essential to any community already jumping from Twitter to Mastodon. While many other tech people touted the technology, and specifically API behind the early growth and adoption of Twitter, I saw these people being present and acting as the essential building blocks of creating what matters within a community. Either way, I see the potential for building what is missing when it comes to injecting the social in my life.

It can be overwhelming to start over, and to have to entirely rebuild your entire social life. I get it, most people are just about the social part when things are already in motion. Most people are just looking for their people, and want to get to the business of being entertained and socializing. I don’t think everyone should or would see the world as I do, and I think many of these folks will end up switching in the next wave of social upheaval on not just Twitter, but also Facebook, Instagram, and the other platforms that have dominated how we see and engage with the digital world around us. I am very excited about the potential on Mastodon, but I have a lot of learning about how it all works, and building to do when it comes to my network, but also trust when it comes to making my way through all the diverse communities popping up in this exciting virtual world.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/12/28/some-see-what-is-missing-but-i-see-opportunity-to-build/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Dispatch From Coaling Station A</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/12/22/dispatch-from-coaling-station-a-copy/"/>
    <updated>2022-12-22T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[We made it as far as Coalinga, CA, formerly known as Coaling Station A, before dark. This is where we’ll be spending two nights here before we continue on through Bakersfield to the edges of Death Valley. As one journeys to Death Valley you have to suspend your traditional views of the world, and no better place to do that than amongst the almond and orange orchards looking out across Interstate 5 outside of Coalinga, CA.



Coalinga is a place I’ve only known as the place you drive by on Interstate 5 that smells like cow poop. In my older age and during my RVing journeys I am all about leaving my past assumptions about any person, place, or thing, and I am looking to experience Coalinga with a fresh and open mind. While I am not staying in Coalinga proper, the RV park we are in, provides a nice slice of what it is like to live in the agriculturally dominated area. 

I did a little historical search on our area, learning that the area was originally a coaling station for the Southern Pacific Railroad, and according to the Wikipedia page, “the city’s main industries are agriculture, oil, Cannabis, education and incarceration”. Which seems like a nice diverse set of investments if you ask me. After a leisurely drive through the town, I can concur, that seems to be the leading industries in the area.

It’s hard around here. Trucks. People with hard looks on their face. People who have been hard done by. Combined with the cold spelling we are experiencing, it doesn’t leave much to explore and get to know. It is a truck area, so you have to drive to see anything and everything. It really isn’t cold. Just California cold. Keeping everyone indoors, or at least parked with your car running, while you wait for who knows what.

I’ve driven by the Interstate 5 Freeway sign for Coalinga probably over 100 times. Always hitting the accelerator. This time I stopped and stayed for no real reason, other than it was the halfway point between home and my Death Valley destination. That was enough to make me stop this time. I can’t say that I will be coming back and staying the area, but I am thankful for stopping and strolling through the Orange and Almond orchards, and visiting the old town.

We will pack up in the morning, hitch up the trailer, and head for the lower Sierras, and make our way up to where the desert meets the mountains. It is here where our next adventure will begin. Coaling Station A was just a pit stop at the beginning of this journey, a cold, evenly rowed, isolated place. I am sure I will travel near Coalinga many more times in my life, and each time I can think about this one time when I stopped and took it in for just a moment.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/12/22/dispatch-from-coaling-station-a-copy/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Twitter and Our Public Health</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/12/18/twitter-and-our-public-health/"/>
    <updated>2022-12-18T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[As we all sit and watch the dumpster fire that is Twitter it can be easy to cheer on the demise of this platform. Although as I stare into the multi-color flames I can’t help but think about tall the work we’ve done on the Twitter plantation of the years, and the role it plays it our world. One are that comes to mind is how many of us received public health news as Covid gripped the world via Twitter. I spent months working on a Covid tracking website that primarily used the Twitter API to pull information from the state and county health departments who all use Twitter. I automated pulling of data from government health agencies and then aggregated it and pushed I back out all using the Twitter API — this will be hard to repeat in the future.

While someday we may be able to get municipal, county, and state health departments to adopt a more federated approach to social media, I am guessing it will take years, and not reach the saturation levels of agencies as well as consistent tuned in that we have on Twitter today. Knowing how government agencies work, it will take some serious champions and evangelists to support standing up Mastodon servers for government agencies to see a more federated approach to social media and sharing of public health data with the masses. While I am fine with having to rebuild my social realm, and even see it as an opportunity, I can’t help but think about what we are collectively losing by letting Elon Musk set fire to the Twitterers we all worked so hard to build.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/12/18/twitter-and-our-public-health/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Staying Within the Machine</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/12/18/staying-within-the-machine/"/>
    <updated>2022-12-18T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I made a conscious decision in 1997 to immerse myself in the incoming technological apparatus that capitalism was unleashing on the world. Until this moment in time I had purposefully avoided capitalism, a career, and understanding how business was applying technology. I had spent the previous decade actively working to subvert the system from the outside-in, and for me to have the impact I wanted on society I knew that I had to get closer to the machine and operate from within, otherwise I was just going to be chewed up by the machine. I noticed how well-designed the machine was at targeting, destroying, or simply locking up threats that were outside the system, but just how difficult it was for the machine to target in between its own gears—this is where I needed to be. I spent the first ten years of this centruy just studying the machine. I needed to know how it was going to work. Once I began to understand how things work I began looking for ways to subvert the machine. To tell stories about how we can still live within the machine, while also throwing our bodies against the machine. You have to learn to tell stories very loudly, and as demonstrated recently with the switch in power via the Twittersphere, you have to be ready to pack up and move to a different part of the machine at any moment. There are two reasons I position myself where I am at, 1) to understand how the machine works so my stories are relevant to the hum of the machine, and 2) make it more difficult to be targeted by the machine for extermination or incarceration. If I am playing along, my stories sound familiar and relevant to folks, but sticking around and keeping my storytelling going is the number one way I do this hustle. I know that you can live a life outside the machine. It isn’t easy, and you have to learn to do without. I may go there at some point. But for now, I’ve kind of learned to enjoy the game. I just have to keep reminding myself why I’m here. I have to not let the sounds of the machine drive me mad, or force me to lose my soul. I have to internalize the sounds and vibrations of the machine, and empathize with the emotions of those who exist around me perpetually to find the stories that matter to us in any given moment. I regularly struggle staying sane and coherent amongst all the noise, and perpetually find myself unable to find the signal that matters, despite years of evidence to the contrary. I’ll keep on keep’n on within this state of existence for as long as I can. At some point I fully expect to need to step away, but I’ve gotten to know the machine so well, it has kind of become an old friend. Not for the service it does to its master, but...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/12/18/staying-within-the-machine/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>An Apocalypse Groundhog Day</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/12/04/an-apocalypse-groundhog-day/"/>
    <updated>2022-12-04T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I haven’t been writing about my apocalyptic upbringing lately because for the most part I’ve moved beyond it. Writing here on my blog and pondering the subject since the 2016 election has put me in a pretty sweet spot when it comes to living life and not stressing about the programming I was raised with. However, recently a story was shared with me about someone I grew up with sharing rantings about how the apocalypse was just around the corner and wanted to make sure this person I was talking to was fully prepared. This person has a much more caring approach to sharing upcoming apocalyptic news than some of the other people I grew up with who take a much more “you are either with us or against us” attitude about each upcoming apocalypse, but still the same narrative applies. This person was one of the origins of my anxiety on this subject, with warnings going back to about 1985. I remember the early warnings of nuclear apocalypse and being given a gun by this person. Something that would repeat regularly, but the most notable were the mid 1980s nuclear war, and the 2000 Y2K bug. I’ve been pretty angry for the last decade or so at this person, as I was making my way out of this nonsense, but more recently I am pretty sad for them that they are stuck in a sort of apocalyptic Groundhog Day. Playing out over and over, but they never quite are able to see that their apocalyptic beliefs are more about them and less about the world around them. I feel sad for them, but not bad enough where I’ll spend much time trying to convince them otherwise—-I spent years trying that unsuccessfully. I’d prefer just living my life and keeping myself convinced that while there are plenty of scary things in the world to focus on, life is amazing, and totally worth living in the moment. I can now see how genuinely afraid this person is of the world. I can see how their view of the world is derived from simmering in medium-grade toxic masculinity, exacerbated by an actual toxic environment of lead, plastics, oils, and other substances we are poisoning our world with. I’ve seen this person physically fight other men, siphon lead gas from trucks, and remember their stories of how they used to eat lead from the window sill as a child. I just don’t think at this point they are aware of the toxicity they’ve basted in for most of their life, and they sure can’t see the chain yanking they’ve responded to over the generations from politicians and the wealthy to keep them very afraid of cities, and people from other countries. The fear is so vivid now, but in 1985 and 2000 I couldn’t see it. I just experienced, felt, and channeled it. Now I just see someone who is very isolated and afraid, and unable to see that they’ve spent their entire...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/12/04/an-apocalypse-groundhog-day/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Redlining: A Drive Down Grand Avenue in Oakland</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/11/27/posting-a-message-nobody-reads-copy/"/>
    <updated>2022-11-27T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I was driving my friend and fellow API conspirator Fran Mendez around Oakland this week while he was in town from Spain. I regularly drive people around Oakland, and most have had some experience in the city, but most have experienced West Oakland, and have very little awareness of the redlining that has shaped the city. Most people just see poverty and trash and assume a traditional racist stance and think that the people living here have chosen to live like this. When in reality, it has been engineered and orchestrated. To demonstrate, I wanted to drive Grand Avenue in Oakland, traveling from the higher grade areas to the lower grade areas in a “Residential Security Map” from the 1930s, which was used to shape the city we live in and experience today.

If you pay attention to the video as you approach the redline you begin to see less investment, and then you experience the edge of the redline defined by the freeway. When this map was created, the freeway did not exist, it was added along the line. Once you cross the line you begin to see trends alongside the road, more abandoned stores, and a general lack of investment. You begin to see some new construction of residential and office space, and there is evidence of manufacturing going on, but the impact of planning almost 100 years ago is still evident. I have a video driving the other which I may play with some, and I have one driving up San Pablo towards Berkeley, and back again which I may turn into a video as well. I am not that skilled at working with video, but this is giving me some practice, while also helping me convey how these historical relics are still shaping our world today.
]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/11/27/posting-a-message-nobody-reads-copy/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Posting a Message Nobody Reads</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/11/26/posting-a-message-nobody-reads/"/>
    <updated>2022-11-26T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I had just stood up the Mastodon instance for my API Evangelist account, logged in, and was staring at the empty message box. What would I say? I had no followers. Nobody would be listening even if I did say something. So I followed my Kin Lane account, and then followed API Evangelist back. Now at least I would be talking to myself. This seems much more appropriate. I don’t need an audience. I’ve always (that’s a lie) done API Evangelist for myself, and secondarily for others. Over the last decade of storytelling I’ve developed a pantheon of characters I am talking to when I publish any stories. Some were made up from real people I come across in my adventures, others are made up entirely just to fit in with the narrative I am peddling. I like to pretend I don’t need an audience, but I am also hyper aware of an on again and off again need to feed the ego, and actually have someone out there reading and engaging with my writing. It is terrifying to not have any social followers. A significant portion of my social presence is wrapped up in my identity as the API Evangelist and now the Chief Evangelist. Twitter has played a significant role in feeding my ego, and paying the bills. You experience ego whiplash when you go from 13.6K followers on Twitter to 0 followers on Mastodon. I have 17K followers on my Kin Lane Twitter, and experienced the same whiplash twice over this week. Honestly, I love it though. A little ego flattening is essential in this world. However, it isn’t just ego, and I’ve honestly been working on the Twitter plantation since 2007, and these 13.5K + 17K followers are the building blocks of digital identity. Not just my identity, but my career. I’ve made a couple of million dollars through my blog and my Twitter account since 2010. So, should I be grateful to Twitter for this? Is it purely their “network effect”? Or is this just a fraction of what I could have made if I couldn’t have fully controlled my contribution to the Twitter community? Similar to what I am now doing with Mastodon? Rebuilding all over again. What happens when I am suddenly nobody? Well, that is a little dramatic, as many of my API people were pretty easy to find on Mastodon. I guess some of my brand translates. Partly because I’ve built in on the apievangelist.com domain. Grounding my storytelling within my own domain(s), and being thoughtful about which networks I engage on, and syndicating my stories to is the number one reason I’ve been able to make a living through my use of social media. I am not afraid of having to rebuild this via Mastodon, and other federated solutions. I am not quitting Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, and other networks. They are necessary evils to a certain degree. I am even considering how I can leverage other platforms I’ve used like...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/11/26/posting-a-message-nobody-reads/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>I Have My Mastodon Instance for Kin Lane Set Up</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/11/25/i-have-my-mastodon-instance-for-kin-lane-setup/"/>
    <updated>2022-11-25T07:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I have been simmering on the whole Twitter drama lately, and the mass migration to Mastodon. As I said before, I am not being emotional about this, and want to think about this in the context of what I consider to be my overall domain strategy. I run my own websites, blogs, email, and I think the time has come for me to own my social network. It makes me sad and a little mad to see what is happening to Twitter, and while I won’t be deleting my account or going anywhere soon, I do want to explore what Mastodon has to offer, and consider how it fits into my world. I use Twitter for a lot more than just talking with my friends. I use it to research things. I automate curation and syndication of my stories using the API. And it is one of the last few social applications I will allow on my mobile phone. Twitter is still very important to me, but I think it is time to begin laying the foundation for my social presence within my domain(s) using Mastodon. After some noodling I decided to install my own Mastodon server. I have the skills and resources to do this, and it is important to me that I understand the inner workings of it all. I operate my world on Amazon Web Services, so I spun up a Debian Linux EC2 instance, and got to work setting up my social presence—-I followed this setup script (https://www.linuxbabe.com/debian/install-mastodon-debian-server), but then made it my own. The first time I did it I created a user called “info” and made a few mistakes in how I configured my AWS S3 storage and other things, but ultimately I ended up with a working single user instance of Mastodon under the kinlane.com domain. This will be my personal and professional social domain, where I focus on the things that matter to me as a human being online. Next, I will get to work setting one up for my apievangelist.com domain, but for now I am learning the ropes with my more personal instance. While you won’t find me becoming all evangelical about Mastodon to others, you will find me talking a lot about how I use it moving forward. I can solidly see where it fits into my infrastructure stack. Social is very important to me, and Elon Musk and Twitter are squandering a lot of work I’ve put into that platform over the years. I am willing to do all this work over again, but I am not looking to do it too many more times. I feel like we are hitting this threshold with platforms and technology in general, but not all of us will be able to sort it all out. I feel like having Elon Musk acting like this out in public is doing us all a favor, because this is happening behind the scenes of many of the platforms we are using, they are just...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/11/25/i-have-my-mastodon-instance-for-kin-lane-setup/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>My New Jekyll Template</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/10/16/my-new-jekyll-template/"/>
    <updated>2022-10-16T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I got some inspiration lately and went hunting for a new Jekyll Theme to rule my blog universe. I love blogging across my domains, and I love the storytelling scaffolding of a Jekyll site running on Github. The balance of words and data with a GitOps API-driven approach to things just works for my brand of storytelling. This new “docs” themed template (https://jekyll-theme-docs.netlify.app/) has everything I love about Jekyll from a storytelling perspective but they have gone the extra distance with collections and the mix of data, blogs, pages, and the magic of a static website. If you don’t get Jekyll it can be difficult to see, but if you do, you really understand the magic of YAML-driven data and words combined with FREE website hosting via GitHub pages. I have now applied this template across my four top domains, Kin Lane, Alternate Kin Lane, Algorotoscope, and API Evangelist. For some reason blogging is my primary mode of storytelling. I find it difficult to write just in my notebook. There is some public performance and ego to what I do, but honestly I am not driven by page views or engagement. It just has to be published publicly on a blog for it to matter. It has happened. It is real. Once it lives within a domain on the web. Weird I know, but it is the only way I can reliably produce the content, visuals, and storytelling I need to move forward. So be it. Anyways, Jekyll and GitHub has played an important role in this storytelling evolution because of the ease in publishing stories, essays, and landing pages via a simple static blog. This “Docs” template has a lot of the usual things I like, but it also has a few bells and whistles, and work invested in information qrchitecture that makes it a delight to work with. First and foremost this new template has a search. Which in a static realm isn’t trivial. Since all my sites act as a sort of archive and memory for me, this is something I have wanted for some time now. The way it setup its “docs” section provided me with a blueprint for how I can organize existing bodies of stories and data, but also how I can incrementally organize, iterate, and evolve new stories. For example, I am able to better tag stories on API Evangelist and surface them in “docs” or “info” sections like design or governance. I can also just write like the wind over time and dump into the “posts” folder and then on a regular basis evaluate what I have written and organize into a more curated outline of topics. This template also has RSS, Atom, Sitemap.xml, and some other utility capabilities that just make things a lot easier to manage. Overall it is a power template that really maximizes the potential of a GitOps Jekyll approach to storytelling, which I’ll be taking full advantage of from my API-first view of things. I have some...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/10/16/my-new-jekyll-template/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>The Makeup of My Anxiety</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/09/24/the-makeup-of-my-anxiety/"/>
    <updated>2022-09-24T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I struggle with anxiety. I have most of my life. I have been able to find balance with it on a daily and weekly basis, and while I am able to function and even move forward, the impact of it in the moment is massive and heavy most days. I choose to find my own way through this jungle, as opposed to a pharmaceutical route, and have developed a number of coping mechanisms. But, as I get older I continue to seek more solutions, and as I roll over 50 years of age I think I have found the most effective tool in my toolbox–creativity. Through lots of journaling, I have been able to identify that most of my anxiety comes from a lack of creativity and nourishment in my days due to work, life, and the world around me. Let’s see if I can articulate what I am seeing in my head. My anxiety is directly proportionate to the lack of creativity and investment in the human Kin each day. The more I work. The more time I spend online. The more anxiety I have. The more creative I am. The more writing I do. The more art I make. The more books I read. The less anxiety I have. I have weeks, and even years that my anxiety is light. These are the times where I spend the majority of my days telling stories and nourishing my brain and body with creative endeavors. The times my anxiety hits me the hardest are the times I neglect giving myself evenings and weekends, and I invest all of my energy in my work and career, which also involves spending a great deal of time online, outside of the physical realm. It is so easy to neglect oneself in todays’ busy world. In recent years I have spent a lot of time analyzing my work ethic, career trajectory, and the impact capitalism has on my health and well-being. I am successful by all financial measures. I am no longer living in poverty, and have an extremely well paid job at the top of my field of work. However, with this success my anxiety on a weekly level has increased. However, along with this success I have managed to keep reading, writing, making art, and nourishing my creative side. Granted, I am not doing it to the levels I would like, but it is still there, providing me with the ability to better understand my anxiety, and increase or decrease my dosage of creativity to better manage my anxiety. Through simple experiments, it is clear that creative nourishment is what is missing when it comes to my ongoing anxiety. The trick now is to properly administer the right dosage of creativity that keeps me on track with my anxiety. It can be hard to remember to be creative in a busy day of work. With a lot of responsibility and work on my plate, it is easy for the day to get...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/09/24/the-makeup-of-my-anxiety/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>A List of Books that Helped Me Recently</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/08/21/a-list-of-books-that-helped-me-recently/"/>
    <updated>2022-08-21T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[Once I began seeing family members start dropping like flies when it came to voting for Trump in 2016 election I knew there was no turning back for me. I’ve long been on a quest to come to terms with my own complicity in white supremacy, and this was the opportunity for me to shift things into overdrive and understand more about why and how I saw the world around me. After Trump was elected i wanted to develop better understand how people I care about could believe in such a horrible human being, and ultimately be so fearful of the world “out there”. Ever since 2016 I have been on a journey to come to t3erms this reality, but more importantly I wanted open my eyes and push myself to be a better human being, and be the change I wanted so desperately to see in the world. There are many other books that I’ve read that have shifted how I see the world in the last seven years, but these ones have specifically helped me better understand my white family members, unwind the programming I have been exposed to in my youth, and learn to develop empathy for marginalized human beings around me. Bunk - The Rise of Hoaxes, Humbug, Plagiarists, Phonies, Post-Facts, and Fake News - by Kevin Young White Trash - The 400-Year Untold History of Class in America -By Nancy Isenberg Educated - By Tara Westover - Westover recounts overcoming her survivalist Mormon family in order to go to college, and emphasizes the importance of education in enlarging her world. Stamped From The Beginning - The Definitive History of Racist Ideas in America - By Ibram X. Kendi Evicted - Poverty and Profit in the American City - By Matthew Desmond Women, Race &amp;amp; Class - A powerful study of the women’s liberation movement and the tangled knot of oppression facing Black women - By Angela Y. Davis Freedom Is a Constant Struggle - Ferguson, Palestine, and the Foundations of a Movement - By Angela Y. Davis Loaded - A Disarming History of the Second Amendment - by Roxanne Dunbar-Ortiz The Warmth of Other Suns -The Epic Story of America’s Great Migration - by Ijeoma Oluo Braiding Sweetgrass - Indigenous Wisdom, Scientific Knowledge and the Teachings of Plants - By Robin Wall Kimmerer The Color of Law - A Forgotten History of How Our Government Segregated America - By Richard Rothstein How the Word Is Passed - A Reckoning with the History of Slavery Across America - by Clint Smith The 1619 Project - A reframing of American history that placed slavery and its continuing legacy at the center of our national narrative. - By Nikole Hannah-Jones Mediocre - The Dangerous Legacy of White Male America - by Ijeoma Oluo After reading these books, there is no turning back. I just put down Mediocre, and the conclusion perfectly summed up this quest I have been on. I get where much of my anxiety comes from...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/08/21/a-list-of-books-that-helped-me-recently/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>I Made It. I Survived.</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/06/25/i-made-it-i-survived/"/>
    <updated>2022-06-25T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I turned 50. This is a big milestone for anyone. For me personally, it is everything. As a result of the programming I received from those I grew up with, as I approached being an adult, I assumed I would die by the time I was 30. This isn’t me being dramatic at 50. Me, and several of my friends believed wholeheartedly that we would die is some grand event before we were 30 years old (couple friends achieved). This belief didn’t originate from any single source, but was an aggregate of the bleak, scary, and fearful reality that I grew up in. leave me rolling over 50, a pretty proud moment for me. I made it. I survived. This moment is all mine. I am sure I can find a few individuals to thank for helping me out, as well as find a few individuals who I could blame for not helping out, but ultimately I made it here because of my determination and belief that this life was worth living, and this beautiful world of ours was worth being a part of. I am really proud of myself. Despite all of the trouble in the world at any given moment, I am committed to continuing to live as long as I possibly can, and for to make this world better in any way that I can. I am love with who I have become, my one biological offspring I managed to bring into this world, my amazing wife and partner in crime, and my joyous Rottweiler best friend Poppy. One of the greatest contributors to me thinking I would die before 30 was the bleak landscape painted by elders in my rural white community. From my early days I remember hearing stories of how the Russians were going to invade, that nuclear war was inevitable, and the our own government would be coming for us at any moment. When you are marinated in this from any early age, you believe it. Every knock on the door could be the government coming for your guns and the livelihood you have managed to scratch out. Looking back, I can’t help but think about what a prison this is. None of the events foretold ever came true, but most of these people I knew are still spinning the same old fearful yarns about financial and societal collapse, without any self-reflection regarding why these things have’t come to be, or the damage they are causing to young people in their orbit. When you are a young man growing up in this reality, it can be hard to hold out any hope for the future. Why go to college when the world is going to end? Why have savings in the bank when the government will just take it? You learn to live in the moment, perpetually at your own expense. It becomes a reality that you can never see beyond. Everything out “there” is just dangerous and scary, and probably looking to...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/06/25/i-made-it-i-survived/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Processing the Last Couple of Weeks</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/06/12/processing-the-last-couple-of-weeks/"/>
    <updated>2022-06-12T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am sitting on the couch at home in Oakland after an emotional week traveling to and from Southern Oregon. Leading up to Isaiah’s birthday and two years after he passed away from an overdose, his mother and I wanted to do something meaningful to celebrate his life. After two years of isolation due to Covid-19, we felt like it was time to get out, and I thought it would be a good idea to retrace some of the hikes I did back in 2016 as part of our Drone Recovery summer. So, Audrey, Poppy, and I loaded up the car and drove up to Southern Oregon and eventually Northern California, which would end up being a very emotional and unexpected set of journeys in the woods, on the beach, and in our hearts. I have stepped back and thought about this journey in five separate parts, writing about each portion of the journey as it’s own post, but then stepping even further back to consider our journey as a whole, and think a little bit about what it means for the future. While there was plenty of other parts of our journey, I felt like these five areas impacted me the post as we made our way through this challenging time in our life. Having the Strength to Power on Through - My work is a big part of my identity and focus right now, and has provided me with the few to get through everything we’ve been going through. I am very thankful for my career and the job I have right now, but it doesn’t come without it’s challenges as I try to navigate Isaiah, his mom’s grief, my health, and everything else that is Kin Lane. I entered the last couple of weeks with a lot of anxiety and I am leaving it feeling very confident and on solid ground when it comes to work and what I do as a person. Making it to the Top - Audrey, Poppy, and I hiked to the top of Kerby Peak this last week, making for a very emotional and physically challenging ascent up the 5500+ feet mountain. The weather didn’t comply and it was raining as we hiked to the peak and made for a very dark and windy summit, but it all just added to the catharsis of the moment. I was very thankful for being able to share this mountain with Audrey, and with Isaiah. It is a magical place, and it makes it even more magical to be able to connect Audrey with her son who has passed. What are we doing to Our Kids - We couldn’t make it up to the second hike I had planned for Audrey and I due to a forest fire that occurred the summer that Isaiah passed. Apparently the fire lookout station where Isaiah and I spent the day had burned, as well as miles of forest around it. With heavy hearts we made our way back...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/06/12/processing-the-last-couple-of-weeks/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Thankful for My Girls</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/06/10/thankful-for-my-girls/"/>
    <updated>2022-06-10T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[One of the highlight of this last week, as well as my life in general is my girls, Audrey and Poppy (and Kaia who is in Korea at the moment). As I step back and evaluate the week I am full of gratitude for Audrey and Poppy. They are my rocks. My inspiration. My heart. None of this would be happening without Audrey as my sidekick and I am not sure we would be functioning human beings after Isaiah’s passing without the Poppy dog. I cannot end this week of processing without acknowledging the role these two play in me being a happy and functioning part of society—Audrey and Poppy mean the world to me. Watching Audrey throughout our relationship has been a massive learning experience, but most watching her the last two years since Isaiah’s passing has been a humbling journey. Watching a mother lose her son, and not just make her way through the grief, but come out healthier, stronger, and more optimistic about life has helped me figure out my own way through this fucked up world. I was balling at the top of Kerby Peak as I took this picture, overcome with emotion as I brought Audrey to the same summit I brought Isaiah back in 2016. Audrey making it to the top of Kerby Peak was symbolic for me of everything she has worked through as a mother over the last couple of years. I look forward to coming back to Kerby Peak every year with her, seeing how strong she (and me) has become. Like Kerby Peak, the trail for us since Isaiah passing has been full of beauty, switchbacks, rocks, and many other challenges and emotional moments. I am very thankful for being on this journey with such a strong woman, but one that is willing to explore the world with me and make the most of our time left on this earth. I am so very thankful for Audrey. Alongside Audrey, there is the Poppy dog! This 80 pounds of joy we rescued while in depths of sadness the month after Isaiah passed, only to rescue the two of us. Poppy is the flower that has grown from Isaiah’s overdose, and filters all the sadness and anger we have from all of this into an ongoing stream of joy and adventure. I can’t articulate strongly enough about how much this dog means to me. She has brought so much joy to our life since Isaiah passed, and she is perpetually teaching us how to live in the moment and find joy in even the littles of things. I hate getting up in the morning, and this dog has me getting up at 5 or 6 AM every morning, even on the weekends. This derpy bundle of love is always excited for a walk, adventure, or just a simple game as we lay on a hotel bed. Like Audrey and Kaia, Poppy dog has a grip on my heart that terrifies me, but...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/06/10/thankful-for-my-girls/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Stop Taking The Long Way Around</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/06/09/stop-taking-the-long-way-around/"/>
    <updated>2022-06-09T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[We spent the second half of our journey this week in Crescent City, CA, a little town on the coast of the Oregon and California border. It is a town I have a lot of history with, and a town I have literally gone out of my way to bypass for the last 30 years. I was skeptical of spending time in Crescent City, but I wanted to try and revisit some of the trails Isaiah and I hike in the redwoods back in 2016. Like with Isaiah, I suspended by dislike of the town while I was there with Audrey, and try to recreate a meaningful experience during our time processing the death of the kid. But, like many other points along the way, II found that this wasn’t just about the kid, and our time Crescent City became more about me than just the kid and Audrey. We weren’t able to recreate the hikes that Isaiah and I did in the redwoods because dogs weren’t allowed on the paths. We did manage to find one path off to the side of Jedidiah Smith State Park where we could make a loop through some very beautiful redwood groves, which Poppy loved. Once we completed this hike we made our way through downtown Crescent City to our hotel, setting camp for the next couple of days. When we woke up the next morning we walked through town to a coffee place that supposedly had decent breakfast burritos, and I found myself really grumpy having to walk alongside the highway through town, but as we made our way back we realized there was a formal walking path through the parks and harbor that left me in a much better mood. The next morning we drove north of the city to a lake area where we walked through beautiful forests and meadows, completing a 4.5 loop through the mouth of the Smith River. This was an entirely new hike for both Audrey and I, and slowly I realized that this portion of the journey would be more about me than it was about Isaiah. I had a lot of baggage regarding this area, and as I began unraveling the why and what behind my dislike for the area, it became clear that it was baggage I could do away with. The hike around the lake, and the new-found walking path through downtown energized me, and the state of processing I found myself in for the week due to Isaiah, once again left me wide open for unpacking and dealing with more of my own shit. The next day we discovered the Azteca Grill inside the nearby Chevron, who served up very high quality and genuine breakfast burritos, and made use of the walking path to visit the lighthouse, but also tapped into the beach south of the city next to our hotel. Walking the beach to the end and back was about 7 miles providing a very lovely but also physically intense...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/06/09/stop-taking-the-long-way-around/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>What We Are We Doing to Our Kids</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/06/07/what-are-we-doing-to-our-kids/"/>
    <updated>2022-06-07T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[Another hike I did with Isaiah back in 2016 as part of our Drone Recovery summer was up to Bolan Lake Lookout. Like Kerby Peak, I found that Isaiah was more alert and aware up at Bolan Lake, and he even smiled for me as we were goofing around at the lookout. After Kerby Peak, Bolan Lake Lookout was the next place I wanted to share with Audrey, so that we could make the place behind this picture a little more real for her. Bolan Lake was a place I spent a lot of time as a child, and it was a place I was happy to share with Isiah, and now with Audrey. Bolan Lake is a beautiful wildness lake with a 3 mile trail up to the summit where there is a beautiful fire lookout with an amazing view of the Illinois Valley. Well, it used to have all of that, until it burned in the 2020 Slater fire. According to the Forest Service the lookout was completely burned in the fire, and I couldn’t verify what condition the area around the lake was because we couldn’t get through, but the damage we did see broke my heart. As we drove up from the valley floor, the normally forested road I knew of my youth was scorched and destroyed for mile after mile. When I turned off the two lane road onto the dirt road we immediately encountered a couple of trucks blocking the road, preventing anyone from getting through. They were logging the burn, and it was dangerous to go any further, so we never made it to the lake. As I drove down the mountain I thought it would be appropriate to head across the valley to another hike Isaiah and I did up at Babyfoot Lake. Babyfoot Lake burned back in 2002 as part of the Biscuit Fire, and while the mountain is scarred, it is coming back to life. There is a huge amount of renewal occurring, but like Bolan Lake it is a far cry from what it used to be. It was too overwhelming for me to see the condition Bolan Lake was in, and the new firs, pines, and flowers covering the landscape at Babyfoot lake was exactly the healing I was needed. My heart just can’t fully process what happened up at Bolan Lake, and I think that will have to wait until next year, and evolve over my lifetime, but never actually getting back to what I knew as a child. Like the weather on Kerby Peak, I can’t help but feel like the Slater fire of 2020 reflects my overall journey with Isaiah and Audrey, and the flowers we saw along the hike to Babyfoot lake provided some of the color we needed for this moment in time. There were a number of Irises, and other flowers up there, but the Indian paintbrush I feel like provides the color palette we need for the healing required in this...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/06/07/what-are-we-doing-to-our-kids/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Making It to the Top</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/06/06/making-it-to-the-top/"/>
    <updated>2022-06-06T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I put the most brutal and meaningful hike to celebrate Isaiah first up in the week. Isaiah and I did Kerby Peak back in 2016 and it nearly broke us. Kerby Peak was one of the few spots where Isaiah became lucid and would talk to me, which was a common pattern I’d see in only the most remote and hardcore of natural locations. The further away we got from cities, the more Isaiah opened up, pulled down his hoodie and engaged in conversation. I wanted Audrey to experience the beauty and hardness of this hike, and see what Isaiah saw as we ascended Kerby Peak, hiking a total of seven miles, but the hike up went from about 2500K elegant to 5500K—making a very punishing hike to the summit. The Kerby Peak Trail is located in Southern Oregon outside a small town called Selma. The trail starts out pretty simple from the parking area, but then pretty quickly begins to climb out of the Fir and Madrone forest into the older growth Douglas Fir stand. This type of forest is my favorite type of forest, possessing some of the most brilliant colors of green I have ever on this earth. We slowly zigged and zagged the switchbacks through some of the grandest moss covered trees I have seen in my life. I kept making dumb jokes about each switchback being the last switchback, as we made our way through the lush forest. It had been raining for a couple of days and the forest was very damp and cold, but the climbing elevation kept me warm as I chugged my way up the trail. Eventually we begin to break out of the forest into a more rockier elevation, which at first glance looks like it could be the summit, but pretty quickly you realize this is far from the top. We kept working our way through the slowly thinning landscape. I needed to make frequent stops to catch my breath and cool myself down, and Audrey and Poppy were very patient with my slow pace. After a quick stop for lunch right before the summit, we finally rounded the rocky summit and made our way to the top of Kerby Peak. The weather didn’t fully cooperate, but it didn’t diminish the emotion of the locating the rock where Isiah was standing back in 2016 I was able to get a video, but as you can see, we weren’t able to stay up there very long. I have to say the experience isn’t what I expected, but it felt like exactly what we needed to keep processing what has happened over the last couple of years. There was a lot of emotion and wind up top of Kerby Peak, providing a much needed cathartic relief from everything we’ve been through. Poppy led the way down off the stormy and dark summit, taking us down through the rocks, along the trees that are getting thicker and taller with each step we...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/06/06/making-it-to-the-top/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Having the Strength to Power on Through</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/05/27/having-the-strength-to-power-on-through/"/>
    <updated>2022-05-27T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I’ve been working hard lately. It is an understatement to say that I have a lot on my plate. My team has grown to 25, and I have a number of big projects front and center right now. While I have many different projects to think about big and small, there is one particular project that happens every year around this time that has intense deadlines and deliverables that are out of my control, and I am the only person with enough of a handle on the big picture to tackle. I need to be on my game, and it isn’t a time for anything to go wrong, but on the Friday before the Memorial holiday weekend it was clear that everything would go wrong, and I would just have to fight my forward and resist letting everything fall apart. We had entered the portion of the year between when Isaiah died in May of 2020 and is birthday in June, so shit was heavy and emotionally thin. I had spent the morning of the Friday before Memorial Day not eating so that I could have my liver scanned, had woke up generally grumpy about a number of work related, and was still struggling to process what had happened in Uvalde Texas. I was tackling my regular workday, while also preparing for working 12+ hour days over the 3-day holiday weekend so I could fulfill this annual project before it’s deadline which happened to magically shift right into time I scheduled off to process Isaiah passing, and I felt a strong snap. That mental break that sounds like the sizzle of a desert highway in the midday sun. I’ve seen it many times before, but I couldn’t let this episode own me. I had to find a way to get through the next week so that I could not just finish this project, but be there for my wife during her time of need. I was laying on the couch, crippled with anxiety and sinking into the pits of a depression. All too familiar territory, and I knew that I couldn’t let things slide any further, and I had to find a way to not just operate Kin in safe mode, but I needed to find some fuel to get him through. I’ve long perfective my approach to using my anxiety for fuel to get me through work times, which ultimately ends pulling me out of the ditches of depression. However, I found that I am also am getting much better at separating out the layers of what the fuck is wrong with me, identify any usable fuel, while also setting aside the things I can’t do anything about, and light the fire under my ass regarding the things I can do something about—resulting in the following layers: Kin is a Loser - This is a well known fact that I honestly get fucking sick of hearing, so anything in this category goes directly into the fuel category. Done More...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/05/27/having-the-strength-to-power-on-through/</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Stories From Our Youth That We Still Believe</title>
    <link href="http://kinlane.com/2022/05/15/stories-from-our-youth-that-we-still-believe/"/>
    <updated>2022-05-15T08:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[I am fascinated in recent years by the stories I absorbed in my youthful and more formative years. I feel like my 20s were spent figuring out who I was, and my 30s were spent figuring out the world, and I guess here in my 40s I thought it would all be a cake walk, but now I feel like my 40s were about unwinding all the shit I was programmed with before I turned 20. For me, it isn’t just the realization that a significant number of the stories I was exposed with growing up were bullshit, it was also that so much of it is woven in with white male supremacy, and more concerning, what other stories are out there that influence how I see myself and the world. Learning about the stories I was programmed with while still so young and moldable is fascinating, but it is the quest to find other more deep seated beliefs that I was programmed with in my early is what keeps me up at night. It is easy to explore the surface of this with laughable ones like waiting 30 minutes before I go swimming after eating, or being worried I’d go blind for masturbating, but it is more concerning to think about what else shapes how I see the world that I am completely unaware of. I’d say this is the most disturbing realization I’ve had in my 40s, that so much of my reality is shaped by stories I heard growing up in a predominantly white reality, programmed by movies, television, and the stories I heard from my elders around the dinner table. The more I learn, the more concerned I get about these realities. There are two existing “effect” theories I learned about in recent years that provide me with a kind of Venn diagram to think about the effect of storytelling on me in my youth, giving me possible strategies for thinking my way through this: Dunning-Kruger Effect - Dunning-Kruger effect, in psychology, a cognitive bias whereby people with limited knowledge or competence in a given intellectual or social domain greatly overestimate their own knowledge or competence in that domain relative to objective criteria or to the performance of their peers or of people in general. Murray Gelman Amnesia Effect - The Gell-Mann Amnesia effect is when experts forget how badly their own subject is treated in media and believe that subjects they don’t know much about are treated more competently by the same media. What would we call the effect of not just realizing stories that shaped you from your youth aren’t false, but that there are so many of these out there than you haven’t discovered yet, and worse, that they might be racist in their roots, or have some other problematic aspects. This is the primary effect I am looking to understand. Not just how I believed in “old wives tales”, but how the stories I believe are so woven into white male supremacy—including...]]></content>
    <id>http://kinlane.com/2022/05/15/stories-from-our-youth-that-we-still-believe/</id>
  </entry>
</feed>
