<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-04-20T20:51:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kin Lane</title><subtitle>The ramblings, thoughts, and channeling of Kin Lane.</subtitle><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><entry><title type="html">Quantitative and Qualitative as a Zero Sum Game</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/04/04/quantitative-and-qualitative-as-a-zero-sum-game/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quantitative and Qualitative as a Zero Sum Game" /><published>2024-04-04T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-04T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/04/04/quantitative-and-qualitative-as-a-zero-sum-game</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/04/04/quantitative-and-qualitative-as-a-zero-sum-game/">&lt;p&gt;Technology likes to focus on scale, prioritizing quantitative approaches to defining and shaping what digital success looks like. To achieve scale you need to effectively reduce an experience or series of experiences to scalable transactions. This is a game that often begins with an equal balance of qualitative and quantitative approaches to defining, measuring, and ultimately shaping digital success, but over time it becomes easier to focus so heavily on scale and quantitative measurements that push you lose sight of what quality means, reducing whatever hustle you have going on to zero sum game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that the venture capital hustle is all about scale. Scale at all costs. My quaint view of delivering useful technology that human beings need is easily chewed up and spat out in this hustle. I am good at the venture fueled startup hustle within a certain range from Series A to D, and once you succeed things become about things I am not good at, or feel comfortable  doing. This is where the company selling a product becomes the product, which I fully understand to investors. This was always true, but when you are on the ground floor of a startup, you don’t see it this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been along for the ride of several startups now. I have a clearer picture now. I got on these roller coasters, or aided in their operation as a carny, fully knowing that the roller coaster wasn’t the product, and that even the roller coaster experience wasn’t the product—that it was the carnival. It doesn’t change who I am. I can’t help but focus on the product or service. The direct tangible things that humans need or do not need. I get it now that this belief gets used and abused by startup founders and investors—they need people like me to operate the ride. They need people like me to bring the qualitative experience to the carnival, and get people riding the roller coaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get that there is a lot of money to be made in a carnival. In operating, speculating, and hustling folks as your carnival rolls through town. I just struggle with existing and operating at that level. I thrive the most at the direct human to technology engagement level, not the detached, derivative, scaled up version. I am running the roller coaster, teacup ride, and shooting balloon game level. However once you reach series D and you start rigging the shooting balloon game and making the prizes cheaper and shittier, this is where I get frustrated. Series D is where you cease to offer, measure, and believe in the qualitative value your users need, and you focus solely on the quantity of tickets sold to the carnival. The individual rides and acts do not matter anymore—-it is just about tickets sold at the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning it is all about the clowns, rides, acts, and making it as much fun to be at the carnival as possible. You want to get people showing up and telling their friends about the experience. You want to get people thinking about being at the carnival throughout their day, and into the night. However, in the end all of the qualitative aspects of your ride or act become second to just getting people in the door, or worse, keeping them from leaving, and forcing them to join the circus, even if they do not enjoy it. I don’t think startup founders and investors truly get the zero sum game they’ve set into motion. I just don’t find meaning or purpose in getting wealth this way. I’d prefer either riding along with the carnival until Series D time, or simply operate a regular business. The only problem is investors will run you out of town in any game, with their Series A, B, C acts, where they price you out, and throw all in on the quality of the experience to get your customers in their door, only to fuck them over down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will always lose in this game. I focus on the qualitative aspects of the intersection of humans and technology, in a sea of quantitative beliefs and focus. Quantitative and qualitative can co-exist, just not in the current venture fueled version of the Internet we’ve built. The game in the end is always about squeezing any value and quality from the game and sharing the spoils amongst the few who thrive in this environment. I do not. I enjoy the thrill of the ground. I like to see the thrill in the eyes of people who enjoy the ride or find enjoyment in my theatrical act. This makes me a useful tool in the toolbox of those who can’t do, but fancy themselves carnival producers. I just have to remember this as I move through this world. It isn’t that I haven’t known this before, I just get caught up in the carnival and forget about the real world out there as I immerse myself in what matters to me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Qualitative" /><category term="Quantitative" /><category term="Business" /><category term="Investment" /><summary type="html">Technology likes to focus on scale, prioritizing quantitative approaches to defining and shaping what digital success looks like. To achieve scale you need to effectively reduce an experience or series of experiences to scalable transactions. This is a game that often begins with an equal balance of qualitative and quantitative approaches to defining, measuring, and ultimately shaping digital success, but over time it becomes easier to focus so heavily on scale and quantitative measurements that push you lose sight of what quality means, reducing whatever hustle you have going on to zero sum game.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/citizenship-cloud-red.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/citizenship-cloud-red.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">That Emotion That Prevents You From Reading Books</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/04/01/that-emotion-that-prevents-you-from-reading-books/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="That Emotion That Prevents You From Reading Books" /><published>2024-04-01T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-01T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/04/01/that-emotion-that-prevents-you-from-reading-books</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/04/01/that-emotion-that-prevents-you-from-reading-books/">&lt;p&gt;My eyes get tired. I don’t have the time. It is hard to focus. And the many other excuses I have uttered throughout my adult life when it comes to why I can’t read even 1 book, let alone possess a steady diet of book reading, all seems intentionally crafted to me these days. I’ve managed to carve out two (going on my third) dedicated session where I carve out dedicated time and make book reading a priority. I’d say that in normal times I am to the point where I am always moving forward (albeit slow) with a book at any given time. Something I haven’t done for about 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This session I find myself in right now I am thoughtfully unpacking that emotion I have when I stop ready, or make an excuse why I open the laptop or turn on the TV instead of cracking open a good book. It is a well-known, yet uncomfortable feeling that provides me with a rich substrate for growing a diverse range of insecurities. The emotion has become an essential driver of who I am, or more aptly, who I am not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can read. I can read well. I actually enjoy reading. I know reading is better for me than television or the Internet. Yet, I still accept this lesser version of myself. I crave book reading, but the world around me seems to have all roads leading towards me not reading. The undercurrents always pull me towards reading something online or watching something on television. It all seems to be designed that way. I have to consciously battle these forces daily and make the decision to read a book instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing that comes close to reading books for me is reading my news and blog feeds online. Social media, videos, and other sources just don’t do it for me. The cycles are too short. The feedback loops are too volatile. Reading a book is the only time my brain slows down to healthy levels, and living too long with a nutrient starved online information diet leaves you more susceptible to the forces working to convince you not to read. It feels like the frame rate of reading books or blog posts is of an acceptable speed, where anything faster has the potential to become too much like being on a hamster wheel and do not have deep enough roots or nutrients to sustain me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything in life seems to pull you away from reading. Work, the Web. It all seems to demand your attention. I have long recovered from the urge to watch television being a stronger pull than reading a book, but I have just begun the same journey when it comes to the Internet. Largely because my career is wrapped up in being online, but I suspect there is more. I am still unpacking all of this, and as with the television I know that I will find my way out. I want to spend the bulk of my time in this second half of my life in a book, and wandering bookstores, libraries, galleries, and museums around New York City. I can feel the way the Internet depletes my shoulder and the way that a book replenishes my soul, I just need to get my actions, and the way I live my life in alignment with what I know is right.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Reading" /><category term="Books" /><summary type="html">My eyes get tired. I don’t have the time. It is hard to focus. And the many other excuses I have uttered throughout my adult life when it comes to why I can’t read even 1 book, let alone possess a steady diet of book reading, all seems intentionally crafted to me these days. I’ve managed to carve out two (going on my third) dedicated session where I carve out dedicated time and make book reading a priority. I’d say that in normal times I am to the point where I am always moving forward (albeit slow) with a book at any given time. Something I haven’t done for about 20 years.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/america-immigration_dumping-ground-old-bearded-man-thinking.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/america-immigration_dumping-ground-old-bearded-man-thinking.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What Will We Do After This AI Wave</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/04/01/what-will-we-do-after-this-ai-wave/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Will We Do After This AI Wave" /><published>2024-04-01T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-01T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/04/01/what-will-we-do-after-this-ai-wave</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/04/01/what-will-we-do-after-this-ai-wave/">&lt;p&gt;I like my blog because it provides me with dated looks into how I feel in any particular moment–something I need to feel sane in a pretty insane digital landscape that likes to just memory hole things so it can perpetually celebrate what is next. With this in mind I wanted to write a blog post about the current AI wave we are in so that I can read it after we have survived it—-which we will. It is so fascinating how people so badly want to believe in AI, and the oxygen gets sucked out of the room for anyone with thoughts on other subjects, or push back on AI in any way. I just want a journal entry for this moment, not so I can point back and say “I Told You So!”. It is just so I can stay sane in all this insanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what will we do after this AI wave? The same as after previous ones. Keep doing the hard work to tame the tech beast we’ve unleashed. When I see what AI is capable of, I see useful incremental shifts in how we communicate, build, and manage technology in our business and professional lives. When I see what promises are made around what AI is capable of, I see a lot of hustling, money moving around, disrupting labor, and many people who enjoy being “prompt engineers” while being fed what the narrative is. I am sure we will obtain some new and interesting incremental AI tools and services this round, but I see things already beginning to settle into what I’ve seen with previous waves, and people will begin looking for what is next without much retrospection on what just was. It is how things work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this round I will do more work to solidify my business and financial base so that I can more easily weather future hype cycles around AI. One thing I’ve learned about AI (and other technological) believers, is the line up at the trough to believe again. I see a lot of parallels between religion, drug addiction, and digital technology. Believers are going to believe, often despite overwhelming real-world evidence. In this AI cycle the big tech companies like Microsoft and Nvidia, who are selling the AI picks and shovels will do well. There will be another layer of companies who are selling AI experiences directly who will do well, but not because of what they are selling to AI consumers, but what they are selling to investors and the market. AI is just one of the more visible storytelling derivatives all wound up and bundled with previous derivatives to deliver this generated digital financial products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly I find a little more oxygen and peace up here above the hype. It is lonely. But I am not caught up in the insanity of building a specific tool or service, or trying to make investors and the market believe my business is actually real when it isn’t. I am just doing the hard work of mapping and governing a single enterprise for my day job, and also of the wider public API ecosystem as my side hobby. All of which will contribute to the evolution of AI while not being caught up in this single wave of AI. AI is just API entropy from my perspective. It is just the next application of APis. Your AI will only be as good as your APIs. The loudest AI believers will be just like the loudest Web 3.0 believers, they’ll just switch unapologetically to what is next. Many younger folks will learn and take the lessons with them to their next jobs, slowly becoming more pragmatic with each wave. Most will just ride each wave like it is all that matters today, and joyfully ride each wave with the same delusional buy-in—-it is how digital technology works.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="AI" /><category term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category term="Trends" /><summary type="html">I like my blog because it provides me with dated looks into how I feel in any particular moment–something I need to feel sane in a pretty insane digital landscape that likes to just memory hole things so it can perpetually celebrate what is next. With this in mind I wanted to write a blog post about the current AI wave we are in so that I can read it after we have survived it—-which we will. It is so fascinating how people so badly want to believe in AI, and the oxygen gets sucked out of the room for anyone with thoughts on other subjects, or push back on AI in any way. I just want a journal entry for this moment, not so I can point back and say “I Told You So!”. It is just so I can stay sane in all this insanity.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://algorithmic.rotoscope.work/images/collections/the-persistence-of-memory/highway-truck-silo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://algorithmic.rotoscope.work/images/collections/the-persistence-of-memory/highway-truck-silo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Domains</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/24/my-domains/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Domains" /><published>2024-03-24T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-03-24T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/24/my-domains</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/24/my-domains/">&lt;p&gt;I am a big believer in owning your own domain. I do not care what you put there, but you should have at least on online domain which you control. Ideally you have an email address there too, and keep your site(s) somewhat active. I have winters on each domain where I do not update anything, but I always come back to them, otherwise I let a domain go. Today is one of those days where I step back and assess the state of my personal and professional domain(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-personal-side&quot;&gt;My Personal Side&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have historically been very public with the personal side of my storytelling, and this is something I think I will continue as long as I can. I find it rewarding to be in control of the narrative for my digital self this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kin-lane-kinlanecom&quot;&gt;Kin Lane (kinlane.com)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is me. This is my doorway. Sometimes it is very personal. Sometimes it is political. Sometimes more technical. Other times it is just my personal journal.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://kinlane.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/kin-lane.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alternate-kin-lane-alternatekinlanecom&quot;&gt;Alternate Kin Lane (alternate.kinlane.com)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where I write about the things I see that aren’t real. The line can be blurred sometimes with my professional world, but everything I write here lives in alternate realm.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://alternate.kinlane.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/alternate-kin-lane.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alorotoscope-algorithmicrotoscopework&quot;&gt;Alorotoscope (algorithmic.rotoscope.work)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the image factory for all of my domain, where I produce images evolved from photos I took using AI models I’ve developed to show how technology obfuscates and distorts reality.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://algorithmic.rotoscope.work&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/algorotoscope.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-digital-self-thedigitalselforg&quot;&gt;The Digital Self (thedigitalself.org)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my religion. It is just what I tell myself daily to find balance in this digital world. I believe strongly that taking control over our digital domain is how we’ll save our physical self.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://thedigitalself.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/the-digital-self.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;drone-recovery-dronerecoveryorg&quot;&gt;Drone Recovery (dronerecovery.org)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a site about Isaiah and the summer we went out to wrestle with his addiction. Ultimately I wasn’t successful in recovering this drone, but I revisit this site often.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://dronerecovery.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/drone-recovery.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-professional-side&quot;&gt;My Professional Side&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where I do my professional work focused almost exclusively on APIs. Because of my approach to storytelling it can be difficult to understand where the line between my personal and professional storytelling is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;api-evangelist-apievangelistcom&quot;&gt;API Evangelist (apievangelist.com)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where I have been working to make sense of the technology, business, policies, and people of APIs since 2010, sharing stories about what I am seeing at this dimension of our digital transformation. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://apievangelist.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/api-evangelist.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apisio-apisio&quot;&gt;APIs.io (apis.io)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search engine I am developing with my partner in crime Steve Willmott, working to make APIs more discoverable using our open source API discovery format called APIs.json.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://apis.io&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/apis-io.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apisjson-apisjsonorg&quot;&gt;APIs.json (apisjson.org)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open source API discovery format that I developed with Steve Willmott back in 2014, and we have been working on ever since, and have found renewed energy for here in 2024. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://apisjson.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/apis-json.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;api-commons-apicommonsorg&quot;&gt;API Commons (apicommons.org)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open source API lifecycle format that I developed with Steve Willmott back in 2014, as part of my work on the Oracle vs. Google copyright case, which we are giving some more attention as a common place to store machine-readable APIs.json properties.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://apicommons.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/api-commons.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;api-specification-toolbox-apispecificationtoolboxcom&quot;&gt;API Specification Toolbox (apispecificationtoolbox.com)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an open source directory of API specifications I setup while planning and building Postman Open Technologies, and is something I’d like to give more attention each year to help me keep a handle on all of the specifications and tooling.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://apispecificationtoolbox.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/api-specification-tollbox.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;contrafabulists-contrafabulistscom&quot;&gt;Contrafabulists (contrafabulists.com)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the parent level business my wife and I own together to house all of our domains under a single roof. We operated Hack Education and API Evangelist under this for a decade, and I will likely maintain on into the future–just in case.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://contrafabulists.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/my-domains/contrafabulists.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-importance-of-my-domain&quot;&gt;The Importance of My Domain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say that my universe of personal and professional domains is one of the most important assets I own. I have had Kin Lane since 2007, API Evangelist since 2010, and the other domains map to a variety of life experiences. With the demise of Twitter, and the shake-up of the social networking landscape, my domains are even more critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My domains reflect me. They are how I make a living. They are how I am creative. I own and operate all of the domains on my own. I use CloudFlare, AWS, and GitHub to manage all of my sites and APIs. When my domains are active, I feel active. It is important to me to maintain control over my digital self. Without sufficient control over my digital self tends to lead to insufficient control over my physical self. I am hyper aware of how intertwined they are in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been spending more time across my domains lately. I am finding more energy for Kin Lane, Alternate Kin Lane, and Algorotoscope. I still find regular energy for API stories. I’ve had a huge burst of energy for APIs.json and APIs.io, and will be rebooting API Commons alongside. I want to do this with the API Specification Toolbox, and even gather some updated thoughts around being a Contrafabulist. I’d say that all of my domains make me happy for the first time. I don’t feel like I have too many, and I don’t feel like I am a slave to any of them. They are where I freely express myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this post was to just gather all of my domains in one spot, and step back and thinking about them all in concert. I really think they reflect my interests and personality. And they are mine. I am not worried about page views in my domain. Well I guess, APIs.io I may begin to care again, but the rest, meh. They are there first and foremost for me. If people stumble across any of it–awesome! My domain exist just for me to take control over my digital self, but also to help me manage my physical self. I am pleased. My domain makes me happy and I can spend about 90% of my online time here, and that is just fine.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Domains" /><category term="Stories" /><category term="Images" /><category term="Fiction" /><category term="Non-Fiction" /><summary type="html">I am a big believer in owning your own domain. I do not care what you put there, but you should have at least on online domain which you control. Ideally you have an email address there too, and keep your site(s) somewhat active. I have winters on each domain where I do not update anything, but I always come back to them, otherwise I let a domain go. Today is one of those days where I step back and assess the state of my personal and professional domain(s).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/copper-circuit-kin-chesapeake.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/copper-circuit-kin-chesapeake.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Going Directly to the Source to Buy Books</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/25/going-directly-to-the-source-to-buy-books/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Going Directly to the Source to Buy Books" /><published>2024-02-25T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-25T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/02/25/going-directly-to-the-source-to-buy-books</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/25/going-directly-to-the-source-to-buy-books/">&lt;p&gt;I am looking for all of the ways I can push back on the often suffocating world around me. I am looking for daily incremental  ways in which I can push back, or at least not entirely be complicit in all the capitalism introduced illnesses that plagues us. One of the cornerstones ways in which I push back is that I read books, but I also work really hard to make sure I buy a book from the author and publisher, rather than Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this idea for a post on my blog when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.akpress.org/catalog/product/view/id/3332/s/loaded/&quot;&gt;I purchased Loaded, A Disarming History of the Second Amendment, by Roxanne Dunbar-Ortiz&lt;/a&gt;, a couple years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.akpress.org/catalog/product/view/id/3332/s/loaded/&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While purchasing her book, I made sure I went directly to her publisher to make sure I supported them, and not a lion share going to Amazon-—it really wasn’t that much work for me to click on the 2nd or 3rd link on Google search, but something that mattered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, more recently, after learning about &lt;a href=&quot;https://uncpress.org/book/9781469677248/gun-country/&quot;&gt;Gun Country, Gun Capitalism, Culture, and Control in Cold War America, by Andrew C. McKevitt&lt;/a&gt;, I was reminded of making sure I purchased from the source because of the related 2nd Amendment topic of the books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.akpress.org/catalog/product/view/id/3332/s/loaded/&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading though, I’ve added the dimension that I am not just going directly to the publisher to support the smaller publishers and their authors, I am organizing these regular actions into a bucket of actions I take regularly to push back on capitalism. Gun Country reminded me that suicides, mass shootings, and other gun related atrocities are things that I have very little control over, but I can do more to push back on the capitalism that makes gun ownership a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these books are on &lt;a href=&quot;https://kinlane.com/deprogramming/&quot;&gt;my list of books I’ve used to deprogram me&lt;/a&gt;, and having links to the publishers page helps me, and my readers quickly support their work, while expanding their horizons reading these books. Purchasing books from the source is a small thing, but something that will add up over time for someone who reads regularly like me, and something if encouraged by each other, could grow into something that actually has a meaningful impact.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Guns" /><category term="Publishing" /><category term="Capitalism" /><category term="Books" /><summary type="html">I am looking for all of the ways I can push back on the often suffocating world around me. I am looking for daily incremental ways in which I can push back, or at least not entirely be complicit in all the capitalism introduced illnesses that plagues us. One of the cornerstones ways in which I push back is that I read books, but I also work really hard to make sure I buy a book from the author and publisher, rather than Amazon.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/american-dream-fundamental-old-books-rack.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/american-dream-fundamental-old-books-rack.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Book I Needed to Understand Our Gun Obsession</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/25/the-book-i-needed-to-understand-our-gun-obsession/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Book I Needed to Understand Our Gun Obsession" /><published>2024-02-25T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-25T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/02/25/the-book-i-needed-to-understand-our-gun-obsession</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/25/the-book-i-needed-to-understand-our-gun-obsession/">&lt;p&gt;I just finished &lt;a href=&quot;https://uncpress.org/book/9781469677248/gun-country/&quot;&gt;Gun Country, Gun Capitalism, Culture &amp;amp; Control in Cold War America, by Andrew C. McKevitt&lt;/a&gt;. It was exactly the book I needed to continue unpacking my youth — 1972 through 1995. I do not own guns anymore, but I did up until 2012 (and briefly again in 2019), and only just now coming to terms with the crazy mixed up feelings I have about them. I am very thankful for this book because it was the first academic book I have found that addressed World War II forward. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.akpress.org/catalog/product/view/id/3332/s/loaded/&quot;&gt;Loaded, by Roxanne Dunbar-Ortiz&lt;/a&gt;, was the only thing I have read recently that shifted my views of the landscape in any meaningful way, but Gun Country just gave me everything I need to keep unpacking my shit-—thanks Andrew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to read the book to grasp what is wrong with this country, but it is also a guide to understanding the toxic reality in which I grew up in, and what I am working so hard to unwind. I grew up in Southern Oregon in the 1970s, in the cities and counties the book references as the heart of the shift that occurred in the NRA and gun culture that led us to where we are today. I was a product of the Cold War fear, white flight, and anti-government programming that got us where we are today. I managed to get out just as Obama was taking office, and was successful in elevating my view of things to a more global perspective-—only occasionally looking back, while desperately looking for answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/john-wayne-the-searchers-castle-cannon-tree.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d say Obama shifted things for me, allowing me to begin studying my earlier programming. I gave away all my guns to my best friend Derek in 2012, and chose to live in Los Angeles, New York, DC, and travel the world. My work in Washington D.C., and the shift to Trumpism showed me there was no going back. In 2020, my best friend shot himself in the head with one of my guns, just as covid took hold of our world. In 2020, my last conversation with my partner’s son was a fight where I refused to give him his guns back, I never saw him again. He didn’t commit suicide, but he overdosed the same month Derek did–just as covid grabbed hold of us. I now live in a world where I remember my first 22 rifle, .270 Winchester hunting rifle, 9MM pistol, 12 gauge shotgun, .54 caliber black powder rifle, fully automatic rifle, SKS Chinese rifle, and the smell of cleaning and firing them while also confidently knowing I want nothing to do with having a gun ever again–no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book helps you see the control of it all. The culture. The consumerism. The racism. The nationalism. The fear. The fear. The fear. It helps you see that most of the rhetoric is born after WWII, and not a handed down tradition since the founding of this country. I mean the racism is, but the culture and consumer aspect is manufactured to just sell us a product that speaks to our identity. I spent summers doing 4H at the fairgrounds mentioned in the book. I can still count on all the family and friends I care deeply about who always have a gun on them, and who own 25 or 50+ guns and countless rounds of ammunition. I live in New York City as I read Gun Country and I am extremely grateful for the careful research and storytelling in the book. It came at a time when I needed this reinforcement. For me, there is a confidence in being well read and having an understanding of the root of this illness, in the same way I think that being ignorant and not understanding the world had given me un-shaking confidence that owning a gun was essential to living.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Guns" /><category term="Consumerism" /><category term="Capitalism" /><category term="Communism" /><category term="Cold War" /><summary type="html">I just finished Gun Country, Gun Capitalism, Culture &amp;amp; Control in Cold War America, by Andrew C. McKevitt. It was exactly the book I needed to continue unpacking my youth — 1972 through 1995. I do not own guns anymore, but I did up until 2012 (and briefly again in 2019), and only just now coming to terms with the crazy mixed up feelings I have about them. I am very thankful for this book because it was the first academic book I have found that addressed World War II forward. Loaded, by Roxanne Dunbar-Ortiz, was the only thing I have read recently that shifted my views of the landscape in any meaningful way, but Gun Country just gave me everything I need to keep unpacking my shit-—thanks Andrew!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/gun-country.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/gun-country.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wrestling with Toxic Masculinity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/23/wrestling-with-toxic-masculinity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wrestling with Toxic Masculinity" /><published>2024-02-23T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/02/23/wrestling-with-toxic-masculinity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/23/wrestling-with-toxic-masculinity/">&lt;p&gt;I went to see Moulin Rouge on Broadway with Boy George as Harold Zidler yesterday, and then came home and watched the movie Iron Claw. I am having flashbacks to the 1980s and much like the movie Iron Claw, I am wrestling with experiences and programming around masculinity and just how toxic and wild the ride has been. I remember passionately declaring I did not like Boy George, not because I didn’t like Boy George, but because my life would be made a living hell by those around me if I didn’t. I find it to be therapeutic to sort through these emotions, gather my memories and feelings, and write them down to potentially rewire much of the programming I received in the 1970s and 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t into wrestling and I didn’t have a domineering father. I had a series of boyfriends and stepfathers to contend with, and never knew my dad, so I think the masculine signals and programming I received were a mix of jumbled noise from television, movies, and the world around me. I remember when Culture Club rose to popularity, and despite the songs being catchy and ubiquitous, you knew as a young teenage man in a rural area that you could not signal any affection for the music or fashion, otherwise your life would be made miserable. I was straight, I couldn’t imagine what this would do to your reality if you actually were queer. It fucked me up so badly for a period of time I thought maybe I was actually gay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can say, looking confidently back from the age of 50, that the 1980s were a fucked up period of programming for young men. I am sure that every decade meets this definition, but damn the 1980s were brutal. I can see now how my fear of retribution by the kids around me manifested itself into a performance of hatred for Boy George. How confusing and reinforcing of self-hatred. I can see now how fear manifested itself into masculine confusion and toxicity in these moments, and resulted in WWE style performances in the hallways, lunchroom, and on the playground. I was skinny and weak, so never participated in physical performances, but it surely fed my love of knives, guns, and made my brain a rich environment for toxic masculine programming in the 1980s. I can’t tell if things would have been better or worse for me if I had grown up with more muscles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I absolutely loved Moulin Rouge. The music and spectacle was soul nourishing. I loved to be able to see Boy George, and experience them singing “Do You Really Want To Hurt Me”—even just the little bit they did. It is healing to be in New York City in 2024 experiencing Broadway musicals, despite the programming I received in 1984. I am confident in my sexuality at 50, and have wrestled with the majority of my masculinity issues. My wrestling was more about Boy George than it was about the Iron Claw, but the grip of toxic masculinity was the same I’d say. I purposefully write these stories on my blog knowing that male elders from my childhood occasionally accidentally read my blog, but I regularly shed tears thinking about the personal hell they live in because of the iron claw they are in the grip of. I don’t know how to help them see the sadness and misery they’ve signed themselves up for each day through regular reinforcement of their fears, anxieties, and insecurities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, the antidote I feel is theater. Not in all the classic ways in which homophobic people will poke and make fun of plays and musicals. It is just the dancing, music, and nourishing joy they bring to you. People being themselves while pretending to be others. People explore very difficult as well as joyful subjects through song and dance. It really does a lot to reverse the programming and bring down the walls we put up. I know that many people on Facebook snicker every time I post a photo of the playbill and theater, as if I am bragging or flaunting my privilege. No, I am sincerely sharing my love of the theater and signaling the healing that is occurring in my life. I am sorry that you still live in such a rigid, deficient, and hard-done-by reality, that my theater joy doesn’t translate. It really is the answer that troubles us, and should be prescribed to every high schooler in the country, and then maybe, just maybe, someday we can do away with toxic masculinity, and our children can grow up more confident, loved, and able to love others.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Masculinity" /><category term="Toxic Masculinity" /><category term="Men" /><category term="Boy George" /><category term="Moulin Rouge" /><summary type="html">I went to see Moulin Rouge on Broadway with Boy George as Harold Zidler yesterday, and then came home and watched the movie Iron Claw. I am having flashbacks to the 1980s and much like the movie Iron Claw, I am wrestling with experiences and programming around masculinity and just how toxic and wild the ride has been. I remember passionately declaring I did not like Boy George, not because I didn’t like Boy George, but because my life would be made a living hell by those around me if I didn’t. I find it to be therapeutic to sort through these emotions, gather my memories and feelings, and write them down to potentially rewire much of the programming I received in the 1970s and 1980s.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/copper-circuit-Kins-Album-Mom-2_0010.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/copper-circuit-Kins-Album-Mom-2_0010.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Using the Term Luddite To Understand Where People Stand</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/23/using-the-term-luddite-to-understand-where-people-stand/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using the Term Luddite To Understand Where People Stand" /><published>2024-02-23T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/02/23/using-the-term-luddite-to-understand-where-people-stand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/23/using-the-term-luddite-to-understand-where-people-stand/">&lt;p&gt;I always make a mental note of folks who wield the term “Luddite” to describe people who in their minds are anti-technology. Luddites weren’t anti-technology. Luddites were anti-exploitative labor practices that coincided with technological shifts that were happening across the industry landscape. If you are invoking Luddism when people push back on AI, saying they are anti-technology, you are joining forces with the team who are in favor of exploitative labor practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know there are hundreds of concepts like this that are used to size each of us up on a daily basis. I am just revealing one of the ways in which I am sizing folks up on social media and in casual conversation. Luddism being anti-technology is something I used to believe, but now after reading several books on Luddism and the movement, I understand not just how ignorant I was, but more importantly how this ignorance gets used to undermine our lives on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would consider myself a Luddite. I am not actively interested in smashing machines, but I support those who do. I am fascinated by modern equivalents of this like AI poisoning. I am not anti-technology. I am anti technology being used to exploit people. I am fascinated by how the term Luddite gets twisted and used to manipulate us. I am fascinated by how a history deprived audience can be made to believe in the opposite meaning of a word or phrase, co-opted and twisted by those who are threatened by the phrase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure that I say numerous things that are ignorant of history, and others use to judge my awareness and position in the world. It is my desire to minimize these things through reading. Not online. Books. I am confident that our only defense against this very slippery slope where words get used against us is to ground ourselves in reading as many books, across as many different subjects, by as many diverse authors as possible. Where you stand in the future will regularly be defined into two dimensions, those who read and those who do not.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Labor" /><category term="Capital" /><category term="Industry" /><category term="Luddite" /><summary type="html">I always make a mental note of folks who wield the term “Luddite” to describe people who in their minds are anti-technology. Luddites weren’t anti-technology. Luddites were anti-exploitative labor practices that coincided with technological shifts that were happening across the industry landscape. If you are invoking Luddism when people push back on AI, saying they are anti-technology, you are joining forces with the team who are in favor of exploitative labor practices.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/citizenship-loom.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/citizenship-loom.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Subways, Skyscrapers, and Servers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/22/subways-skyscrapers-servers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Subways, Skyscrapers, and Servers" /><published>2024-02-22T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-22T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/02/22/subways-skyscrapers-servers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/22/subways-skyscrapers-servers/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_J._Sprague&quot;&gt;Frank Sprague&lt;/a&gt; who contributed to the development of the electric motor, electric railways, and electric elevators, and his impact on cities. While he was perfecting the electric motors usage to power early subway systems, he was simultaneously applying the electric motor to elevator systems in tall buildings. Sprague literally laid the foundation for our modern cities reaching for the skies by allowing people to live in the suburbs and ride the subway to work each day, but also work in increasingly taller buildings because they could take the elevator to the top. I am left with images of millions of humans moving in, up, down, and out of cities each day, and how this is playing out when the digital landscape is introduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t help but see the servers behind the web as part of this same set of mechanisms propelling us through space, and now cyberspace. When I look at the API infrastructure that drives our world through this Sprague-ian lens, I can’t help but see little cybernetic belts and gears moving us through cyberspace, and increasingly in the physical space we occupy. I’ve long associated the subway and public transit with API infrastructure, but the more I read about and experience NYC transit, the more parallels I am seeing. I see Sprague motors taking me from my home to the street, and from the street where I live to the street where I work, and then up to my office. As I make this journey I use my API-powered apps to literally navigate and access transit, but also find myself observing people on their mobile devices as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I close my eyes and visualize our relationship with servers in the same way I do with subways and skyscrapers I see a fusion between industrial age factories with belts connecting machines and Neo unplugging himself and getting a look at the energy grid in the Matrix. I see the digital belts and gears that connect our mobile devices, automobiles, televisions, and daily experiences and propel us through the physical and digital worlds. Sometimes I feel cursed seeing this landscape, where other times I feel like I am blessed. I close my eyes and I see systems all around us. Like with subways and skyscrapers we are being moved around where we are needed or want to be, but in this new cybernetic realm we can move in many directions at once, changing our relationship with ourselves and the world around us in new ways we don’t fully understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is tough to quantify the role that electric motors have played in shaping the world around us, but how we move through it. When you see APIs as little virtual electric motors that move our digital bits, you begin to see overlaps between these complex systems we’ve set in motion around the world. APIs are just state machines, which act as little belts, gears, and motors that power our digital experience. They are what allow me to navigate my journey to work via Google Maps, and swipe my phone as I enter the subway at 59th Street and Columbus Circle. It is these little API belts, gears, and motors that literally help me make my way to work each day, while also having a conversation with my wife via SMS, reading the news via my NYTimes app, and catching up on what is going on across my social networks. This API system moves me in and out of midtown each day, and gets me back home, just as Sprague’s electric motors contributed to me moving on the subway and in elevators at home and work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn’t just the direct ways in which we propel ourselves through the world that interests me, it is the new ways in which we are propelled in different directions using web APIs. I spend my days walking around the city observing food delivery riders being told where to go via their API applications, and snow shovelers taking pictures of sidewalks when they are done clearing the snow. I am fascinated how APIs are moving us to and from work whether in the physical or digital world. I am fascinated by understanding which of these API belts, gears, and motors have standard “run of the mill” control over our day where we are in control, as well as where things get a little more exploitative and shift our relationship with the world in darker ways. Like the automobiles relationships with public transit and cities, I think we won’t live up to the full potential of API electric motors in benefitting the human race, and we’ll be forced to make our way through a sprawling maze of digital waste lands to make ends meet moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Subways" /><category term="Skyscrapers" /><category term="Servers" /><summary type="html">I’ve been reading about Frank Sprague who contributed to the development of the electric motor, electric railways, and electric elevators, and his impact on cities. While he was perfecting the electric motors usage to power early subway systems, he was simultaneously applying the electric motor to elevator systems in tall buildings. Sprague literally laid the foundation for our modern cities reaching for the skies by allowing people to live in the suburbs and ride the subway to work each day, but also work in increasingly taller buildings because they could take the elevator to the top. I am left with images of millions of humans moving in, up, down, and out of cities each day, and how this is playing out when the digital landscape is introduced.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/bf-skinner-ny-56th-foggy.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/bf-skinner-ny-56th-foggy.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I Am Not Mentally Ill, It is Just the World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/11/i-am-not-mentally-ill-it-is-just-the-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Am Not Mentally Ill, It is Just the World" /><published>2024-02-11T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-11T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/02/11/i-am-not-mentally-ill-it-is-just-the-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/02/11/i-am-not-mentally-ill-it-is-just-the-world/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent considerable time talking about my mental health publicly and privately. I’ve never been diagnosed with any particular condition, but as the person who is most familiar with what is going on in my head, I can tell you it is a far-out space roller coaster. You’ll have to read my blog, as well as my alternate blog if you want to understand more about how I see things. However, in this moment I am looking to zoom in on a statement from my wife Audrey that echoes in my head whenever I talk so openly about my mental state recently. She simply says, I think we focus too much on the phrase “mental illness” too much, when this is not about us, it is about the world around us. This is powerful. This is everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is right. We’ve all been trained to carry this load. That the illness is us. It is our heads. I am tired of carrying this burden. I am going to change the words I use to describe what is happening. I tried to describe what I’d traditionally call “mental illness” in my family, and my kids’ family the other night, and it was really hard to describe it as about how society works, nor more aptly, how it doesn’t work. I just don’t have the vocabulary. I am so used to blaming myself, my family, and the people in the communities I grew up in. It will take me some effort and practice to shift how I talk about this condition that seems to afflict so many of us, but I fear it has been misdiagnosed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was trying to practice this reversal in how I think about things on the NYC subway yesterday, where what I’d call “mental illness” was on full display. Rather than a sick young woman smacking my hadn’t off the railing near her, and defending her space from others with her feet, bags, and overall presence-—I saw a young woman who had been chewed up by a society that lacked the systems for properly supporting what she truly needed. Granted, I am not a doctor, and lack any training in identifying any of this, but I feel it helps me be more compassionate and empathetic to see this about society and not this young woman’s fault. Which I see as a dangerous side effect of rugged individualism-—so many of us get left to deal with things on their own. It is our fault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Viewing my world this way gives me an outward thrust when it comes to the gravity of living in the world, where before I felt like my world was always caving in. I struggle each day being Kin, but it is so worth it. I am thankful for everything I have when it comes to my physical and mental health, as well as my personality, interests, and beliefs. I am determined to stop shouldering myself with the blame for all the illnesses in the world, and the friction I encounter through my day. I feel like I work hard on my own shit, and while I still have more to deal with, I feel like at this point most of what still troubles me the most is the way in which the wider world works or doesn’t work. I am confident that learning to use different words to describe this reality is impacting me, my family, friends, and community, and that I can begin to navigate a new course when talking about my mental state.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Mental Illness" /><category term="Living" /><summary type="html">I’ve spent considerable time talking about my mental health publicly and privately. I’ve never been diagnosed with any particular condition, but as the person who is most familiar with what is going on in my head, I can tell you it is a far-out space roller coaster. You’ll have to read my blog, as well as my alternate blog if you want to understand more about how I see things. However, in this moment I am looking to zoom in on a statement from my wife Audrey that echoes in my head whenever I talk so openly about my mental state recently. She simply says, I think we focus too much on the phrase “mental illness” too much, when this is not about us, it is about the world around us. This is powerful. This is everything.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/copper-circuit-kin-boulder-last-before.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/copper-circuit-kin-boulder-last-before.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>