<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-12-09T10:54:43-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kin Lane</title><subtitle>The ramblings, thoughts, and channeling of Kin Lane.</subtitle><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><entry><title type="html">Radical Book Buzz with Library Freedom Project and Library Futures at the Francis Kite Club</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/09/radical-book-buzz-with-library-freedom-project-and-library-futures-at-the-francis-kite-club/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Book Buzz with Library Freedom Project and Library Futures at the Francis Kite Club" /><published>2024-12-09T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/09/radical-book-buzz-with-library-freedom-project-and-library-futures-at-the-francis-kite-club</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/09/radical-book-buzz-with-library-freedom-project-and-library-futures-at-the-francis-kite-club/">&lt;p&gt;Audrey and I headed down to the East Village last night for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/radical-book-buzz-with-library-freedom-project-and-library-futures-tickets-1073114086119&quot;&gt;Radical Book Buzz&lt;/a&gt; with Library Freedom Project and Library Futures at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.franciskiteclub.com/&quot;&gt;The Francis Kite Club&lt;/a&gt;. The intimate event showcased the good work of the Library Freedom Project and Library Futures organizations, but also showcased ten publishers who support radical authors across a variety of genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%&quot;&gt;

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haymarketbooks.org/books/2517-no-straight-road-takes-you-there&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haymarketbooks.org/books/2517-no-straight-road-takes-you-there&quot;&gt;No Straight Road Takes You There&lt;/a&gt; by Rebecca Solnit from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haymarketbooks.org/books/2517-no-straight-road-takes-you-there&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - In the spirit of her bestselling book Hope in the Dark, Rebecca Solnit explores how our actions can shape the future and the liberatory possibilities of embracing uncertainty.
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://sevenstories.com/books/4670-talking-about-abolition&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://sevenstories.com/books/4670-talking-about-abolition&quot;&gt;Talking About Abolition&lt;/a&gt; by Sonali Kolhatkar from &lt;a href=&quot;https://sevenstories.com/books/4670-talking-about-abolition&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Powerful interviews with scholars, organizers, and activists who are leading the movement to end policing and prison.
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.versobooks.com/products/3281-motherdom&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.versobooks.com/products/3281-motherdom&quot;&gt;Motherdom&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Bollen from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.versobooks.com/products/3281-motherdom&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Blaming, shaming and flimsy evidence, welcome to the ugly world of Good Mother myths.
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://pmpress.org/index.php?l=product_detail&amp;amp;p=1664&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://pmpress.org/index.php?l=product_detail&amp;amp;p=1664&quot;&gt;B. Traven, Portrait of a Famous Unknown&lt;/a&gt; by Golo from &lt;a href=&quot;https://pmpress.org/index.php?l=product_detail&amp;amp;p=1664&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - B. Traven, Portrait of a Famous Unknown is a graphic biography that tells the larger-than-life story of the German revolutionary, actor, and writer known as B. Traven (1882–1969).
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://orbooks.com/catalog/if-i-must-die/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://orbooks.com/catalog/if-i-must-die/&quot;&gt;If I Must Die&lt;/a&gt; by Refaat Alareer from &lt;a href=&quot;https://orbooks.com/catalog/if-i-must-die/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - This rich, elegiac compilation of work from the late Palestinian poet and professor, Refaat Alareer, brings together his marvelous poetry and deeply human writing about literature, teaching, politics, and family.
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/archipelagobooks/p/C-GEtlIOrJk/?img_index=1&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/archipelagobooks/p/C-GEtlIOrJk/?img_index=1&quot;&gt;Mafalda&lt;/a&gt; by Quino from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/archipelagobooks/p/C-GEtlIOrJk/?img_index=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - INTRODUCING MAFALDA, by the legendary Argentine comic book artist Quino! Frank Wynne will translate five volumes of MAFALDA comics for Elsewhere Editions, with our first volume set to publish next spring.
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feministpress.org/books-overflow/sympathy-for-wild-girls&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feministpress.org/books-overflow/sympathy-for-wild-girls&quot;&gt;Sympathy For Wild Girls&lt;/a&gt; by Demree McGhee from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feministpress.org/books-overflow/sympathy-for-wild-girls&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - A debut collection of surreal, skin-piercing stories about the boundless longing of queer Black women.
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europaeditions.com/book/9798889660897/gabriele&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europaeditions.com/book/9798889660897/gabriele&quot;&gt;Gabriële&lt;/a&gt; by Anne Berest &amp;amp; Claire Berest from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europaeditions.com/book/9798889660897/gabriele&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - 
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenewpress.com/books/king-of-north&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenewpress.com/books/king-of-north&quot;&gt;King of the North&lt;/a&gt; by Anne Berest &amp;amp; Claire Berest from &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenewpress.com/books/king-of-north&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - The Martin Luther King Jr. of popular memory vanquished Jim Crow in the South. But in this myth-shattering book, award-winning and New York Times bestselling historian Jeanne Theoharis argues that King’s time in Boston, New York, Los Angeles, and Chicago—outside Dixie—was at the heart of his campaign for racial justice.
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plutobooks.com/9780745349374/ghassan-kanafani/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plutobooks.com/9780745349374/ghassan-kanafani/&quot;&gt;Ghassan Kanafani, Selected Political Writings&lt;/a&gt; by Ghassan Kanafani from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plutobooks.com/9780745349374/ghassan-kanafani/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Ghassan Kanafani (1936 - 1972) is perhaps the greatest Palestinian novelist, whose books including Men in the Sun and Returning to Haifa documented the horrors of war and occupation. He was also a leading political thinker, strategist and revolutionary. Here, his writings on politics, history, national liberation and the media are collected in English for the first time
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be working through these titles, but also continuing to explore what is coming from these publishers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kinlane/kinlane/blob/main/_data/publishers.yml&quot;&gt;I published this list as YAML&lt;/a&gt; so that I can power future stories, but also feed my reminders to regularly tune into what these publishers offer and reduce my attention given to Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thankful for the work of these two organizations for making the event happen and bring together the publishers, but also everyone that made it out last night for such an important aspect of storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%&quot;&gt;

    

    
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td width=&quot;175&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.libraryfutures.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/book-event-nyc/library-futures.png&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; style=&quot;border: 3px solid #000;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.libraryfutures.net/&quot;&gt;Library Futures&lt;/a&gt; - We mobilize a community of experts to encourage the adoption of technologies that uplift libraries in the digital age, promoting new possibilities for preservation of and unfettered access to information. Library Futures is a project of The Engelberg Center on Innovation Law &amp;amp; Policy at NYU Law.
        &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    

&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked away with more of an awareness of how the translation of radical books between languages, but also how the republishing of books that have gone out of print impacts our storytelling. I was also reminded of how this fucked up timeline we find ourselves in is driven by Amazon, Overdrive, Elsevier, and Penguin Random House, HarperCollins, Macmillan, Simon and Shuster, and the other top book publishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I make my way through these books I will publish more here about what I am reading, and when I find any new books from these publishers I will share as well. It feels like these outlets are our lifeline to the storytelling that is going to save us, sustain us, and bring us together in these troubling times. I don’t know about you, but I am looking to spend my time in the next few years reading and trying to attend as many events like this as I can to help me stay in tune with what truly matters.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Publishing" /><category term="Authors" /><category term="Books" /><category term="Radical" /><category term="Libaries" /><summary type="html">Audrey and I headed down to the East Village last night for the Radical Book Buzz with Library Freedom Project and Library Futures at The Francis Kite Club. The intimate event showcased the good work of the Library Freedom Project and Library Futures organizations, but also showcased ten publishers who support radical authors across a variety of genres.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/book-event-nyc/radical-book-buzz.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/book-event-nyc/radical-book-buzz.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Artificial Intelligence Is The Last Stop For My Technology Career</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/20/artificial-intelligence-is-the-end-of-the-line-for-my-api-career/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Artificial Intelligence Is The Last Stop For My Technology Career" /><published>2024-11-20T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-20T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/20/artificial-intelligence-is-the-end-of-the-line-for-my-api-career</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/20/artificial-intelligence-is-the-end-of-the-line-for-my-api-career/">&lt;p&gt;I have been listening and thinking deeply about why the artificial intelligence conversation is leaving such a bad taste in my mouth. It is hard to form a thought, let alone vocalize oneself in today’s hostile and noisy environment about not just AI, but the wider Internet, but I figured I’d draw a few lines in the sand on the beach of my little island. I am very confident in the fact that, as many AI believers love to point out, that I will be left behind by the current AI revolution. More precisely, I will stay behind. Meaning, this is where I get off this particular technological train. It is partly my age, but primarily just a difference in the ideology around what the Internet technology is for, and what it isn’t for, particularly when it comes to serving humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the fundamental building blocks of why I am skeptical of AI, which I feel pretty strongly are serious areas of concern. And I am confounded why people I thought were logical, caring, and pragmatic human beings are so willing to overlook, kick the can down the road, and believe that AI will “just fix”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Labor&lt;/strong&gt; - AI Is so clearly being used as a way of shifting power in the labor discussion at this moment, and I am not just talking about perceived employee replacement—-I am talking about the blind desire of business leadership to use AI and automation to replace people even before understanding how it works and what the impacts are.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment&lt;/strong&gt; - AI uses so much energy and has renewed our appetite for coal and nuclear in a time where we were just beginning to make better choices for the future of our children, but the stupid tractor beam around AI does not at all seem to care about the negative impact of AI in the real world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attribution&lt;/strong&gt; - There is no respect, and there is even disdain or copyright, authorship, expertise, and any provenance regarding the data and connect being used to train LLMs, something that upends over a century of law that was put in place to protect the artists and creators who are having their works stolen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Box&lt;/strong&gt; - Everything is such a black box, and not because it has to, but because it is by design—-the darker and more complex the better the environment is for spinning stories about what is possible, when it is actually all knowable and visible, it is just better to tell the story that it is all a mysterious magical black box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two points confound me. I get that rich people have a labor wet dream they want fulfilled using AI, but the droves of workers who are lining up to the trough to sell the future of their work to a few powerful corporations blows my mind. Reading a few science fiction novels when you were a kid and a belief that you will someday be one of the rich people has immense powers of activating some serious blindness when it comes to seeing the human beings who are working within the machine, or are being ground up by it. The delusional belief that we don’t have to think about the environmental factors because AI will eventually solve it is a new and very powerful version of kicking the can down the road so our kid have to deal with things, is something that leaves me pretty angry with the AI believers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two anger my soul and make AI personally something that doesn’t interest me, but if I was to reduce things down to a pure economic or career based perspective, the last two are what draws the end of the line for my career. I got into this business because APIs like AWS, Google Maps, and Twilio were making systems that were historically off-limits or out of reach to the average developer more accessible. I believed in this wave of APIs because APIs were making things more accessible using low-cost HTTP technology, making things like compute, storage, maps, sms, and other valuable resources that historically only big companies had access to—-were now available to everyday developers. This, dare I say, democratization of digital resources and capabilities is what I believe is the power of Internet technology delivered via simple, low-cost, HTTP-powered APIs. AI is not this. It is the opposite of that.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/bf-skinner-train-hand-car.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px&quot; /&gt;
I am not in the business of developing tools for a few very rich people. Sorry. It doesn’t make me happy. Even with the promise that I will be one of those rich people. Meh. Blah. Sorry, this is not what I was put on this planet for. There is no way that you can argue that AI is a future for humanity at this point. Don’t get me wrong, I don’t doubt that AI will continue, but I am damn sure it won’t be in the business of improving the lives of human beings around me. Sorry. It won’t. Sure, you might be able to point to a handful of ways it will unlock some new knowledge, but at what cost to our collective ability to live and work, and even just breathe the air and drink the water. Sorry, this is where I get off the train. It doesn’t mean I will go away. I won’t. I actually don’t believe that AI will consume everything and change everything in this moment, and APIs will continue to be a needed skill well past when I leave this world. But I refuse to stay on the mainstream technology train if it is team AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The language that AI believers are using is the canary in the coal mine for me. They are aggressive and absolute. You MUST do this. You HAVE to do this. AI believers love using very apocalyptic and scary stories to get you to stay on the train. This reeks of authoritarianism to me. I have never been a compliant individual and will always roll my middle finger up in the face of people telling me I have to do something. So here it is. FUCK YOU! I don’t care. I will not be pandering to AI. Like other applications of APIs I will stay aware of what is happening, but I never went too deep on mobile or device applications, so I am happy to keep AI at an arm’s length. Sure, this will hurt my career. But I don’t care. I am not in this for my ego or bank account. I am in this because I am a human being fighting the good fight for all of my other human beings. I am here to keep the machine visible and understandable, and shining a light not the bias and exploitation that occurs in the gears of the machine. This is something that becomes impossible to do in an AI world (this is by design), so I’ll be drawing the line here, and I strong believe that AI as it is currently being sold is a dead end street. Maybe it is just the end of the line for me. So be it. It is a good place to get off this authoritarian clown train car.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Career" /><summary type="html">I have been listening and thinking deeply about why the artificial intelligence conversation is leaving such a bad taste in my mouth. It is hard to form a thought, let alone vocalize oneself in today’s hostile and noisy environment about not just AI, but the wider Internet, but I figured I’d draw a few lines in the sand on the beach of my little island. I am very confident in the fact that, as many AI believers love to point out, that I will be left behind by the current AI revolution. More precisely, I will stay behind. Meaning, this is where I get off this particular technological train. It is partly my age, but primarily just a difference in the ideology around what the Internet technology is for, and what it isn’t for, particularly when it comes to serving humanity.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/bf-skinner-train-engine.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/bf-skinner-train-engine.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Portrait of Francis Williams Helps Me See the Bias in the System</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/20/the-portrait-of-francis-williams-helps-me-see-the-bias-in-the-system/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Portrait of Francis Williams Helps Me See the Bias in the System" /><published>2024-11-20T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-20T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/20/the-portrait-of-francis-williams-helps-me-see-the-bias-in-the-system</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/20/the-portrait-of-francis-williams-helps-me-see-the-bias-in-the-system/">&lt;p&gt;I am obsessed with seeing and showcasing the bias in the Internet. My storytelling on &lt;a href=&quot;https://apievangelist.com&quot;&gt;API Evangelist&lt;/a&gt; is driven by this obsession and &lt;a href=&quot;https://algorithmic.rotoscope.work/&quot;&gt;the AI images I use across my storytelling&lt;/a&gt; is all about keeping this bias visible. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v46/n22/fara-dabhoiwala/a-man-of-parts-and-learning&quot;&gt;It is a long read, but this amazing story of the portrait of Francis Williams has helped better see the direct bias, but also the echoing programming of that bias within the systems and applications we are building with APIs&lt;/a&gt;. For me, APIs are just busy codifying what already exists in the real world, but making it harder to cut out once set in motion as part of the automation and AI applications we are setting loose at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will have to read the story for yourself—it is long, but well worth it. In short, a man is selling a painting of a black man from Jamaica in the 1700s, and the story behind the painting reveals just how far white people will go to discredit the intelligence and humanity of black people, but also how all of our own programmed biases work to prevent us from seeing the truth. This is just one man and one painting, but the story for me reveals the institutional mechanisms that exist millions of times each day throughout the physical and online world. And that we are codifying and automating the tools for white people to directly be this awful, but also equip everyone to do it unconsciously and far removed from any knowledge or consequence of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I see the institutional bias that exists all around us offline and online today, the more I can’t look back, and the more I see it. The direct bias is an easy target, and as we all are experiencing right now, it is still a dominant narrative, but I feel like it is the automated everyday bias like people applied to the portrait of Francis Williams along the way that is so very, very, very damaging. The guy who wanted to diminish any legacy Francis Williams might have had is awful, the way everyone sees the painting along the way is the deep dark shit that is baked into our everyday responses. This is the coding and programming that we are baking into the Internet, and enabling, automating, and abstracting away via our mobile devices and now artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am fascinated by seeing the bias in the system in new and mundane ways, but I am also fascinated by how blind I am to much of it, but once I see, it changes everything. I get why it is so terrifying for folks to experience, but I’m obsessed with continuing to pull back the curtain on this. It is liberating to see and experience. It is painful and terrifying, but liberating. It drives me nuts to be ignorant. The gravity of white supremacy frustrates me. I do not like not being able to see things, and my white male privilege is regularly blocking my view. Pulling back the layers, story by story, voice by voice, and in this case painting by painting, is helping me unwind the anxiety I have about the world. These things still exist out there, but actually seeing them and being honest with myself about them, and regularly creating visualizations and stories that help shine a light on what exists out there in the system is my contribution to keeping the conversation alive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Bias" /><category term="Racism" /><category term="Art" /><summary type="html">I am obsessed with seeing and showcasing the bias in the Internet. My storytelling on API Evangelist is driven by this obsession and the AI images I use across my storytelling is all about keeping this bias visible. It is a long read, but this amazing story of the portrait of Francis Williams has helped better see the direct bias, but also the echoing programming of that bias within the systems and applications we are building with APIs. For me, APIs are just busy codifying what already exists in the real world, but making it harder to cut out once set in motion as part of the automation and AI applications we are setting loose at the moment.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-cli/filters/francis-williams.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-cli/filters/francis-williams.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tech Regerts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/05/tech-regerts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tech Regerts" /><published>2024-11-05T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-05T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/05/tech-regerts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/05/tech-regerts/">&lt;p&gt;I don’t have too many regrets as I enter the second half of my life. I am pretty confident in who I am and that my journey was worthwhile. I am a good and hardworking person. However, when it comes to Internet technology I have a couple of serious regrets, or more appropriately regerts. To help me deal with these regerts I went and got a tattoo on my arm to help me repent, but also not lose sight of what matters in the future—here are my regerts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I let my kid spend so much time online as a youth and teen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Believed in that libertarian manifest horseshit from John Perry Barlow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Believed the startup founders when they said they wouldn’t sell out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Believed VCs when they said they were selling the same product as me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Believed that y’all wanted to understand the system and do the work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being complicit and playing a role in the rise and enablement of fascism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I’ve dropped the ball when it comes to Internet technology whispering 
bullshit into my ear. Getting a tattoo at age 52 was no minor shift for me. Not because of the pain, but because of the decisions I’ve made in my life. I have never gotten it because when I was younger I was a criminal that sold drugs. The first time I was arrested was at 18 years old on the corner of Haight Ashbury in San Francisco, and when they took me in they took pictures of the scars on my body and asked if I had any tattoos—I didn’t. This occurred three more times over the next couple of years, leaving me resolute that I would never get a tattoo—despite having an image of several tattoos that I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting photographed naked holding your privates in a wet and cold jail cell leaves an imprint on you. At 52, while still a criminal I worry less about getting photographed naked. I get why police do it now-—to humiliate and belittle you. I have a pretty big scar on my left leg from a chainsaw accident cutting firewood, which is what the photographer always focused on taking from several angles, because I didn’t have any tattoos. So, getting a tattoo is a big deal for me, and the artwork I’ve chosen has a lot of meaning for me at many different levels—-providing me with a piece of artwork I can use to guide me forward in my work with technology. I can’t understate the importance of this moment in technology right now. I know that many people are willfully ignorant of what is happening, but we’ve been working on the fascist Maggie’s farm for the last 25 years, and we are complicit in standing up some fucked up shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be rubbing my shoulder every time I talk to startup founders and VCs. I will be rubbing my shoulder with every post I publish to &lt;a href=&quot;https://apievangelist.com&quot;&gt;API Evangelist&lt;/a&gt;, and every &lt;a href=&quot;https://algorithmic.rotoscope.work/&quot;&gt;Algorotoscope&lt;/a&gt; image I produce and publish. I won’t be getting out of the tech game, and I will never be retiring. I will work on continuing to make the machine visible from the outside-in until the day I die. I am confident in my mission as the API Evangelist in balancing power between the producer and the consumer. I will just keep doing the work, reading, writing, and connecting with human beings in my community. There is no turning back and fixing the mistakes I have made, but I can definitely do the work to push back on what I’ve helped set in motion, throwing myself on the machine and resisting becoming an ignorant part of the system.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Regrets" /><category term="Tattoos" /><summary type="html">I don’t have too many regrets as I enter the second half of my life. I am pretty confident in who I am and that my journey was worthwhile. I am a good and hardworking person. However, when it comes to Internet technology I have a couple of serious regrets, or more appropriately regerts. To help me deal with these regerts I went and got a tattoo on my arm to help me repent, but also not lose sight of what matters in the future—here are my regerts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/tech-regerts.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/tech-regerts.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kamala Harris Will Win the Election</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/03/kamala-harris-will-win-the-election/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kamala Harris Will Win the Election" /><published>2024-11-03T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-03T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/03/kamala-harris-will-win-the-election</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/03/kamala-harris-will-win-the-election/">&lt;p&gt;I am going to call it now. Kamala Harris will win this presidential election. People are tired of Trump’s shit. While patriarchy is still strong, it has run its course and Trump is the final gasp of this destructive and toxic way of living in this world. We are ready for woman to lead, and specifically a woman of color. I don’t think a white woman could break through this, and I believe Kamala can. This is the moment, whether you think we are ready or not-—there is no better time than now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kamala will win. It doesn’t mean our problems will be solved. There is still so much work to do. Trump’s people will once again say the election was stolen. They weren’t running to win. They were running to bring it all down. Trump’s loyalists are in it for themselves, at all costs. They won’t just go away after Kamala wins. We will still have to continue doing the hard work to deal with the brain rot that exists in our country, but the majority of people will want better than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write this because I believe in the people in this country. I don’t want to leave or checkout. I want to heal. I want to have a conversation about how do we improve our world. I believe strongly that we men need to step back a bit into supporting roles. We’ve had a good run, and we keep fucking things up. I think we need a little matriarchal healing. The only way I can envision anyone looking at Trump and saying “that is what we need”, is to conjure up memories of the hurt, painful, and scared men I’ve known in the past–a lifestyle that isn’t sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am publishing this two days before the election because I believe. I am not worried about being wrong. I believe in us. We got this. Let’s choose to take care of each other. Let’s choose to be inclusive and caring. You can make all those old patriarchal comments you’ve been trained to over the years to say about women in leadership positions, or you can close your eyes and lead with your heart. Don’t be scared. The world can be a scary place, but we still have the capacity to make caring and confident decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hate will not win in this election…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: I WAS SO WRONG ABOUT YOU AMERICA!! ;-(&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Election" /><category term="Predictions" /><category term="Love" /><summary type="html">I am going to call it now. Kamala Harris will win this presidential election. People are tired of Trump’s shit. While patriarchy is still strong, it has run its course and Trump is the final gasp of this destructive and toxic way of living in this world. We are ready for woman to lead, and specifically a woman of color. I don’t think a white woman could break through this, and I believe Kamala can. This is the moment, whether you think we are ready or not-—there is no better time than now.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/uncle-sam-white-house-west-wing-view.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/uncle-sam-white-house-west-wing-view.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I Need To Write Stories and Publish Them Publicly</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/07/08/why-i-need-to-write-stories-and-publish-them-publicly/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I Need To Write Stories and Publish Them Publicly" /><published>2024-07-08T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/07/08/why-i-need-to-write-stories-and-publish-them-publicly</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/07/08/why-i-need-to-write-stories-and-publish-them-publicly/">&lt;p&gt;I have struggled with why I need to publish stories publicly on my blogs over the last year.  After stepping back from social media, killing Twitter, and limiting my work storytelling to LinkedIn, and personal to Facebook and Instagram I was left with the question once again—why do I publish my stories on my blogs? It is all so wrapped up in my performance as both Kin Lane and API Evangelist, as well as the social media movement of the last 15 years, I struggle with unwinding it all. However, I finally have settled on an acceptable narrative for why I need to publish API stories to API Evangelist, journal my life on Kin Lane, and play with images on Algorotoscope, and fictional stories on my Alternate Kin Lane—it is me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My online identity is a big part of who I am. Soon after finding some success with API Evangelist I noticed how strong the tractor beam was to move to other platforms like Posterous, Tumblr, Medium, as well as operate via social media instead of using open standards like Atom or RSS. I consciously invested in Kin Lane and API Evangelist to retain “value” and “meaning” in what I was doing, and it paid off. My writing on API Evangelist resulted in some very successful storytelling, and has landed me several lucrative gigs along the way. My two domains play an important role in who I am online, but also offline. It isn’t just vanity. It isn’t just a desire to be read. It is my space. It is my voice. It is where I have the most control online in this digital world. These domains are more me than Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn ever will be. kinlane.com, apievangelist.com, and my other suite of domains are my digital self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel successful within my domain. I don’t have an editor or filters within my domain. I get to publish whatever images, videos, and text I want. I get to organize my domains exactly as I want, even if that means they end up a little untidy. I like when my stories get read, and I like it if people notice my images, but it is more important that I just produce and publish these things. I also get to go back and decide what gets deleted and removed, and which domains go away. I like this. It gives me a sense of control over my digital self (in a time where I am unsure). I like telling stories. I like for people to be able to find me online. I enjoy people knowing what I am up to in a self-service way. You just type in my name and explore what I am up to. Page views and likes don’t matter, it is just about sharing my view of the world via my digital channels, and contributing in my own positive way to the online realm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still share stories from API Evangelist on LinkedIn, and occasionally a Kin Lane story on Facebook. I still share photos and images of my life on Facebook and Instagram, and now some on Threads. I don’t care about scale or things going viral. I don’t have to be consistent. I keep many stories in my notebook. My site is easily navigable using the headers within a site, and the footers across my sites. I like this. I am getting better at cleaning up and organizing these domains and giving regular attention to each area. I am thinking about expanding on my Alternate Kin Lane to further incentivize my fictional writing. I am even thinking about setting up a monthly newsletter to provide a digest of it all. I am not worried about readership or advertising, I am just looking to document my view of things, and give me some targets and constraints to work within when it comes to producing stories and images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write and publish stories to my domain to tell stories and project myself into the digital realm. I write and publish stories to influence my little corner of the web. I want to be the web I enjoy seeing and I think I will continue building sections of my sites that accomplish things once done by commercial or free platforms. I think I will keep publishing images to Instagram, but continue to invest in my own image API, as well as my own video API. I will build these things as API Commons, and augment my Jekyll powered website with super powers enabled by these APIs. I have a lot of content, data, images, timelines, videos, and other rich information I have curated over the years. When you combine this with what I am doing with APIs.io, there is a wealth of information available across my domains, that I used to produce stories, contribute to open source projects, and just make available for others to remix and reuse my ideas in their own work—as this is what the web is all about in my mind, not necessarily the version we end up living with today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Stories" /><category term="Publishing" /><category term="Social Media" /><category term="Domains" /><summary type="html">I have struggled with why I need to publish stories publicly on my blogs over the last year. After stepping back from social media, killing Twitter, and limiting my work storytelling to LinkedIn, and personal to Facebook and Instagram I was left with the question once again—why do I publish my stories on my blogs? It is all so wrapped up in my performance as both Kin Lane and API Evangelist, as well as the social media movement of the last 15 years, I struggle with unwinding it all. However, I finally have settled on an acceptable narrative for why I need to publish API stories to API Evangelist, journal my life on Kin Lane, and play with images on Algorotoscope, and fictional stories on my Alternate Kin Lane—it is me.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/yellow-journalism-japanese-man-sitting.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/yellow-journalism-japanese-man-sitting.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Frame Rate of Reading a Book, Listening to Music, and Walking Through the World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/07/07/the-frame-rate-of-reading-a-book-listening-to-music-and-walking-through-the-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Frame Rate of Reading a Book, Listening to Music, and Walking Through the World" /><published>2024-07-07T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-07-07T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/07/07/the-frame-rate-of-reading-a-book-listening-to-music-and-walking-through-the-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/07/07/the-frame-rate-of-reading-a-book-listening-to-music-and-walking-through-the-world/">&lt;p&gt;I feel like an overclocked processor most days. Back in the early days of the Internet I used to gather old computers from large companies and recycle them. As part of this work I’d find certain processors and graphics boards that had more value for modification than others. I remember there were a handful of processors that you could mess with their BIOS and set the rate they would work beyond the factory settings—-it was called overclocking. Most of the time you’d end up with a super fast computer, but sometimes you’d fry and burn out the processor, and you were left with nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not fully recovered from my latest burnout, but I am far enough into it that I can understand more about what put me there and what got me out of it. I learn a lot with each burnout. About myself and the world around me, but more specifically how I respond to the world around me. I get wound up easily. I let myself be overclocked beyond my factory settings. Others understand that people like me exist and take advantage of overclocking me to get more performance than you’d get out of normal folks. Capitalism is good at this. It is good at figuring out what your limits are and pushing you as far as it can, while extracting most of the value for itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hyper aware of how I get to the point where I burn out. I am kinetic. I easily get wound up. It is how I work—-I throw myself into it. It is what I do. I don’t know of any other way to approach what I do for a living. It is something that isn’t always in alignment with employers, but is also something that can be wonderful for generating value for a startup. Which is where I’ve seen the most exploitation of my day over the last 25 years, leading to my burning out. It isn’t just startups, the poster child for late stage capitalism. It is also Internet technology. It has a way of charging me up, something that is difficult to unwind. If I don’t deal with it on a daily or weekly basis, it manifests itself as burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thrive at a high digital frame rate. My brain will work through massive system architectures in hours or days, which might take others weeks or months. This is a frame rate that becomes dangerously high, leaving me stuck in a movie theater till room purgatory most evenings with the project spinning and filling, slapping the back of my mind with each revolution. After months or years of living in this state, I begin to lose my grip. The antidote to this is relying on a more analog frame rate on a daily and weekly basis, counterbalancing the velocity of working with APIs in the technology sector. Two examples of this analog frame rate are reading a book, walking around New York City, and listening to music on my record player. I find that the only way to maintain my digital self is to counterbalance with a regular digest of reading physical books, listening to physical records, and walking around a diverse physical world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The frame is just different while reading a book, listening to a record end to end, and walking through the streets of New York and Central Park. It feels like Internet technology is just designed to push my processing capabilities to their limits, both physically and mentally. It is hard for me to tell whether this is just technology or capitalism, or both blended into a human shaping and consuming machine. It feels like a digital version of Charlie Chaplin in Modern Times, but everyday living is the factory. Our personal and professional lives have become blurred, and we are conditioned and programmed every waking moment. Reading a book, listening to music, and walking through the real world feels like the only way I can push back on the digital nothing that is working to consume each day. For me, it is all about living as much of my life at a frame rate that fits the rhythm of my heart and soul—-not markets.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Albums" /><category term="Reading" /><category term="Walking" /><category term="Frame Rate" /><summary type="html">I feel like an overclocked processor most days. Back in the early days of the Internet I used to gather old computers from large companies and recycle them. As part of this work I’d find certain processors and graphics boards that had more value for modification than others. I remember there were a handful of processors that you could mess with their BIOS and set the rate they would work beyond the factory settings—-it was called overclocking. Most of the time you’d end up with a super fast computer, but sometimes you’d fry and burn out the processor, and you were left with nothing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/red-circuit-roman-marcus-looking-down.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/red-circuit-roman-marcus-looking-down.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sitting Down and Listening to an Album</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/07/06/sitting-down-and-listening-to-an-album/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sitting Down and Listening to an Album" /><published>2024-07-06T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-07-06T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/07/06/sitting-down-and-listening-to-an-album</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/07/06/sitting-down-and-listening-to-an-album/">&lt;p&gt;I sat down this morning and listened to two new albums I had purchased this week—-&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vampireweekend.com/&quot;&gt;Only God Was Above Us from Vampire Weekend&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.decemberists.com/&quot;&gt;As It Ever Was, So It Will Be Again by the Decemberists&lt;/a&gt;. I didn’t just put on these albums and then go do something else, like get online, or clean the house. I just sat there and looked out the window, sometimes closed my eyes, and listened to both albums end to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is really, really, really hard to sit and be present listening to music. You have to put the emergency break on. You have to make a commitment to stay engaged with the sounds coming out of the speakers, and be satisfied with the real world images in front of you. Sitting and listening to an album from end to end in the order intended by the artist is important. Sitting and listening is important. Sitting and just being in this world is important. It is something I don’t do enough of. Sure, I sit on my ass all day, but I am not present, I am online doing 10 different things at any given moment. I am doing too much, and sitting listening to music reminds me of what matters. 
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/decemberists-as-it-ever-was-so-it-will-be.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;
Both of the albums I listed were two record albums, meaning there were four albums each with two sides—-that was a total of eight sides, and two hours of music. Two hours of sitting and listening. The albums are great. I love both bands. Their storytelling ability, and the energy behind is moving. It is what I need. It is something I don’t do enough. I have listened to a lot of music since I got my record player last year, but I am usually still online or doing something else. I very rarely do I just sit there and listen. I think about the trade-off we have made in our lives that prevents this from happening on a regular basis. What stops us from sitting and listening to music? Why do we insist on multitasking? I feel like we’ve accepted a lot of distractions for not a lot of return, and are letting what truly matters slip away. Sure we keep a digital version of our music, but it isn’t the same.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/vampire-weekend-only-god-was-above-us.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot; /&gt;
Listening to an album the way the artists intended reminds me a lot of reading a book end to end. They are much richer and nourishing moments than any I spend online. These analog experiences are greater than their digital equivalent. There are just more nutrients present. They slow or stop the &lt;a href=&quot;https://alternate.kinlane.com/2024/03/17/revealing-the-cybernetic-gears-in-our-everyday-life/&quot;&gt;cybernetic gears&lt;/a&gt; from spinning around me in the moment. Even as much as I enjoy doing this, my regular day doesn’t allow for it, and I have to make trade-offs like listening to music while also doing work online in the evenings. Just like reading books, I will be pushing myself to listen to my music more. Not just having it playing in the background, but actually listening to it and feeling it. It makes me happy. It makes me feel better. It soothes me. It confounds me that this isn’t a priority in my evenings and on weekends. What a wonky world I have created.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Albums" /><category term="Artists" /><summary type="html">I sat down this morning and listened to two new albums I had purchased this week—-Only God Was Above Us from Vampire Weekend, and As It Ever Was, So It Will Be Again by the Decemberists. I didn’t just put on these albums and then go do something else, like get online, or clean the house. I just sat there and looked out the window, sometimes closed my eyes, and listened to both albums end to end.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/john-wayne-the-searchers-old-chair-hopsital.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/john-wayne-the-searchers-old-chair-hopsital.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning to Tie My Shoes Again</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/06/13/learning-to-tie-my-shoes-again/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning to Tie My Shoes Again" /><published>2024-06-13T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-06-13T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/06/13/learning-to-tie-my-shoes-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/06/13/learning-to-tie-my-shoes-again/">&lt;p&gt;I have tied a double knot in my shoe laces since I first learned to tie my own shoes. It is something I haven’t thought about a lot over the years. I just do it. Along the way I learned to tie many other types of knots, and I have worn boots, tennis shoes, sandals, and many other types of footwear. I’ve still just always tied a double knot. There has been no change in tne 45+ years of lacing up my shoes. Now, 50 years in, I have just simply started tying just a simple bow. No double knot. No special types of knot. I just lace them up, tie a bow, and go on with my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was married to my first wife she used to make fun of me regularly about tying my shoe with a double knot. I have now learned she was just sad and mean. Back then I still regularly wore boots and I worked manual labor across my houses and properties, so I didn’t let it bother me when she made jokes about me tying a double know with dress or athletic shoes. I just kept tying my shoes like I always have, even when I stopped wearing boots and doing manual labor. Another side effect that grew out of this practice that I never quite grew out of, was that when I wore regular shoes I would just kick them off instead of untying them, something that would eventually wear down the heels—-but it was something that didn’t matter until I got older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had a 4 week long painful achilles heel episode which I realized was due to me wearing an old pair of tennis shoes longer than I should have, and that the heel was worn out from me not untying my shoes and just kicking them off. I’ve since stopped tying my shoes in a double knot and stopped kicking them off, opting to untie and put them away. This has all been a sign for me that I needed to change my behavior. My earlier programming was having a real impact on my reality today. My young male programming and stubbornness was manifesting itself in ways that caused me real pain today, and I needed to change. I need to relearn tying my shoes, and not worry if they come untied as I make my way through the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unwinding what I was taught earlier in life has become a regular chore for me. I find these little things are what seem to matter the most. It is alright if my shoes come untied while walking down the street. I can stop and tie them. I can also tie my shoes tight enough that this doesn’t happen too often. I am getting good at unwinding things I was taught as a young child. I am on the hunt for other simple things that I can change in my life that will have a real impact on my quality of life, and unburden me with habits formed during some of the more clueless years of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Learning" /><category term="Growth" /><category term="Change" /><category term="Reprogramming" /><summary type="html">I have tied a double knot in my shoe laces since I first learned to tie my own shoes. It is something I haven’t thought about a lot over the years. I just do it. Along the way I learned to tie many other types of knots, and I have worn boots, tennis shoes, sandals, and many other types of footwear. I’ve still just always tied a double knot. There has been no change in tne 45+ years of lacing up my shoes. Now, 50 years in, I have just simply started tying just a simple bow. No double knot. No special types of knot. I just lace them up, tie a bow, and go on with my day.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/green-circuit-kin-poppy-bench.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/green-circuit-kin-poppy-bench.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I Got Covid Again</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/06/09/i-got-covid-again/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Got Covid Again" /><published>2024-06-09T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-06-09T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/06/09/i-got-covid-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/06/09/i-got-covid-again/">&lt;p&gt;Last Sunday I started feeling like crap again, and by this Sunday, I am writing this while feeling thankful to be alive. I can’t say that this experience was worse than my first or previous experiences (3 times now), but I can say it is a humbling experience. Monday through Friday the fever was an extreme roller coaster. Tuesday through Thursday I could barely breathe. After a week I am extremely tired, my chest hurts, and I am slowly coming back into the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am seriously humbled by the power of Covid. It resets everything for me. I don’t think about work. I don’t worry about the world around me. I am simply focused on living and getting better. It really flattens you in that way. I know this isn’t the experience for everyone, but for me, it is a world altering journey. I know for some it is barely a blip for them, but for others it becomes life threatening-—with my experience somewhere in between. It confounds me that there are so many folks who are dismissive of its powers, when Covid clearly wields such strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t feel like my life was in danger this week, but I am thankful to be alive coming out of it. It moves me that much. Covid shakes my being. There are few things in this world that leave me just sitting at peace in total silence for hours counting my blessing to be alive. I’ve had numerous brushes with death, and Covid is sobering. It leaves me wondering why so many don’t respect it. What is the basis for this? Did they not have similar experiences? Are they are too swept up in the noise of the world? IDK. Regardless, I am thankful and humbled after such an experience, and welcome every little bit of strength and life as it comes back into my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is precious. I love y’all. I love myself. I am very thankful to be here. I am very thankful for humbling experiences like this. It means everything to me to be here on a Sunday afternoon writing this. I am 52, and made it 25 years further than I ever thought I would make it. Weeks like this one force me to pause and reflect on everything I have, and show me just how lucky I am. Audrey was fortunate as she had just gone in to get her latest vaccine booster, which is something I should have done. I will go in to get a fresh dose in the next month, and I feel like getting flu and Covid shots will be something I end up doing for the rest of my life, and hopefully I won’t get taken out by one of these episodes at some point in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Covid" /><category term="Death" /><category term="Life" /><category term="Sick" /><category term="Illness" /><summary type="html">Last Sunday I started feeling like crap again, and by this Sunday, I am writing this while feeling thankful to be alive. I can’t say that this experience was worse than my first or previous experiences (3 times now), but I can say it is a humbling experience. Monday through Friday the fever was an extreme roller coaster. Tuesday through Thursday I could barely breathe. After a week I am extremely tired, my chest hurts, and I am slowly coming back into the world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/eugenics-butterfly-purple-flower.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/eugenics-butterfly-purple-flower.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>