<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-01-15T19:10:25-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kin Lane</title><subtitle>The ramblings, thoughts, and channeling of Kin Lane.</subtitle><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><entry><title type="html">Becoming a Hunter Gatherer in the Information Age</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/05/becoming-a-hunter-gatherer-in-the-information-age/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Becoming a Hunter Gatherer in the Information Age" /><published>2023-01-05T04:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-05T04:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/05/becoming-a-hunter-gatherer-in-the-information-age</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/05/becoming-a-hunter-gatherer-in-the-information-age/">&lt;p&gt;I was watching a documentary on Fat the other night on PBS. They were conducting a study on a tribe in Africa to better understand why they don’t struggle with obesity and heart disease. The long story short is that our challenges with obesity is wrapped in a mix of our genes, processed foods, and our sedentary existence. The tribe in Africa is just always on the go, and they aren’t eating food that is as processed as ours is, and they have been doing this for many, many generations. I am guessing that our weight problems aren’t the only problems we face due this reality we’ve constructed for ourselves, and I am guessing that many of our mental health challenges are a result of our diet and lack of activity. Leaving me thinking both about my physical and mental health as I move into 2023, an enjoy my 50th year on this planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have done a lot of work to get a handle on my physical health this last year. However, I can do more. I am still not in as good of shape as I need to be. I want to be stronger. I want to be more active. I have also done a lot of work to get a handle on my mental health in recent years. However, I can do more. I still have highs and lows, and some days I struggle to function at all. I’ve done well without medication, and watching my friends struggle with different types of diagnosis and side effects of pharmaceuticals, I am confident I am on the right track. I am able to strike a balance between maintaining my passion, drive, creativity, as well as know when I’m slipping into depression or some other worse state. With this said, I feel like much of my mental health challenges are just due to regular old capitalism and making our way in this fucked up world. I am pretty convinced that if I didn’t work so much, and spend so much time online, I would be in much better shape. This is something I’d like to understand more, and make adjustments over the next couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I love my work, I don’t love all that comes with working at a fast moving startup, managing a large team, and spending so much time online. I am good at what I do. I am paid well. I also work at one of the best startups around. I am definitely top of my field. Yet, I still struggle showing up and being present every day. I feel like this is due to 1) work &amp;amp; capitalism, and 2) being online. I don’t mind working hard. I enjoy it. I hate everything that comes with a job. I also am getting sick of being online all day. I want to be offline, but I struggle with how I will maintain the quality of life I enjoy working in technology. I grew up poor, so I do’nt mind ratcheting things back down in a reasonable way, but I’ve worked hard to get where I am at, so I don’t really want to walk away completely. I just want to transition the next phase of my career to spend less time online, and do more out in the real world. Preferably something within my local area. I love Oakland, California. This all has got me thinking about how would one become a local hunter gatherer in an information age, where I am able to sustain myself by roaming my city each day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not saying I would literally hunt for food and kill it in Oakland. I am adapting this concept to how one my make a living out in the real world, without having to take a job and be online all day. I don’t mind working. I don’t mind be busy. I don’t mind being active. I just really want to avoid having to work for the man and rely solely on my online skills to pay the bills. I just want to be able to roam the streets of Oakland everyday picking up trash, snapping photos, gathering stories, generating data, and doing a variety of things that others might be interested in sponsoring, subscribing to, and supporting in some way. I don’t mind being online. I just don’t want to be at my desk all day. I think about the tribe in Africa ad how they are engage with their local environment every day. I want that. I have fallen in love with Oakland and want to explore the city. I want to get to know each street, block, and neighborhood. I think this is going to be what I set into motion in 2023. I think I am going to start just wandering the streets a couple of days a week, documenting, thinking, picking up trash, and getting to know the space around me. I think over time it will become more clear to me how I can replace my 9-5 some day with something that is more nourishing, and helps me balance both my physical and mental health.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Hunter" /><category term="Gatherer" /><category term="Oakland" /><category term="Digital Self" /><summary type="html">I was watching a documentary on Fat the other night on PBS. They were conducting a study on a tribe in Africa to better understand why they don’t struggle with obesity and heart disease. The long story short is that our challenges with obesity is wrapped in a mix of our genes, processed foods, and our sedentary existence. The tribe in Africa is just always on the go, and they aren’t eating food that is as processed as ours is, and they have been doing this for many, many generations. I am guessing that our weight problems aren’t the only problems we face due this reality we’ve constructed for ourselves, and I am guessing that many of our mental health challenges are a result of our diet and lack of activity. Leaving me thinking both about my physical and mental health as I move into 2023, an enjoy my 50th year on this planet.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/america-immigration_dumping-ground-oakland-oak-tree.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Some See What Is Missing but I See Opportunity to Build</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/28/some-see-what-is-missing-but-i-see-opportunity-to-build/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some See What Is Missing but I See Opportunity to Build" /><published>2022-12-28T04:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-28T04:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/28/some-see-what-is-missing-but-i-see-opportunity-to-build</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/28/some-see-what-is-missing-but-i-see-opportunity-to-build/">&lt;p&gt;Over the Thanksgiving holiday I setup Mastodon instances for my personal and professional domains. Over the last month I’ve invested time into understanding how this federated world works and doesn’t work, and began doing the hard work of building community in this new space. Numerous folks from my Twitter community have come over to Mastodon, but many I know have opted to stay in the Twitterverse, or opted to join other communities for a variety of reasons. The main reason I’ve seen is that there is nothing happening in the Fediverse once they sign up. They don’t see their people, their topics, or anything going on, leaving them wondering why you’d want to be in this universe in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it is because I was there to help build Twitter, as well as numerous other communities in the early days, or I am just a builder mentality, but I see nothing but opportunity to build community within the Fediverse. In addition to seeing opportunity to build community I see a number of the historians, librarians, journalists, artists, and other people I see being essential to any community already jumping from Twitter to Mastodon. While many other tech people touted the technology, and specifically API behind the early growth and adoption of Twitter, I saw these people being present and acting as the essential building blocks of creating what matters within a community. Either way, I see the potential for building what is missing when it comes to injecting the social in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be overwhelming to start over, and to have to entirely rebuild your entire social life. I get it, most people are just about the social part when things are already in motion. Most people are just looking for their people, and want to get to the business of being entertained and socializing. I don’t think everyone should or would see the world as I do, and I think many of these folks will end up switching in the next wave of social upheaval on not just Twitter, but also Facebook, Instagram, and the other platforms that have dominated how we see and engage with the digital world around us. I am very excited about the potential on Mastodon, but I have a lot of learning about how it all works, and building to do when it comes to my network, but also trust when it comes to making my way through all the diverse communities popping up in this exciting virtual world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Social" /><category term="Community" /><category term="Mastodon" /><summary type="html">Over the Thanksgiving holiday I setup Mastodon instances for my personal and professional domains. Over the last month I’ve invested time into understanding how this federated world works and doesn’t work, and began doing the hard work of building community in this new space. Numerous folks from my Twitter community have come over to Mastodon, but many I know have opted to stay in the Twitterverse, or opted to join other communities for a variety of reasons. The main reason I’ve seen is that there is nothing happening in the Fediverse once they sign up. They don’t see their people, their topics, or anything going on, leaving them wondering why you’d want to be in this universe in the first place.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/norman-rockwell-ruby-bridges-fixing-cross.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dispatch From Coaling Station A</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/22/dispatch-from-coaling-station-a-copy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dispatch From Coaling Station A" /><published>2022-12-22T04:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-22T04:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/22/dispatch-from-coaling-station-a%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/22/dispatch-from-coaling-station-a-copy/">&lt;p&gt;We made it as far as Coalinga, CA, formerly known as Coaling Station A, before dark. This is where we’ll be spending two nights here before we continue on through Bakersfield to the edges of Death Valley. As one journeys to Death Valley you have to suspend your traditional views of the world, and no better place to do that than amongst the almond and orange orchards looking out across Interstate 5 outside of Coalinga, CA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/car-rv-coalinga.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Car and Travel Trailer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coalinga is a place I’ve only known as the place you drive by on Interstate 5 that smells like cow poop. In my older age and during my RVing journeys I am all about leaving my past assumptions about any person, place, or thing, and I am looking to experience Coalinga with a fresh and open mind. While I am not staying in Coalinga proper, the RV park we are in, provides a nice slice of what it is like to live in the agriculturally dominated area. 
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/road-through-orchard.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Road Through an Orchard&quot; /&gt;
I did a little historical search on our area, learning that the area was originally a coaling station for the Southern Pacific Railroad, and according to the Wikipedia page, “the city’s main industries are agriculture, oil, Cannabis, education and incarceration”. Which seems like a nice diverse set of investments if you ask me. After a leisurely drive through the town, I can concur, that seems to be the leading industries in the area.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/almond-rows.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Almond Tree Rows&quot; /&gt;
It’s hard around here. Trucks. People with hard looks on their face. People who have been hard done by. Combined with the cold spelling we are experiencing, it doesn’t leave much to explore and get to know. It is a truck area, so you have to drive to see anything and everything. It really isn’t cold. Just California cold. Keeping everyone indoors, or at least parked with your car running, while you wait for who knows what.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/coaling-plaza.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Coalinga Plaza&quot; /&gt;
I’ve driven by the Interstate 5 Freeway sign for Coalinga probably over 100 times. Always hitting the accelerator. This time I stopped and stayed for no real reason, other than it was the halfway point between home and my Death Valley destination. That was enough to make me stop this time. I can’t say that I will be coming back and staying the area, but I am thankful for stopping and strolling through the Orange and Almond orchards, and visiting the old town.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/wife-dog-oranges.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Wife and Dog in Orange Grove&quot; /&gt;
We will pack up in the morning, hitch up the trailer, and head for the lower Sierras, and make our way up to where the desert meets the mountains. It is here where our next adventure will begin. Coaling Station A was just a pit stop at the beginning of this journey, a cold, evenly rowed, isolated place. I am sure I will travel near Coalinga many more times in my life, and each time I can think about this one time when I stopped and took it in for just a moment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Coalinga" /><category term="California" /><category term="Cities" /><category term="Interstate 5" /><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html">We made it as far as Coalinga, CA, formerly known as Coaling Station A, before dark. This is where we’ll be spending two nights here before we continue on through Bakersfield to the edges of Death Valley. As one journeys to Death Valley you have to suspend your traditional views of the world, and no better place to do that than amongst the almond and orange orchards looking out across Interstate 5 outside of Coalinga, CA.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/old-house.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitter and Our Public Health</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/twitter-and-our-public-health/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter and Our Public Health" /><published>2022-12-18T04:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-18T04:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/twitter-and-our-public-health</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/twitter-and-our-public-health/">&lt;p&gt;As we all sit and watch the dumpster fire that is Twitter it can be easy to cheer on the demise of this platform. Although as I stare into the multi-color flames I can’t help but think about tall the work we’ve done on the Twitter plantation of the years, and the role it plays it our world. One are that comes to mind is how many of us received public health news as Covid gripped the world via Twitter. &lt;a href=&quot;https://covid-19-apis.postman.com/&quot;&gt;I spent months working on a Covid tracking website that primarily used the Twitter API to pull information from the state and county health departments who all use Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. I automated pulling of data from government health agencies and then aggregated it and pushed I back out all using the Twitter API — this will be hard to repeat in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While someday we may be able to get municipal, county, and state health departments to adopt a more federated approach to social media, I am guessing it will take years, and not reach the saturation levels of agencies as well as consistent tuned in that we have on Twitter today. Knowing how government agencies work, it will take some serious champions and evangelists to support standing up Mastodon servers for government agencies to see a more federated approach to social media and sharing of public health data with the masses. While I am fine with having to rebuild my social realm, and even see it as an opportunity, I can’t help but think about what we are collectively losing by letting Elon Musk set fire to the Twitterers we all worked so hard to build.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Twitter" /><category term="Health" /><category term="Municipal" /><category term="County" /><category term="State" /><summary type="html">As we all sit and watch the dumpster fire that is Twitter it can be easy to cheer on the demise of this platform. Although as I stare into the multi-color flames I can’t help but think about tall the work we’ve done on the Twitter plantation of the years, and the role it plays it our world. One are that comes to mind is how many of us received public health news as Covid gripped the world via Twitter. I spent months working on a Covid tracking website that primarily used the Twitter API to pull information from the state and county health departments who all use Twitter. I automated pulling of data from government health agencies and then aggregated it and pushed I back out all using the Twitter API — this will be hard to repeat in the future.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/birth-of-a-nation-abandoned-church-far.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Staying Within the Machine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/staying-within-the-machine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Staying Within the Machine" /><published>2022-12-18T04:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-18T04:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/staying-within-the-machine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/staying-within-the-machine/">&lt;p&gt;I made a conscious decision in 1997 to immerse myself in the incoming technological apparatus that capitalism was unleashing on the world. Until this moment in time I had purposefully avoided capitalism, a career, and understanding how business was applying technology. I had spent the previous decade actively working to subvert the system from the outside-in, and for me to have the impact I wanted on society I knew that I had to get closer to the machine and operate from within, otherwise I was just going to be chewed up by the machine. I noticed how well-designed the machine was at targeting, destroying, or simply locking up threats that were outside the system, but just how difficult it was for the machine to target in between its own gears—this is where I needed to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the first ten years of this centruy just studying the machine. I needed to know how it was going to work. Once I began to understand how things work I began looking for ways to subvert the machine. To tell stories about how we can still live within the machine, while also throwing our bodies against the machine. You have to learn to tell stories very loudly, and as demonstrated recently with the switch in power via the Twittersphere, you have to be ready to pack up and move to a different part of the machine at any moment. There are two reasons I position myself where I am at, 1) to understand how the machine works so my stories are relevant to the hum of the machine, and 2) make it more difficult to be targeted by the machine for extermination or incarceration. If I am playing along, my stories sound familiar and relevant to folks, but sticking around and keeping my storytelling going is the number one way I do this hustle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that you can live a life outside the machine. It isn’t easy, and you have to learn to do without. I may go there at some point. But for now, I’ve kind of learned to enjoy the game. I just have to keep reminding myself why I’m here. I have to not let the sounds of the machine drive me mad, or force me to lose my soul. I have to internalize the sounds and vibrations of the machine, and empathize with the emotions of those who exist around me perpetually to find the stories that matter to us in any given moment. I regularly struggle staying sane and coherent amongst all the noise, and perpetually find myself unable to find the signal that matters, despite years of evidence to the contrary. I’ll keep on keep’n on within this state of existence for as long as I can. At some point I fully expect to need to step away, but I’ve gotten to know the machine so well, it has kind of become an old friend. Not for the service it does to its master, but just as a big, dumb, lumbering robot that marches on day after day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a regular post to remind myself of the bigger picture. I really, really, really get tired of technology most days. If I could figure out how to make money doing something offline, I’d sure jump at it. The problem is that I am good at what I do. The problem is staying the course and not burning myself out. It isn’t that I work too much. It is simply that working in tech lacks a lot of nutrients, and the work tends to consume you. Ultimately I don’t think I will ever leave. I don’t think I would enjoy just sitting somewhere checked out. It is just important that we sustain. I am not looking to get rich. I like making a name for myself. But I am more interested in being that slightly interesting person telling stories to anyone who will listen about this crazy invisible machine we’ve built around us that very few seem to even notice. The trick is to keep finding the stories that I find interesting, but also others find interesting. Preferably stories that help us all make sense of this digital chaos that we’ve unleashed, and help us all stay afloat in some meaningful ways.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Career" /><summary type="html">I made a conscious decision in 1997 to immerse myself in the incoming technological apparatus that capitalism was unleashing on the world. Until this moment in time I had purposefully avoided capitalism, a career, and understanding how business was applying technology. I had spent the previous decade actively working to subvert the system from the outside-in, and for me to have the impact I wanted on society I knew that I had to get closer to the machine and operate from within, otherwise I was just going to be chewed up by the machine. I noticed how well-designed the machine was at targeting, destroying, or simply locking up threats that were outside the system, but just how difficult it was for the machine to target in between its own gears—this is where I needed to be.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/copper-circuit-old-computer-bletchley-crypto.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An Apocalypse Groundhog Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/04/an-apocalypse-groundhog-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Apocalypse Groundhog Day" /><published>2022-12-04T04:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T04:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/04/an-apocalypse-groundhog-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/04/an-apocalypse-groundhog-day/">&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been writing about my apocalyptic upbringing lately because for the most part I’ve moved beyond it. Writing here on my blog and pondering the subject since the 2016 election has put me in a pretty sweet spot when it comes to living life and not stressing about the programming I was raised with. However, recently a story was shared with me about someone I grew up with sharing rantings about how the apocalypse was just around the corner and wanted to make sure this person I was talking to was fully prepared. This person has a much more caring approach to sharing upcoming apocalyptic news than some of the other people I grew up with who take a much more “you are either with us or against us” attitude about each upcoming apocalypse, but still the same narrative applies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This person was one of the origins of my anxiety on this subject, with warnings going back to about 1985. I remember the early warnings of nuclear apocalypse and being given a gun by this person. Something that would repeat regularly, but the most notable were the mid 1980s nuclear war, and the 2000 Y2K bug. I’ve been pretty angry for the last decade or so at this person, as I was making my way out of this nonsense, but more recently I am pretty sad for them that they are stuck in a sort of apocalyptic Groundhog Day. Playing out over and over, but they never quite are able to see that their apocalyptic beliefs are more about them and less about the world around them. I feel sad for them, but not bad enough where I’ll spend much time trying to convince them otherwise—-I spent years trying that unsuccessfully. I’d prefer just living my life and keeping myself convinced that while there are plenty of scary things in the world to focus on, life is amazing, and totally worth living in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can now see how genuinely afraid this person is of the world. I can see how their view of the world is derived from simmering in medium-grade toxic masculinity, exacerbated by an actual toxic environment of lead, plastics, oils, and other substances we are poisoning our world with. I’ve seen this person physically fight other men, siphon lead gas from trucks, and remember their stories of how they used to eat lead from the window sill as a child. I just don’t think at this point they are aware of the toxicity they’ve basted in for most of their life, and they sure can’t see the chain yanking they’ve responded to over the generations from politicians and the wealthy to keep them very afraid of cities, and people from other countries. The fear is so vivid now, but in 1985 and 2000 I couldn’t see it. I just experienced, felt, and channeled it. Now I just see someone who is very isolated and afraid, and unable to see that they’ve spent their entire adult lives preparing for a societal collapse that has never come. I know. I know. It still could. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my vantage point now, I can see that these people in my life who live in this apocalypse Groundhog Day were severely traumatized as children, and never quite given the love and therapy necessary to escape the cycles of fear and trauma inflicted upon them. These people are my seniors, and I’ve spent years exhaustively trying to convince them of how beautiful and nourishing the world can be, without much success. It has taken me a decade to dig myself out of this reality, and I have full control over my situation. If they ever showed up on my doorstep yielding themselves to the journey I may change my feelings, but for now, I’m focused 100% on me and my child. I don’t have time to spend on them anymore. It is their own personal Groundhog Day, with their own lessons to be learned. It makes me sad to see someone throw away a perfectly amazing life and spend it fearing some horrible event that is always just around the corner. With no ability to see that that corner has existed for the last 40 years, without a confirmation of their fears. This lack of self-awareness of oneself in the world, not being able to step back and imagine a brighter future terrifies me. Which is why I focus on the sunshine today, the people who are with me today, and doing what nourishes me–writing about this magical world I’ve been blessed with the opportunity to experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Apocalypse" /><category term="Fear" /><category term="Politics" /><summary type="html">I haven’t been writing about my apocalyptic upbringing lately because for the most part I’ve moved beyond it. Writing here on my blog and pondering the subject since the 2016 election has put me in a pretty sweet spot when it comes to living life and not stressing about the programming I was raised with. However, recently a story was shared with me about someone I grew up with sharing rantings about how the apocalypse was just around the corner and wanted to make sure this person I was talking to was fully prepared. This person has a much more caring approach to sharing upcoming apocalyptic news than some of the other people I grew up with who take a much more “you are either with us or against us” attitude about each upcoming apocalypse, but still the same narrative applies.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/stalin-time-dragon-shadow-sun.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Redlining: A Drive Down Grand Avenue in Oakland</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/27/posting-a-message-nobody-reads-copy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Redlining: A Drive Down Grand Avenue in Oakland" /><published>2022-11-27T04:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-27T04:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/27/posting-a-message-nobody-reads%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/27/posting-a-message-nobody-reads-copy/">&lt;p&gt;I was driving my friend and fellow API conspirator Fran Mendez around Oakland this week while he was in town from Spain. I regularly drive people around Oakland, and most have had some experience in the city, but most have experienced West Oakland, and have very little awareness of the redlining that has shaped the city. Most people just see poverty and trash and assume a traditional racist stance and think that the people living here have chosen to live like this. When in reality, it has been engineered and orchestrated. To demonstrate, I wanted to drive Grand Avenue in Oakland, traveling from the higher grade areas to the lower grade areas in a “Residential Security Map” from the 1930s, which was used to shape the city we live in and experience today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kmJhXYVuSLk&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you pay attention to the video as you approach the redline you begin to see less investment, and then you experience the edge of the redline defined by the freeway. When this map was created, the freeway did not exist, it was added along the line. Once you cross the line you begin to see trends alongside the road, more abandoned stores, and a general lack of investment. You begin to see some new construction of residential and office space, and there is evidence of manufacturing going on, but the impact of planning almost 100 years ago is still evident. I have a video driving the other which I may play with some, and I have one driving up San Pablo towards Berkeley, and back again which I may turn into a video as well. I am not that skilled at working with video, but this is giving me some practice, while also helping me convey how these historical relics are still shaping our world today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Cities" /><category term="Oakland" /><category term="Redlining" /><category term="Racism" /><summary type="html">I was driving my friend and fellow API conspirator Fran Mendez around Oakland this week while he was in town from Spain. I regularly drive people around Oakland, and most have had some experience in the city, but most have experienced West Oakland, and have very little awareness of the redlining that has shaped the city. Most people just see poverty and trash and assume a traditional racist stance and think that the people living here have chosen to live like this. When in reality, it has been engineered and orchestrated. To demonstrate, I wanted to drive Grand Avenue in Oakland, traveling from the higher grade areas to the lower grade areas in a “Residential Security Map” from the 1930s, which was used to shape the city we live in and experience today. If you pay attention to the video as you approach the redline you begin to see less investment, and then you experience the edge of the redline defined by the freeway. When this map was created, the freeway did not exist, it was added along the line. Once you cross the line you begin to see trends alongside the road, more abandoned stores, and a general lack of investment. You begin to see some new construction of residential and office space, and there is evidence of manufacturing going on, but the impact of planning almost 100 years ago is still evident. I have a video driving the other which I may play with some, and I have one driving up San Pablo towards Berkeley, and back again which I may turn into a video as well. I am not that skilled at working with video, but this is giving me some practice, while also helping me convey how these historical relics are still shaping our world today.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/berkeley-redlining-drive-thumbnail.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Posting a Message Nobody Reads</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/26/posting-a-message-nobody-reads/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Posting a Message Nobody Reads" /><published>2022-11-26T04:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-26T04:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/26/posting-a-message-nobody-reads</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/26/posting-a-message-nobody-reads/">&lt;p&gt;I had just stood up &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.apievangelist.com/web/@api&quot;&gt;the Mastodon instance for my API Evangelist account&lt;/a&gt;, logged in, and was staring at the empty message box. What would I say? I had no followers. Nobody would be listening even if I did say something. So I followed my Kin Lane account, and then followed API Evangelist back. Now at least I would be talking to myself. This seems much more appropriate. I don’t need an audience. I’ve always (that’s a lie) done API Evangelist for myself, and secondarily for others. Over the last decade of storytelling I’ve developed a pantheon of characters I am talking to when I publish any stories. Some were made up from real people I come across in my adventures, others are made up entirely just to fit in with the narrative I am peddling. I like to pretend I don’t need an audience, but I am also hyper aware of an on again and off again need to feed the ego, and actually have someone out there reading and engaging with my writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is terrifying to not have any social followers. A significant portion of my social presence is wrapped up in my identity as the API Evangelist and now the Chief Evangelist. Twitter has played a significant role in feeding my ego, and paying the bills. You experience ego whiplash when you go from 13.6K followers on Twitter to 0 followers on Mastodon. I have 17K followers on my Kin Lane Twitter, and experienced the same whiplash twice over this week. Honestly, I love it though. A little ego flattening is essential in this world. However, it isn’t just ego, and I’ve honestly been working on the Twitter plantation since 2007, and these 13.5K + 17K followers are the building blocks of digital identity. Not just my identity, but my career. I’ve made a couple of million dollars through my blog and my Twitter account since 2010. So, should I be grateful to Twitter for this? Is it purely their “network effect”? Or is this just a fraction of what I could have made if I couldn’t have fully controlled my contribution to the Twitter community? Similar to what I am now doing with Mastodon? Rebuilding all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens when I am suddenly nobody? Well, that is a little dramatic, as many of my API people were pretty easy to find on Mastodon. I guess some of my brand translates. Partly because I’ve built in on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apievangelist.com/&quot;&gt;apievangelist.com domain&lt;/a&gt;. Grounding my storytelling within my own domain(s), and being thoughtful about which networks I engage on, and syndicating my stories to is the number one reason I’ve been able to make a living through my use of social media. I am not afraid of having to rebuild this via Mastodon, and other federated solutions. I am not quitting Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, and other networks. They are necessary evils to a certain degree. I am even considering how I can leverage other platforms I’ve used like Tumblr in new ways, but with Mastodon operating within my domain at the core. Leveraging my blog(s), and messaging, social, and other APIs to orchestrate, automate, and help me be more organized in my approach to how I use these platforms. Once again, I find myself thinking about the value of my digital bits, this time it is the value of a message with nobody following me. Sitting here staring at this empty text box with zero followers on a federated network is humbling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do we post messages with text, images, and video online? Do we do it for attention? Do we do it to help educate and inform others? There are many positive and not so positive reasons we post messages online. I do not think many people publish text, images, or video online without intending to influence and communicate with one or many other human beings. I do it to get my ideas out of my head. I do it because I like crafting stories, and having a real or perceived audience helps with this process. I thoroughly enjoyed sitting in this moment contemplating the posting of a message that nobody would read. I opted to be all business, acknowledging this wonderful new federated world, but quickly getting to work automating my presence here using the open source Mastodon API for both my Kin Lane and API Evangelist instances. You see, my identity is all wrapped up in APIs in many different ways-—it is APIs all the way down. Which is why I can write posts that nobody reads because I am not just just pandering to my audience, I am actually building out an automated information network about APIs using APIs. Now, let’s get to work building out this network, so eventually somebody will read these messages.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Twitter" /><category term="Mastodon" /><category term="Social" /><category term="Domains" /><category term="Messaging" /><category term="Monetization" /><summary type="html">I had just stood up the Mastodon instance for my API Evangelist account, logged in, and was staring at the empty message box. What would I say? I had no followers. Nobody would be listening even if I did say something. So I followed my Kin Lane account, and then followed API Evangelist back. Now at least I would be talking to myself. This seems much more appropriate. I don’t need an audience. I’ve always (that’s a lie) done API Evangelist for myself, and secondarily for others. Over the last decade of storytelling I’ve developed a pantheon of characters I am talking to when I publish any stories. Some were made up from real people I come across in my adventures, others are made up entirely just to fit in with the narrative I am peddling. I like to pretend I don’t need an audience, but I am also hyper aware of an on again and off again need to feed the ego, and actually have someone out there reading and engaging with my writing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/oldroad-old-road-clean-view.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I Have My Mastodon Instance for Kin Lane Set Up</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/25/i-have-my-mastodon-instance-for-kin-lane-setup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Have My Mastodon Instance for Kin Lane Set Up" /><published>2022-11-25T04:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-25T04:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/25/i-have-my-mastodon-instance-for-kin-lane-setup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/25/i-have-my-mastodon-instance-for-kin-lane-setup/">&lt;p&gt;I have been simmering on the whole Twitter drama lately, and the mass migration to Mastodon. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apievangelist.com/2022/11/14/where-does-mastodon-fit-in-with-my-overall-api-circus-stack/&quot;&gt;As I said before, I am not being emotional about this, and want to think about this in the context of what I consider to be my overall domain strategy&lt;/a&gt;. I run my own websites, blogs, email, and I think the time has come for me to own my social network. It makes me sad and a little mad to see what is happening to Twitter, and while I won’t be deleting my account or going anywhere soon, I do want to explore what Mastodon has to offer, and consider how it fits into my world. I use Twitter for a lot more than just talking with my friends. I use it to research things. I automate curation and syndication of my stories using the API. And it is one of the last few social applications I will allow on my mobile phone. Twitter is still very important to me, but I think it is time to begin laying the foundation for my social presence within my domain(s) using Mastodon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some noodling I decided to install my own Mastodon server. I have the skills and resources to do this, and it is important to me that I understand the inner workings of it all. I operate my world on Amazon Web Services, so I spun up a Debian Linux EC2 instance, and got to work setting up my social presence—-I followed this setup script (https://www.linuxbabe.com/debian/install-mastodon-debian-server), but then made it my own. The first time I did it I created a user called “info” and made a few mistakes in how I configured my AWS S3 storage and other things, but ultimately &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.kinlane.com/web/@kin&quot;&gt;I ended up with a working single user instance of Mastodon under the kinlane.com domain&lt;/a&gt;. This will be my personal and professional social domain, where I focus on the things that matter to me as a human being online. Next, I will get to work setting one up for my apievangelist.com domain, but for now I am learning the ropes with my more personal instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you won’t find me becoming all evangelical about Mastodon to others, you will find me talking a lot about how I use it moving forward. I can solidly see where it fits into my infrastructure stack. Social is very important to me, and Elon Musk and Twitter are squandering a lot of work I’ve put into that platform over the years. I am willing to do all this work over again, but I am not looking to do it too many more times. I feel like we are hitting this threshold with platforms and technology in general, but not all of us will be able to sort it all out. I feel like having Elon Musk acting like this out in public is doing us all a favor, because this is happening behind the scenes of many of the platforms we are using, they are just better at keeping the public performance under control. Federated infrastructure is appealing to me, and operating my essential digital resources and capabilities within my own is something I’m very opinionated about. However, I think with Twitter, my view of things has been obfuscated by other social and political goings on, and I don’t think I am entirely thinking straight about the platform, and setting up Mastodon is helping me shift that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I measure the work I have done on Twitter beyond just the number of followers I have there. I worry about being able to assemble the same scope of audience I have on Twitter on my Mastodon, but honestly it is a game to me, so I am up for playing. As I engage on my Mastodon platform, exploring this federated universe, I am learning a lot. I am getting a chance to reboot not just my Twitter presence, but my overall social presence. There isn’t a single social network I am loyal to, but I have done years of work on Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and LinkedIn, so it is unlikely I will be going anywhere soon. But, I do see the opportunity to reboot how I engage on these platforms, shifting the center of balance once again to my domain, and syndicate out as necessary. It is a fascinating world. I didn’t have much hope that we could recreate our social world out here (in the Fediverse), but I see it was more about me being ground down by the politics of Twitter, than it was about the reality of doing it. This is how they want us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, well I am pretty stoked to have this instance of Mastodon setup. I am working with Audrey to set up her instance, and I am setting up a multi-user instance for API Evangelist. I won’t be letting others sign up, but I will be setting up multiple accounts within the domain to focus on specific topical domains. My goal is to minimize the information overload on the main API Evangelist channel, and provide specific channels you can subscribe to, using each individual user as a way to separate things out. We’ll see. I am in early days now, but from an information architecture, social, and API perspective it is pretty exciting times. I have a new federated canvas that I can paint on. Sure, it is scary because I have to rebuild my audience, but that is fine. It will give me a chance to build out new relationships, and form new communities across a variety of topics. I managed to increase my excitement levels about social networking and Mastodon by a couple of levels. This is good. I needed this right now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Twitter" /><category term="Mastodon" /><category term="Social" /><category term="Domains" /><summary type="html">I have been simmering on the whole Twitter drama lately, and the mass migration to Mastodon. As I said before, I am not being emotional about this, and want to think about this in the context of what I consider to be my overall domain strategy. I run my own websites, blogs, email, and I think the time has come for me to own my social network. It makes me sad and a little mad to see what is happening to Twitter, and while I won’t be deleting my account or going anywhere soon, I do want to explore what Mastodon has to offer, and consider how it fits into my world. I use Twitter for a lot more than just talking with my friends. I use it to research things. I automate curation and syndication of my stories using the API. And it is one of the last few social applications I will allow on my mobile phone. Twitter is still very important to me, but I think it is time to begin laying the foundation for my social presence within my domain(s) using Mastodon.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/bf-skinner-pink-elephant-car-wash.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My New Jekyll Template</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/16/my-new-jekyll-template/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My New Jekyll Template" /><published>2022-10-16T05:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-16T05:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/10/16/my-new-jekyll-template</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/16/my-new-jekyll-template/">&lt;p&gt;I got some inspiration lately and went hunting for a new Jekyll Theme to rule my blog universe. I love blogging across my domains, and I love the storytelling scaffolding of a Jekyll site running on Github. The balance of words and data with a GitOps API-driven approach to things just works for my brand of storytelling. This new “docs” themed template (https://jekyll-theme-docs.netlify.app/) has everything I love about Jekyll from a storytelling perspective but they have gone the extra distance with collections and the mix of data, blogs, pages, and the magic of a static website. If you don’t get Jekyll it can be difficult to see, but if you do, you really understand the magic of YAML-driven data and words combined with FREE website hosting via GitHub pages. I have now applied this template across my four top domains, Kin Lane, Alternate Kin Lane, Algorotoscope, and API Evangelist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason blogging is my primary mode of storytelling. I find it difficult to write just in my notebook. There is some public performance and ego to what I do, but honestly I am not driven by page views or engagement. It just has to be published publicly on a blog for it to matter. It has happened. It is real. Once it lives within a domain on the web. Weird I know, but it is the only way I can reliably produce the content, visuals, and storytelling I need to move forward. So be it. Anyways, Jekyll and GitHub has played an important role in this storytelling evolution because of the ease in publishing stories, essays, and landing pages via a simple static blog. This “Docs” template has a lot of the usual things I like, but it also has a few bells and whistles, and work invested in information qrchitecture that makes it a delight to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost this new template has a search. Which in a static realm isn’t trivial. Since all my sites act as a sort of archive and memory for me, this is something I have wanted for some time now. The way it setup its “docs” section provided me with a blueprint for how I can organize existing bodies of stories and data, but also how I can incrementally organize, iterate, and evolve new stories. For example, I am able to better tag stories on API Evangelist and surface them in “docs” or “info” sections like design or governance. I can also just write like the wind over time and dump into the “posts” folder and then on a regular basis evaluate what I have written and organize into a more curated outline of topics. This template also has RSS, Atom, Sitemap.xml, and some other utility capabilities that just make things a lot easier to manage. Overall it is a power template that really maximizes the potential of a GitOps Jekyll approach to storytelling, which I’ll be taking full advantage of from my API-first view of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some concerns about writing out in the open, but ultimately it is getting increasingly harder to be found online today and stand out, so these concerns aren’t very overwhelming. I am more concerned with writing and organizing my thoughts and doing it out in the open view Jekyll within a specific domain, using data, collections, posts, and pages to orchestrate the variety of stories I have stuck in my head. Some of these narratives and other projects will end up just living online via a each site I publish, however others will end up being a printed affair, taking what I’ve organized and assembling as a book. Projects like Drone Recovery and Algorotocope. The Jekyll site will continue to be a creative vehicle for publishing my thoughts within these domains, but at some point I’d like to have a physical book I can put on the shelf and visit without even having to get online. I feel a new generation of storytelling emerging, and after migrating my sites over this new template I realize just how much fiction and non-fiction writing I have done over the last decade. Something I am looking to continue and increase velocity in the next decade.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="Storytelling" /><category term="Stories" /><category term="GitHub" /><summary type="html">I got some inspiration lately and went hunting for a new Jekyll Theme to rule my blog universe. I love blogging across my domains, and I love the storytelling scaffolding of a Jekyll site running on Github. The balance of words and data with a GitOps API-driven approach to things just works for my brand of storytelling. This new “docs” themed template (https://jekyll-theme-docs.netlify.app/) has everything I love about Jekyll from a storytelling perspective but they have gone the extra distance with collections and the mix of data, blogs, pages, and the magic of a static website. If you don’t get Jekyll it can be difficult to see, but if you do, you really understand the magic of YAML-driven data and words combined with FREE website hosting via GitHub pages. I have now applied this template across my four top domains, Kin Lane, Alternate Kin Lane, Algorotoscope, and API Evangelist.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/jekyll-site-template-2022.png" /></entry></feed>