<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-09-16T13:28:17-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kin Lane</title><subtitle>The ramblings, thoughts, and channeling of Kin Lane.</subtitle><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><entry><title type="html">Leaving People Behind</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/25/leaving-people-behind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leaving People Behind" /><published>2023-07-25T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-25T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/25/leaving-people-behind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/25/leaving-people-behind/">&lt;p&gt;I have long struggled and written about the people I leave behind in my life. There are a long list of people I have moved away from, severed communication with, and just evolved beyond over the years. Honestly, very, very, very few people can keep up with my mercurial approach to living, my appetite for travel and learning things, and more recently my determination to do the hard work of unraveling the programming of my youth has left even more people behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing this to brush off the latest wave of cords that I’ve either released or have been neglected and ignored to the point that they’ll break free without much effort. I am sitting in New York in the most expensive apartment I have ever rented, going to work for a major financial data and media outlet. I struggle to find people in my life who I can discuss my success with. I can only talk to a handful of friends about what I do and how far along in my journey I am—others can’t relate, and some actively see me as rubbing it in their face and bragging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d say that I only have about 5% guilt left about my success when engaging with people from my past. I’d say I’ve moved from about 60% guilt to 25% guilt in the last five years through a lot of hard work. However my last two trips to Oregon to visit friends and family, and exiting from Postman this summer has helped me get down to about 5% guilt regarding the people I leave behind. I am not cutthroat	and mean in my approach, but I don’t have many fucks to give when it comes to moving forward in the second half of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not doing this to be snobby, rich or famous. I am simply looking to live my life to the fullest–while celebrating along the way. I avoid screwing people over financially, but I am very, very guarded when it comes to whom I let in emotionally. This is my game. You have to pay your dues to get in on the game and hustle. You also have to be moving at a similar velocity either physically, creatively, or technically—otherwise we aren’t even on the same wavelength. Historically I have done most of the work switching wavelengths, but now that I have turned 50 I am expecting others to do the work. The bar is much higher now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Relationships" /><category term="Change" /><category term="Programming" /><category term="History" /><category term="Baggage" /><summary type="html">I have long struggled and written about the people I leave behind in my life. There are a long list of people I have moved away from, severed communication with, and just evolved beyond over the years. Honestly, very, very, very few people can keep up with my mercurial approach to living, my appetite for travel and learning things, and more recently my determination to do the hard work of unraveling the programming of my youth has left even more people behind.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://algorithmic.rotoscope.work/images/collections/the-persistence-of-memory/old-barn.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://algorithmic.rotoscope.work/images/collections/the-persistence-of-memory/old-barn.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Making the Most of a Strange World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/23/making-the-most-of-a-strange-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making the Most of a Strange World" /><published>2023-07-23T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-23T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/23/making-the-most-of-a-strange-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/23/making-the-most-of-a-strange-world/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve done a lot of thinking lately. The 3rd anniversary of Isaiahs death has me reassessing everything around me. The last three years have been surreal. The covid pandemic dictated the shape of how I see the world around me, but it was something in which Isaiah’s death had taken to new levels. The world always has seemed a little off to me, but in May and June of this year, everything seemed off and in need of shaking up. So I did just that—I shook the Etch A Sketch with all of the powers at my disposal, and in the way I saw fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I stopped working. Burnout had left me near total depletion. Covid took away any fucks I had to give about anything except what really mattered. Then coming up on the 3rd anniversary of Isaiah’s death and turning 51 was forcing me to think of things in very absolute terms. There was no room for unnecessary energy or activity in my life. The world is strange, and most of the time I just deal with the world on its terms, letting each day roll by as it is, but I found myself unable to do this, and in desperate need to shift the world to match exactly what I wanted and needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The math for my job wasn’t penciling out anymore. Living in Oakland seemed tainted by Covid. Audrey seemed like she has not just recovered, but was beginning to grow and thrive again—however I needed to be sure. The world just had that weird Truman Show like quality to it, but with some disturbing and dark Instagram filter applied. Nothing seemed real. It all seemed scripted and out of my control. I needed to shake the Etch A Sketch, and redraw everything around me, otherwise I wasn’t going to unable to continue functioning. It was that serious. I don’t know how to articulate it, but if I didn’t reconfigure my life and the world around me, I wasn’t sure I would be able to continue with the regularly scheduled programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved from Oakland, CA to New  York, NY. I went from Postman, a startup, to Bloomberg, a well established enterprise. I spent May and June getting my head on my shoulders. I tore myself down and rebuilt myself back up. I had let myself get into pretty bad shape, though working too hard in a covid tinged world, but more importantly through ignoring my mental health. Luckily I don’t drink anymore, otherwise I think it could have been much worse. The result was still a very unwieldy couple of months emotionally, but ultimately something that was neatly wrapped up within 60 days and done in a way that caused the minimal amount of damage to Audrey, Poppy, Kaia and my well being (can’t speak for others). Something that I historically haven’t very good at, but this round I was pretty proud of my laser focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is a strange place. I find if I operate on purely the terms set by the world around me, everything can end up in a pretty sad state. However, I can be quite the dictator when it comes to protecting what matters most to me, and be damned everyone and everything else. Granted, for others, it can be pretty difficult to deal with me as a family member, friend, employee, or otherwise. If you’ve been in my life for a number of years, you have likely grown accustom to it (or told me to get lost)—I am an unwieldy bitch. However, I find that focusing on who I am and what truly matters results in being able to continue taking things to the next level professionally, and producing storytelling that matters the most to this ongoing production of the Kin Lane show.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Reboot" /><category term="Rest" /><category term="Burnout" /><summary type="html">I’ve done a lot of thinking lately. The 3rd anniversary of Isaiahs death has me reassessing everything around me. The last three years have been surreal. The covid pandemic dictated the shape of how I see the world around me, but it was something in which Isaiah’s death had taken to new levels. The world always has seemed a little off to me, but in May and June of this year, everything seemed off and in need of shaking up. So I did just that—I shook the Etch A Sketch with all of the powers at my disposal, and in the way I saw fit.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://algorithmic.rotoscope.work/images/collections/bf-skinner-behaviorism/bf-skinner-old-piano-playing-hospital.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://algorithmic.rotoscope.work/images/collections/bf-skinner-behaviorism/bf-skinner-old-piano-playing-hospital.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Do We Want a Contactless World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/18/do-we-want-a-contactless-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do We Want a Contactless World" /><published>2023-04-18T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-18T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/18/do-we-want-a-contactless-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/18/do-we-want-a-contactless-world/">&lt;p&gt;During my recent wanderings in Oakland, I came across a parking sign that promised a “Contactless” experience, which got me thinking about the concept of contactless in our world today. It’s a term we hear quite often, either explicitly stated or implied by barriers, plexiglass, or the absence of human presence. As usual, I have some questions about this phenomenon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is contactless, exactly?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do we want a contactless world?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is contactless inherently good or bad?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the social implications of contactless?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the definition, contactless refers to anything that doesn’t involve physical contact or direct interaction, such as technology that enables a smart card or mobile phone to connect wirelessly to an electronic reader, often for making payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand the need for social distancing during the pandemic and think it’s a sensible approach. I have also always been a fan of minimizing human contact by using self-service checkout lanes, vending machines, and other forms of automation. Although I lean towards avoiding human interaction, there are moments when I can be very good at engaging with people under any circumstances. I am torn between celebrating a contactless world and recognizing that it may not be a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I contemplate who contactless is for and what it is, I find myself in some uncomfortable places. At first glance, contactless is meant to prevent the spread of a virus, which is a positive thing. However, contactless didn’t start in 2020. Self-service and contactless mobile experiences have been evolving for some time now. Although I believe contactless is intended for consumers, I think it’s more for business reasons than for us. There are many financial, labor, and other concerns intertwined with the idea of contactless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each contactless interaction generates one more data point to surveil, resulting in yet another digital cord attached to your digital self. Every contactless transaction throughout your day adds up, generating timestamps, surveillance photos, biometric data, and other information. While a coffee order placed with a human and paid for with cash may be captured on a security camera, the interaction does not appear on my permanent digital record. These data accumulations have significant consequences, and we have yet to discuss how they are used to shape our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human interaction is crucial. We know it is essential for the development of children and continues to be important throughout our lives. It can be what keeps us alive for a long time. Losing contact with one another seems like it would be harmful to humanity. It feels like it would remove the lubricant we need to function as communities and as a society. I will spend time looking into research in this area. I am genuinely interested in understanding the impact that mobile devices are having, as well as how this phenomenon has escalated during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it increasingly challenging to interact with people in public because I don’t do it as much as I used to. I’m out of practice. Although I still have the ability to engage when necessary as part of my job or while out in public, I just don’t do it as often. It feels like one of the missing nutrients in my life these days. Contactless feels like scurvy or some sort of vitamin deficiency to me. It’s something I used to have in abundance during my younger years, but it’s missing now. Contactless is a difficult topic to wrap my head around. I’ll need to spend more time thinking about it to understand it better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Contactless" /><category term="People" /><category term="Covid" /><summary type="html">During my recent wanderings in Oakland, I came across a parking sign that promised a “Contactless” experience, which got me thinking about the concept of contactless in our world today. It’s a term we hear quite often, either explicitly stated or implied by barriers, plexiglass, or the absence of human presence. As usual, I have some questions about this phenomenon:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://algorithmic.rotoscope.work/images/collections/citizenship/citizenship-rocking-chair-on-porch_36332220150_o.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://algorithmic.rotoscope.work/images/collections/citizenship/citizenship-rocking-chair-on-porch_36332220150_o.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How We See Things Like a Bank Collapse</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/19/how-we-see-things-like-a-bank-collapse/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How We See Things Like a Bank Collapse" /><published>2023-03-19T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-19T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/19/how-we-see-things-like-a-bank-collapse</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/19/how-we-see-things-like-a-bank-collapse/">&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about the storytelling surrounding the recent collapse of the Silicon Valley Bank (SVB) a lot lately. I just gave a talk at a company retreat about the importance of storytelling, and how all dimensions of the SVB situation is about telling and believing in stories. From our belief in money, markets, banks, to our continued belief in technology and venture capital, the recent goings on was all about stories. A significant part of this storytelling involves how we see things, and when you have very abstract concepts like financial products, businesses, and technology, the images we use to understand what is happening. When it came to SVB I particularly noticed the usage of images involving the front of SVB bank branches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, what is going on in there?
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/silicon-valley-bank/people-looking-in-windows.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;People looking in Windows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s have a dude making a phone call in front!
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/silicon-valley-bank/dude-on-phone.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;People looking in Windows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get some security guards out front to make it look like something of value is in there.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/silicon-valley-bank/guards-in-front.webp&quot; alt=&quot;People looking in Windows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s make sure to show that they are responding to customers.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/silicon-valley-bank/employee-explaining.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;People looking in Windows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, people are getting the message.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/silicon-valley-bank/people-reading-letters.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;People looking in Windows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Show a money truck in front to show there is money.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/silicon-valley-bank/money-truck.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;People looking in Windows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s just show people hanging out having fun.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/silicon-valley-bank/people-standing.webp&quot; alt=&quot;People looking in Windows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be a little more creative with a reflection.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/silicon-valley-bank/reflection-in-window.webp&quot; alt=&quot;People looking in Windows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the goings on of the last couple of weeks I was just tuned into the storytelling, and the visuals that media sites and blogs were using grabbed my attention. I love that our notion of a bank is still so anchored on the notion of a physical bank with vaults of cash. That when there is a digital run on a bank we still need images of physical locations to tell our stories. All of this stuff is so very abstract, and out of reach of our imaginations, despite spending so much of our time online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like our inability to see complex financial products and the expanding digital landscape that shapes our lives is something that is going to continue to disrupt our lives. I think our world is increasingly complex and nobody has a complete picture in their head about how it all works. This allows for some seriously messed up hustles to occur on multiple levels, and is something that will take years for us all to understand the impact our financial system has had on our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Banks" /><category term="Money" /><category term="Markets" /><category term="Stories" /><summary type="html">I have been thinking about the storytelling surrounding the recent collapse of the Silicon Valley Bank (SVB) a lot lately. I just gave a talk at a company retreat about the importance of storytelling, and how all dimensions of the SVB situation is about telling and believing in stories. From our belief in money, markets, banks, to our continued belief in technology and venture capital, the recent goings on was all about stories. A significant part of this storytelling involves how we see things, and when you have very abstract concepts like financial products, businesses, and technology, the images we use to understand what is happening. When it came to SVB I particularly noticed the usage of images involving the front of SVB bank branches.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/silicon-valley-bank/silicon-valley-bank-stock.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/silicon-valley-bank/silicon-valley-bank-stock.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Things Are Hard</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/26/things-are-hard/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Things Are Hard" /><published>2023-02-26T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-26T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/26/things-are-hard</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/26/things-are-hard/">&lt;p&gt;I am struggling lately. I made it through the kid passing, covid, and managed to quit drinking, lose a bunch of weight, and get healthier, only to be really, really struggling in this moment. I want to make sure and document this moment in the calendar, if nothing else just to be able to look back and remind myself of the ups and downs of being Kin Lane. I have a well-paid job, amazing team, and yet I am struggling with showing up to work and giving a shit. It has been about 3 weeks now, and while I seem to have gotten through the worst, I am really finding it challenging to show up for work each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am four years into my job and it is the longest I’ve had a job in decades. I love my work. I love my team. I struggle with capitalism. I struggle with working at a fast-growing startup. I struggle with working in technology. I struggle just being Kin Lane. I wish I could put my finger on exactly what it is, but it is clearly approach burn-out levels. I’ve seen it before. I am working hard to find balance and step away from work on the weekend, but it can be challenging to leave it behind. The only way I can do it is to take long weekends and get out of the house and go somewhere in the RV. It is the only that stops the brain, heals the body, but sadly it doesn’t seem to be enough to get me through the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear a lot of folks are going through this right now. People from all over the world, from all industries, are just hitting the wall. Sadly, I think that business leadership doesn’t see this, or simply doesn’t care. Or maybe they are hitting their own kind of wall. I am at the top of my game, and I’d gladly take a massive pay cut to be able to work for myself again and switch back to the freelance or small business hustle. It seems so dumb. I am paid very well, but I am just not feeling the mojo. I have amazing work on the table, but I am just not feeling the mojo. I can’t help it is the result of some collective squeezing by the man right now that is leaving me in this state. I feel like we are all getting squeezed and despite my privileged position, I can’t help but emotionally feel solidarity with the rest of the tech workers and other industries being consumed by technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t help but feel complicit. This is what I mean when I say that I spend my days reducing everything to a transaction, as I translate our very meaningful physical worlds into digital API transactions. I feel like I work for the “nothing”. You know that all-consuming presence from the Never-ending Story? I feel like I am complicit in sucking the life out of our world and not just moving it online, I am making it something that can be bought and sold. This is why I am struggling. I struggle with what I am doing to the world. What we are doing to the world. I just don’t think that the web is going to save us. I spend all day everyday online and make more money than I ever have, and I am sadder, more depressed, and questioning everything about my life. I am sure I’ll make my way through it, but damn, I am stuck in the swamps of sadness lately. Things are hard.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Labor" /><category term="Career" /><category term="Digital" /><category term="Depression" /><summary type="html">I am struggling lately. I made it through the kid passing, covid, and managed to quit drinking, lose a bunch of weight, and get healthier, only to be really, really struggling in this moment. I want to make sure and document this moment in the calendar, if nothing else just to be able to look back and remind myself of the ups and downs of being Kin Lane. I have a well-paid job, amazing team, and yet I am struggling with showing up to work and giving a shit. It has been about 3 weeks now, and while I seem to have gotten through the worst, I am really finding it challenging to show up for work each day.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/yellow-journalism-hiding-monster-statue.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/yellow-journalism-hiding-monster-statue.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Becoming a Hunter Gatherer in the Information Age</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/05/becoming-a-hunter-gatherer-in-the-information-age/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Becoming a Hunter Gatherer in the Information Age" /><published>2023-01-05T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-05T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/05/becoming-a-hunter-gatherer-in-the-information-age</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/05/becoming-a-hunter-gatherer-in-the-information-age/">&lt;p&gt;I was watching a documentary on Fat the other night on PBS. They were conducting a study on a tribe in Africa to better understand why they don’t struggle with obesity and heart disease. The long story short is that our challenges with obesity is wrapped in a mix of our genes, processed foods, and our sedentary existence. The tribe in Africa is just always on the go, and they aren’t eating food that is as processed as ours is, and they have been doing this for many, many generations. I am guessing that our weight problems aren’t the only problems we face due this reality we’ve constructed for ourselves, and I am guessing that many of our mental health challenges are a result of our diet and lack of activity. Leaving me thinking both about my physical and mental health as I move into 2023, an enjoy my 50th year on this planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have done a lot of work to get a handle on my physical health this last year. However, I can do more. I am still not in as good of shape as I need to be. I want to be stronger. I want to be more active. I have also done a lot of work to get a handle on my mental health in recent years. However, I can do more. I still have highs and lows, and some days I struggle to function at all. I’ve done well without medication, and watching my friends struggle with different types of diagnosis and side effects of pharmaceuticals, I am confident I am on the right track. I am able to strike a balance between maintaining my passion, drive, creativity, as well as know when I’m slipping into depression or some other worse state. With this said, I feel like much of my mental health challenges are just due to regular old capitalism and making our way in this fucked up world. I am pretty convinced that if I didn’t work so much, and spend so much time online, I would be in much better shape. This is something I’d like to understand more, and make adjustments over the next couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I love my work, I don’t love all that comes with working at a fast moving startup, managing a large team, and spending so much time online. I am good at what I do. I am paid well. I also work at one of the best startups around. I am definitely top of my field. Yet, I still struggle showing up and being present every day. I feel like this is due to 1) work &amp;amp; capitalism, and 2) being online. I don’t mind working hard. I enjoy it. I hate everything that comes with a job. I also am getting sick of being online all day. I want to be offline, but I struggle with how I will maintain the quality of life I enjoy working in technology. I grew up poor, so I do’nt mind ratcheting things back down in a reasonable way, but I’ve worked hard to get where I am at, so I don’t really want to walk away completely. I just want to transition the next phase of my career to spend less time online, and do more out in the real world. Preferably something within my local area. I love Oakland, California. This all has got me thinking about how would one become a local hunter gatherer in an information age, where I am able to sustain myself by roaming my city each day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not saying I would literally hunt for food and kill it in Oakland. I am adapting this concept to how one my make a living out in the real world, without having to take a job and be online all day. I don’t mind working. I don’t mind be busy. I don’t mind being active. I just really want to avoid having to work for the man and rely solely on my online skills to pay the bills. I just want to be able to roam the streets of Oakland everyday picking up trash, snapping photos, gathering stories, generating data, and doing a variety of things that others might be interested in sponsoring, subscribing to, and supporting in some way. I don’t mind being online. I just don’t want to be at my desk all day. I think about the tribe in Africa ad how they are engage with their local environment every day. I want that. I have fallen in love with Oakland and want to explore the city. I want to get to know each street, block, and neighborhood. I think this is going to be what I set into motion in 2023. I think I am going to start just wandering the streets a couple of days a week, documenting, thinking, picking up trash, and getting to know the space around me. I think over time it will become more clear to me how I can replace my 9-5 some day with something that is more nourishing, and helps me balance both my physical and mental health.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Hunter" /><category term="Gatherer" /><category term="Oakland" /><category term="Digital Self" /><summary type="html">I was watching a documentary on Fat the other night on PBS. They were conducting a study on a tribe in Africa to better understand why they don’t struggle with obesity and heart disease. The long story short is that our challenges with obesity is wrapped in a mix of our genes, processed foods, and our sedentary existence. The tribe in Africa is just always on the go, and they aren’t eating food that is as processed as ours is, and they have been doing this for many, many generations. I am guessing that our weight problems aren’t the only problems we face due this reality we’ve constructed for ourselves, and I am guessing that many of our mental health challenges are a result of our diet and lack of activity. Leaving me thinking both about my physical and mental health as I move into 2023, an enjoy my 50th year on this planet.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/america-immigration_dumping-ground-oakland-oak-tree.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/algorotoscope-master/america-immigration_dumping-ground-oakland-oak-tree.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Some See What Is Missing but I See Opportunity to Build</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/28/some-see-what-is-missing-but-i-see-opportunity-to-build/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some See What Is Missing but I See Opportunity to Build" /><published>2022-12-28T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-28T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/28/some-see-what-is-missing-but-i-see-opportunity-to-build</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/28/some-see-what-is-missing-but-i-see-opportunity-to-build/">&lt;p&gt;Over the Thanksgiving holiday I setup Mastodon instances for my personal and professional domains. Over the last month I’ve invested time into understanding how this federated world works and doesn’t work, and began doing the hard work of building community in this new space. Numerous folks from my Twitter community have come over to Mastodon, but many I know have opted to stay in the Twitterverse, or opted to join other communities for a variety of reasons. The main reason I’ve seen is that there is nothing happening in the Fediverse once they sign up. They don’t see their people, their topics, or anything going on, leaving them wondering why you’d want to be in this universe in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it is because I was there to help build Twitter, as well as numerous other communities in the early days, or I am just a builder mentality, but I see nothing but opportunity to build community within the Fediverse. In addition to seeing opportunity to build community I see a number of the historians, librarians, journalists, artists, and other people I see being essential to any community already jumping from Twitter to Mastodon. While many other tech people touted the technology, and specifically API behind the early growth and adoption of Twitter, I saw these people being present and acting as the essential building blocks of creating what matters within a community. Either way, I see the potential for building what is missing when it comes to injecting the social in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be overwhelming to start over, and to have to entirely rebuild your entire social life. I get it, most people are just about the social part when things are already in motion. Most people are just looking for their people, and want to get to the business of being entertained and socializing. I don’t think everyone should or would see the world as I do, and I think many of these folks will end up switching in the next wave of social upheaval on not just Twitter, but also Facebook, Instagram, and the other platforms that have dominated how we see and engage with the digital world around us. I am very excited about the potential on Mastodon, but I have a lot of learning about how it all works, and building to do when it comes to my network, but also trust when it comes to making my way through all the diverse communities popping up in this exciting virtual world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Social" /><category term="Community" /><category term="Mastodon" /><summary type="html">Over the Thanksgiving holiday I setup Mastodon instances for my personal and professional domains. Over the last month I’ve invested time into understanding how this federated world works and doesn’t work, and began doing the hard work of building community in this new space. Numerous folks from my Twitter community have come over to Mastodon, but many I know have opted to stay in the Twitterverse, or opted to join other communities for a variety of reasons. The main reason I’ve seen is that there is nothing happening in the Fediverse once they sign up. They don’t see their people, their topics, or anything going on, leaving them wondering why you’d want to be in this universe in the first place.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/norman-rockwell-ruby-bridges-fixing-cross.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/norman-rockwell-ruby-bridges-fixing-cross.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dispatch From Coaling Station A</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/22/dispatch-from-coaling-station-a-copy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dispatch From Coaling Station A" /><published>2022-12-22T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-22T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/22/dispatch-from-coaling-station-a%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/22/dispatch-from-coaling-station-a-copy/">&lt;p&gt;We made it as far as Coalinga, CA, formerly known as Coaling Station A, before dark. This is where we’ll be spending two nights here before we continue on through Bakersfield to the edges of Death Valley. As one journeys to Death Valley you have to suspend your traditional views of the world, and no better place to do that than amongst the almond and orange orchards looking out across Interstate 5 outside of Coalinga, CA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/car-rv-coalinga.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Car and Travel Trailer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coalinga is a place I’ve only known as the place you drive by on Interstate 5 that smells like cow poop. In my older age and during my RVing journeys I am all about leaving my past assumptions about any person, place, or thing, and I am looking to experience Coalinga with a fresh and open mind. While I am not staying in Coalinga proper, the RV park we are in, provides a nice slice of what it is like to live in the agriculturally dominated area. 
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/road-through-orchard.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Road Through an Orchard&quot; /&gt;
I did a little historical search on our area, learning that the area was originally a coaling station for the Southern Pacific Railroad, and according to the Wikipedia page, “the city’s main industries are agriculture, oil, Cannabis, education and incarceration”. Which seems like a nice diverse set of investments if you ask me. After a leisurely drive through the town, I can concur, that seems to be the leading industries in the area.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/almond-rows.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Almond Tree Rows&quot; /&gt;
It’s hard around here. Trucks. People with hard looks on their face. People who have been hard done by. Combined with the cold spelling we are experiencing, it doesn’t leave much to explore and get to know. It is a truck area, so you have to drive to see anything and everything. It really isn’t cold. Just California cold. Keeping everyone indoors, or at least parked with your car running, while you wait for who knows what.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/coaling-plaza.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Coalinga Plaza&quot; /&gt;
I’ve driven by the Interstate 5 Freeway sign for Coalinga probably over 100 times. Always hitting the accelerator. This time I stopped and stayed for no real reason, other than it was the halfway point between home and my Death Valley destination. That was enough to make me stop this time. I can’t say that I will be coming back and staying the area, but I am thankful for stopping and strolling through the Orange and Almond orchards, and visiting the old town.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/wife-dog-oranges.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Wife and Dog in Orange Grove&quot; /&gt;
We will pack up in the morning, hitch up the trailer, and head for the lower Sierras, and make our way up to where the desert meets the mountains. It is here where our next adventure will begin. Coaling Station A was just a pit stop at the beginning of this journey, a cold, evenly rowed, isolated place. I am sure I will travel near Coalinga many more times in my life, and each time I can think about this one time when I stopped and took it in for just a moment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Coalinga" /><category term="California" /><category term="Cities" /><category term="Interstate 5" /><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html">We made it as far as Coalinga, CA, formerly known as Coaling Station A, before dark. This is where we’ll be spending two nights here before we continue on through Bakersfield to the edges of Death Valley. As one journeys to Death Valley you have to suspend your traditional views of the world, and no better place to do that than amongst the almond and orange orchards looking out across Interstate 5 outside of Coalinga, CA.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/old-house.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kinlane-productions2.s3.amazonaws.com/coalinga/old-house.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitter and Our Public Health</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/twitter-and-our-public-health/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter and Our Public Health" /><published>2022-12-18T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-18T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/twitter-and-our-public-health</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/twitter-and-our-public-health/">&lt;p&gt;As we all sit and watch the dumpster fire that is Twitter it can be easy to cheer on the demise of this platform. Although as I stare into the multi-color flames I can’t help but think about tall the work we’ve done on the Twitter plantation of the years, and the role it plays it our world. One are that comes to mind is how many of us received public health news as Covid gripped the world via Twitter. &lt;a href=&quot;https://covid-19-apis.postman.com/&quot;&gt;I spent months working on a Covid tracking website that primarily used the Twitter API to pull information from the state and county health departments who all use Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. I automated pulling of data from government health agencies and then aggregated it and pushed I back out all using the Twitter API — this will be hard to repeat in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While someday we may be able to get municipal, county, and state health departments to adopt a more federated approach to social media, I am guessing it will take years, and not reach the saturation levels of agencies as well as consistent tuned in that we have on Twitter today. Knowing how government agencies work, it will take some serious champions and evangelists to support standing up Mastodon servers for government agencies to see a more federated approach to social media and sharing of public health data with the masses. While I am fine with having to rebuild my social realm, and even see it as an opportunity, I can’t help but think about what we are collectively losing by letting Elon Musk set fire to the Twitterers we all worked so hard to build.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Twitter" /><category term="Health" /><category term="Municipal" /><category term="County" /><category term="State" /><summary type="html">As we all sit and watch the dumpster fire that is Twitter it can be easy to cheer on the demise of this platform. Although as I stare into the multi-color flames I can’t help but think about tall the work we’ve done on the Twitter plantation of the years, and the role it plays it our world. One are that comes to mind is how many of us received public health news as Covid gripped the world via Twitter. I spent months working on a Covid tracking website that primarily used the Twitter API to pull information from the state and county health departments who all use Twitter. I automated pulling of data from government health agencies and then aggregated it and pushed I back out all using the Twitter API — this will be hard to repeat in the future.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/birth-of-a-nation-abandoned-church-far.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/birth-of-a-nation-abandoned-church-far.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Staying Within the Machine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/staying-within-the-machine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Staying Within the Machine" /><published>2022-12-18T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-18T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/staying-within-the-machine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/18/staying-within-the-machine/">&lt;p&gt;I made a conscious decision in 1997 to immerse myself in the incoming technological apparatus that capitalism was unleashing on the world. Until this moment in time I had purposefully avoided capitalism, a career, and understanding how business was applying technology. I had spent the previous decade actively working to subvert the system from the outside-in, and for me to have the impact I wanted on society I knew that I had to get closer to the machine and operate from within, otherwise I was just going to be chewed up by the machine. I noticed how well-designed the machine was at targeting, destroying, or simply locking up threats that were outside the system, but just how difficult it was for the machine to target in between its own gears—this is where I needed to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the first ten years of this centruy just studying the machine. I needed to know how it was going to work. Once I began to understand how things work I began looking for ways to subvert the machine. To tell stories about how we can still live within the machine, while also throwing our bodies against the machine. You have to learn to tell stories very loudly, and as demonstrated recently with the switch in power via the Twittersphere, you have to be ready to pack up and move to a different part of the machine at any moment. There are two reasons I position myself where I am at, 1) to understand how the machine works so my stories are relevant to the hum of the machine, and 2) make it more difficult to be targeted by the machine for extermination or incarceration. If I am playing along, my stories sound familiar and relevant to folks, but sticking around and keeping my storytelling going is the number one way I do this hustle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that you can live a life outside the machine. It isn’t easy, and you have to learn to do without. I may go there at some point. But for now, I’ve kind of learned to enjoy the game. I just have to keep reminding myself why I’m here. I have to not let the sounds of the machine drive me mad, or force me to lose my soul. I have to internalize the sounds and vibrations of the machine, and empathize with the emotions of those who exist around me perpetually to find the stories that matter to us in any given moment. I regularly struggle staying sane and coherent amongst all the noise, and perpetually find myself unable to find the signal that matters, despite years of evidence to the contrary. I’ll keep on keep’n on within this state of existence for as long as I can. At some point I fully expect to need to step away, but I’ve gotten to know the machine so well, it has kind of become an old friend. Not for the service it does to its master, but just as a big, dumb, lumbering robot that marches on day after day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a regular post to remind myself of the bigger picture. I really, really, really get tired of technology most days. If I could figure out how to make money doing something offline, I’d sure jump at it. The problem is that I am good at what I do. The problem is staying the course and not burning myself out. It isn’t that I work too much. It is simply that working in tech lacks a lot of nutrients, and the work tends to consume you. Ultimately I don’t think I will ever leave. I don’t think I would enjoy just sitting somewhere checked out. It is just important that we sustain. I am not looking to get rich. I like making a name for myself. But I am more interested in being that slightly interesting person telling stories to anyone who will listen about this crazy invisible machine we’ve built around us that very few seem to even notice. The trick is to keep finding the stories that I find interesting, but also others find interesting. Preferably stories that help us all make sense of this digital chaos that we’ve unleashed, and help us all stay afloat in some meaningful ways.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Career" /><summary type="html">I made a conscious decision in 1997 to immerse myself in the incoming technological apparatus that capitalism was unleashing on the world. Until this moment in time I had purposefully avoided capitalism, a career, and understanding how business was applying technology. I had spent the previous decade actively working to subvert the system from the outside-in, and for me to have the impact I wanted on society I knew that I had to get closer to the machine and operate from within, otherwise I was just going to be chewed up by the machine. I noticed how well-designed the machine was at targeting, destroying, or simply locking up threats that were outside the system, but just how difficult it was for the machine to target in between its own gears—this is where I needed to be.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/copper-circuit-old-computer-bletchley-crypto.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/kinlane-productions2/algorotoscope-master/copper-circuit-old-computer-bletchley-crypto.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>